[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "C99 standard guarantees uniqueness of __________ characters for internal names.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 31",
            "b) 63",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 14"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ISO C99 compiler may consider only first 63 characters for internal names.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "C99 standard guarantees uniqueness of ___________ characters for external names.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 31",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 14"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ISO C99 compiler may consider only first 31 characters for external names.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int __a3;",
            "b) int __3a;",
            "c) int __A3;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int _a3;",
            "b) int a_3;",
            "c) int 3_a;",
            "d) int _3a"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Variable name cannot start with a digit.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "Why do variable names beginning with the underscore is not encouraged?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is not standardized",
            "b) To avoid conflicts since assemblers and loaders use such names",
            "c) To avoid conflicts since library routines use such names",
            "d) To avoid conflicts with environment variables of an operating system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "All keywords in C are in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) LowerCase letters",
            "b) UpperCase letters",
            "c) CamelCase letters",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "Variable name resolution (number of significant characters for the uniqueness of variable) depends on ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compiler and linker implementations",
            "b) Assemblers and loaders implementations",
            "c) C language",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It depends on the standard to which compiler and linkers are adhering.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid C variable name?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int number;",
            "b) float rate;",
            "c) int variable_count;",
            "d) int $main;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since only underscore and no other special character is allowed in a variable name, it results in an error.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true for variable names in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) They can contain alphanumeric characters as well as special characters",
            "b) It is not an error to declare a variable to be one of the keywords(like goto, static)",
            "c) Variable names cannot start with a digit",
            "d) Variable can be of any length"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: According to the syntax for C variable name, it cannot start with a digit.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "Which is valid C expression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int my_num = 100,000;",
            "b) int my_num = 100000;",
            "c) int my num = 1000;",
            "d) int $my_num = 10000;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Space, comma and $ cannot be used in a variable name.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello World! %d <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello World! x;",
            "b) Hello World! followed by a junk value",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Hello World!"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  It results in an error since x is used without declaring the variable x.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm1.c\npgm1.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm1.c:4: error: ‘x’ undeclared (first use in this function)\npgm1.c:4: error: (Each undeclared identifier is reported only once\npgm1.c:4: error: for each function it appears in.)\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10000</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">34</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello World! %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Hello World! 34",
            "c) Hello World! 1000",
            "d) Hello World! followed by a junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since y is already defined, redefining it results in an error.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm2.c\npgm2.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm2.c:5: error: redefinition of ‘y’\npgm2.c:4: note: previous definition of ‘y’ was here\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) float PI = 3.14;",
            "b) double PI = 3.14;",
            "c) int PI = 3.14;",
            "d) #define PI 3.14"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: #define PI 3.14 is a macro preprocessor, it is a textual substitution.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "5. What will happen if the following C code is executed?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> main<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) It will cause a compile-time error",
            "b) It will cause a run-time error",
            "c) It will run without any error and prints 3",
            "d) It will experience infinite looping"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A C program can have same function name and same variable name.\n$ cc pgm3.c\n$ a.out\n3\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) The variable name begins with an integer",
            "b) The special character ‘-‘",
            "c) The special character ‘?’",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A variable name cannot start with an integer, along with that the C compiler interprets the ‘-‘ and ‘?’ as a minus operator and a question mark operator respectively.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ThisIsVariableName <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">12</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ThisIsVariablename <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">14</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ThisIsVariablename<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The program will print 12",
            "b) The program will print 14",
            "c) The program will have a runtime error",
            "d) The program will cause a compile-time error due to redeclaration"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Variable names ThisIsVariablename and ThisIsVariableName are both distinct as C is case sensitive.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm4.c\n$ a.out\n14\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be a variable name in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) volatile",
            "b) true",
            "c) friend",
            "d) export"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:  a\nExplanation: volatile is C keyword.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"st0\">'5'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"FAIL<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The compiler will flag an error",
            "b) The program will compile and print the output 5",
            "c) The program will compile and print the ASCII value of 5",
            "d) The program will compile and print FAIL for 5 times"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ASCII value of 5 is 53, the char type-casted integral value 5 is 5 only.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm1.c\n$ a.out\nFAIL\nFAIL\nFAIL\nFAIL\nFAIL\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "The format identifier ‘%i’ is also used for _____ data type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) int",
            "c) float",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Both %d and %i can be used as a format identifier for int data type.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "Which data type is most suitable for storing a number 65000 in a 32-bit system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) signed short",
            "b) unsigned short",
            "c) long",
            "d) int"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 65000 comes in the range of short (16-bit) which occupies the least memory. Signed short ranges from -32768 to 32767 and hence we should use unsigned short.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a User-defined data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) typedef int Boolean;",
            "b) typedef enum {Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri} Workdays;",
            "c) struct {char name[10], int age};",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: typedef and struct are used to define user-defined data types.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "What is the size of an int data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4 Bytes",
            "b) 8 Bytes",
            "c) Depends on the system/compiler",
            "d) Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The size of the data types depend on the system.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include  &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">       <span class=\"kw4\">signed</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> chr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">       chr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">128</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">       <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> chr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">       <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 128",
            "b) -128",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: signed char will be a negative number.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm2.c\n$ a.out\n-128\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include  &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>file<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        file <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fopen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"test.txt\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"w+\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>file<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>file<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>file<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">'b'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fclose</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>file<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        file <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fopen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"test.txt\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"r\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fgetc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>file<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span>  <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) Infinite loop",
            "c) Depends on what fgetc returns",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm3.c\n$ a.out\na\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "What is short int in C programming?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The basic data type of C",
            "b) Qualifier",
            "c) Short is the qualifier and int is the basic data type",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>f1 <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"equal<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not equal<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) equal",
            "b) not equal",
            "c) output depends on the compiler",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 0.1 by default is of type double which has different representation than float resulting in inequality even after conversion.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm4.c\n$ a.out\nnot equal\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>f1 <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu17\">0.1f</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"equal<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not equal<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) equal",
            "b) not equal",
            "c) output depends on compiler",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 0.1f results in 0.1 to be stored in floating point representations.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm5.c\n$ a.out\nequal\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code on a 32-bit machine?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10000</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">56</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"p and q are %d and %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) p and q are 4 and 4",
            "b) p and q are 4 and 8",
            "c) compiler error",
            "d) p and q are 2 and 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Size of any type of pointer is 4 on a 32-bit machine.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm6.c\n$ a.out\np and q are 4 and 4\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "Which is correct with respect to the size of the data types?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char > int > float",
            "b) int > char > float",
            "c) char < int < double",
            "d) double > char > int"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: char has less bytes than int and int has less bytes than double in any system\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code on a 64 bit machine?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> Sti</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> nu<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> Sti s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 9",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the size of a union is the size of its maximum data type, here int is the largest data type. Hence the size of the union is 4.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm7.c\n$ a.out\n4\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) run time error",
            "c) a.0000000",
            "d) 97.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since the ASCII value of a is 97, the same is assigned to the float variable and printed.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm8.c\n$ a.out\n97.000000\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "Which of the data types has the size that is variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) struct",
            "c) float",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the size of the structure depends on its fields, it has a variable size.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>ORANGE <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MANGO<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> BANANA <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> PEACH<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"PEACH = %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> PEACH<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) PEACH = 3",
            "b) PEACH = 4",
            "c) PEACH = 5",
            "d) PEACH = 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In enum, the value of constant is defined to the recent assignment from left.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm1.c\n$ a.out\nPEACH = 5\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "3. In the following code snippet, character pointer str holds a reference to the string ___________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">char *str =  \"Sanfoundry.com\\0\" \"training classes\";</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sanfoundry.com",
            "b) Sanfoundry.com\\0training classes",
            "c) Sanfoundry.comtraining classes",
            "d) Invalid declaration"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This program has only one %s within first double quotes, so it does not read the string “WOW”.\nThe %s along with the Sanfoundry is not read as a format modifier while new line character prints the new line.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm2.c\n$ a.out\nC programming Class by\n%s Sanfoundry\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define a 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a = %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a = 5",
            "b) a = 10",
            "c) Compilation error",
            "d) Runtime error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘\\0’ is accepted as a char in the string. Even though strlen will give length of string “Sanfoundry.com”, in memory str is pointing to entire string including training classes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> var <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu8\">010</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> var<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 9",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The #define substitutes a with 10 without leaving any identifier, which results in Compilation error.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm3.c\npgm3.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm3.c:5: error: expected identifier or ‘(’ before numeric constant\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> birds <span class=\"br0\">{</span>SPARROW<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> PEACOCK<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> PARROT<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> animals <span class=\"br0\">{</span>TIGER <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> LION<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> RABBIT<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ZEBRA<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> birds m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> TIGER<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 010 is octal representation of 8.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm4.c\n$ a.out\n8\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 2</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> bird <span class=\"br0\">{</span>SPARROW <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> MAX <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> PARROT <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> SPARROW <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> MAX<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> bird b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> PARROT<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) 5",
            "c) Undefined value",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: m is an integer constant, hence it is compatible.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm5.c\n$ a.out\n8\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;string.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"x\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'x'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 1",
            "b) 2 1",
            "c) 2 2",
            "d) 1 (undefined value)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: MAX value is 2 and hence PARROT will have value 3 + 2.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm6.c\n$ a.out\n5\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "enum types are processed by _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compiler",
            "b) Preprocessor",
            "c) Linker",
            "d) Assembler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"p is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) p is 4",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) p is followed by a garbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: r is carriage return and moves the cursor back. sanfo is replaced by class.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm8.c\n$ a.out\nclassundry\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>r<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Address of k",
            "b) Address of r",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Address of k + address of r"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: rn combination makes the cursor move to the next line.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm9.c\n$ a.out\nsanfoundry\nclass\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is false?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Constant variables need not be defined as they are declared and can be defined later",
            "b) Global constant variables are initialized to zero",
            "c) const keyword is used to define constant values",
            "d) You cannot reassign a value to a constant variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the constant variable has to be declared and defined at the same time, not doing it results in an error.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm10.c\npgm10.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm10.c:5: error: assignment of read-only variable ‘p’\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"k is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) k is 6",
            "b) Error due to const succeeding int",
            "c) Error, because a constant variable can be changed only twice",
            "d) Error, because a constant variable cannot be changed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since the pointer p is declared to be constant, trying to assign it with a new value results in an error.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm11.c\npgm11.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm11.c:7: error: assignment of read-only variable ‘p’\npgm11.c:8: warning: format ‘%d’ expects type ‘int’, but argument 2 has type ‘int * const’\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> print<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Sanfoundry.com\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        print<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error because function name cannot be preceded by const",
            "b) Sanfoundry.com",
            "c) Sanfoundry.com is printed infinite times",
            "d) Blank screen, no output"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the constant variable has to be declared and defined at the same time, not doing it results in an error.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 20",
            "c) Undefined value",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cannot change a const type value.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm1.c\npgm1.c: In function ‘foo’:\npgm1.c:13: error: assignment of read-only location ‘*i’\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Compile time warning and printf displays 20",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Changing const variable through non-constant pointers invokes compiler warning.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm2.c\npgm2.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm2.c:5: warning: initialization discards qualifiers from pointer target type\n$ a.out\n20\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 11",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Variable j is not defined.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm3.c\npgm3.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm3.c:4: error: ‘j’ undeclared (first use in this function)\npgm3.c:4: error: (Each undeclared identifier is reported only once\npgm3.c:4: error: for each function it appears in.)\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "4. Will the following C code compile without any error?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the C standard implemented by compilers",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Compilers implementing C90 do not allow this, but compilers implementing C99 allow it.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm4.c\npgm4.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm4.c:4: error: ‘for’ loop initial declarations are only allowed in C99 mode\npgm4.c:4: note: use option -std=c99 or -std=gnu99 to compile your code\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "5. Will the following C code compile without any error?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the C standard implemented by compilers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There can be blocks inside the block. But within a block, variables have only block scope.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm5.c\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "Which of the following declaration is not supported by C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) String str;",
            "b) char *str;",
            "c) float str = 3e2;",
            "d) Both String str; & float str = 3e2;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is legal in Java, but not in C.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "7. Which of the following format identifier can never be used for the variable var?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>var <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Advanced Training in C by Sanfoundry.com\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) %f",
            "b) %d",
            "c) %c",
            "d) %s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: %c can be used to print the indexed position.\n%d can still be used to display its ASCII value.\n%s is recommended.\n%f cannot be used for the variable var.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "Which of the following declaration is illegal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char *str = “Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry”;",
            "b) char str[] = “Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry”;",
            "c) char str[20] = “Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry”;",
            "d) char[] str = “Best C programming classes by Sanfoundry”;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: char[] str is a declaration in Java, but not in C.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used to prevent any changes in the variable within a C program?",
        "Options": [
            "a) immutable",
            "b) mutable",
            "c) const",
            "d) volatile"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: const is a keyword constant in C program.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a pointer declaration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char a[10];",
            "b) char a[] = {‘1’, ‘2’, ‘3’, ‘4’};",
            "c) char *str;",
            "d) char a;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Array declarations are pointer declarations.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 4.0000000",
            "d) 4.4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Since the variable k is defined both as integer and as float, it results in an error.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm8.c\npgm8.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm8.c:5: error: conflicting types for ‘k’\npgm8.c:4: note: previous definition of ‘k’ was here\npgm8.c:6: warning: format ‘%d’ expects type ‘int’, but argument 2 has type ‘double’\npgm8.c:7: error: expected ‘;’ before ‘}’ token\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is false?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A variable defined once can be defined again with different scope",
            "b) A single variable cannot be defined with two different types in the same scope",
            "c) A variable must be declared and defined at the same time",
            "d) A variable refers to a location in memory"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is not an error if the variable is declared and not defined. For example – extern declarations.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "A variable declared in a function can be used in main().",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) True if it is declared static",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the scope of the variable declared within a function is restricted only within that function, so the above statement is false.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) -1",
            "c) 1",
            "d) Implementation defined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> l <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) -1 1",
            "c) 1 -1",
            "d) Implementation defined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Implementation defined",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 3",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Implementation defined",
            "b) -1",
            "c) -3",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "5. What will be the final value of x in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.75",
            "b) Depends on compiler",
            "c) 24",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">5.3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Value of x is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Value of x is 2.3",
            "b) Value of x is 1",
            "c) Value of x is 0.3",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Value of x is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Value of x is 1",
            "b) Value of x is 2",
            "c) Value of x is 3",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"sy0\">--</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Value of b is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Value of x is 12",
            "b) Value of x is 13",
            "c) Value of x is 10",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "What is the precedence of arithmetic operators (from highest to lowest)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %, *, /, +, –",
            "b) %, +, /, *, –",
            "c) +, -, %, *, /",
            "d) %, +, -, *, /"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an arithmetic operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) a * = 10;",
            "b) a / = 10;",
            "c) a ! = 10;",
            "d) a % = 10;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "Which of the following data type will throw an error on modulus operation(%)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) short",
            "c) int",
            "d) float"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "Which among the following are the fundamental arithmetic operators, i.e, performing the desired operation can be done using that operator only?",
        "Options": [
            "a) +, –",
            "b) +, -, %",
            "c) +, -, *, /",
            "d) +, -, *, /, %"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">5.6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 15.6",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>b <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 10",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\" %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -2147483648",
            "b) -1",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "6. What will be the final value of j in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"co1\">//do something</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 10",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on language standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "7. What will be the final value of j in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"co1\">//do something</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 20",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Depends on language standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Yes<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"No<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "Are logical operator sequence points?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "Do logical operators in the C language are evaluated with the short circuit?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "What is the result of logical or relational expression in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True or False",
            "b) 0 or 1",
            "c) 0 if an expression is false and any positive number if an expression is true",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "4. What will be the final value of d in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        b <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">!</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">!!</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 1",
            "b) 0 3",
            "c) 5 3",
            "d) 1 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "Which among the following is NOT a logical or relational operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) !=",
            "b) ==",
            "c) ||",
            "d) ="
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">--</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"TRUE 1<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"sy0\">--</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"TRUE 2<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) TRUE 1",
            "b) TRUE 2",
            "c) TRUE 1  TRUE 2",
            "d) Compiler Dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: This is a sequence point problem and hence the result will be implementation dependent. "
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "Relational operators cannot be used on ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) structure",
            "b) long",
            "c) strings",
            "d) float"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Sanfoundry\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Advanced C Classes\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Advanced C Classes",
            "b) Sanfoundry",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.100000, junk value",
            "b) Junk value, 0.100000",
            "c) 0, 0.100000",
            "d) 0, 0.999999"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code? (Initial values: x= 7, y = 8)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter two numbers <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f %f\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f, %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7.000000, 7",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) 7.000000, junk",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">123828749.66</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0, 0.0",
            "b) 123828749, 123828749.66",
            "c) 12382874, 12382874.0",
            "d) 123828749, 0.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) b",
            "c) 97",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "When double is converted to float, then the value is?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Truncated",
            "b) Rounded",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">23</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">signed</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">23</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Yes<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"No<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the operating system"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">23</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">23</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Yes<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"No<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "function tolower(c) defined in library <ctype.h> works for ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ascii character set",
            "b) Unicode character set",
            "c) Ascii and utf-8 but not EBCDIC character set",
            "d) Any character set"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code considering the size of a short int is 2, char is 1 and int is 4 bytes?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d, %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2, 1, 2",
            "b) 2, 1, 1",
            "c) 2, 1, 4",
            "d) 2, 2, 8"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "Which type of conversion is NOT accepted?",
        "Options": [
            "a) From char to int",
            "b) From float to char pointer",
            "c) From negative int to char",
            "d) From double to char"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: Conversion of a float to pointer type is not allowed. "
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "4. What will be the data type of the result of the following operation?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">(float)a * (int)b / (long)c * (double)d</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) long",
            "c) float",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "Which of the following type-casting have chances for wrap around?",
        "Options": [
            "a) From int to float",
            "b) From int to char",
            "c) From char to short",
            "d) From char to int"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "Which of the following typecasting is accepted by C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Widening conversions",
            "b) Narrowing conversions",
            "c) Widening & Narrowing conversions",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "When do you need to use type-conversions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The value to be stored is beyond the max limit",
            "b) The value to be stored is in a form not supported by that data type",
            "c) To reduce the memory in use, relevant to the value",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer:  d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "1. What is the difference between the following 2 codes?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt; //Program 1</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>  a<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No difference as space doesn’t make any difference, values of a, b, d are same in both the case",
            "b) Space does make a difference, values of a, b, d are different",
            "c) Program 1 has syntax error, program 2 is not",
            "d) Program 2 has syntax error, program 1 is not"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt; //Program 2</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>  a<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+++</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a = 1, b = 1",
            "b) a = 2, b = 1",
            "c) a = 1, b = 2",
            "d) a = 2, b = 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15, 4, 5",
            "b) 9, 6, 9",
            "c) 9, 3, 5",
            "d) Undefined (Compiler Dependent)"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "For which of the following, “PI++;” code will fail?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #define PI 3.14",
            "b) char *PI = “A”;",
            "c) float PI = 3.14;",
            "d) none of the Mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d, %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>d <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a = 10, b = 9",
            "b) a = 10, b = 8",
            "c) a = 5, b = 9",
            "d) a = 5, b = 8"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        b<span class=\"sy0\">--;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">--</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 4",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">     <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) = operator is not a sequence point",
            "b) ++ operator may return value with or without side effects",
            "c) it can be evaluated as (i++)+i or i+(++i)",
            "d) = operator is a sequence point"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d % d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0, 2",
            "b) 0, 1",
            "c) 1, 2",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 11",
            "c) Garbage value",
            "d) Address of i"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"X is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) X is 97",
            "b) X is 98",
            "c) X is 99",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">--</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">--;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>  y<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3 2 3",
            "b) 2 3 3",
            "c) 3 2 2",
            "d) 2 3 4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 1",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>b <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>%d%d%d%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>  b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6 -6 0 0",
            "b) 6 -5 0 1",
            "c) -6 -6 0 1",
            "d) 6 -6 0 1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -4",
            "b) -5",
            "c) 4",
            "d) -3"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">^</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 9",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer:  a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ~a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a)  -9",
            "b) -10",
            "c) -11",
            "d)  10"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">7</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Honesty\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>~<span class=\"nu0\">7</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu12\">0x000f</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"is the best policy<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Honesty is the best policy",
            "b) Honesty",
            "c) is the best policy",
            "d) No output"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) No Output"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "5. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Logical Shift left",
            "b) No output",
            "c) Arithmetic Shift right",
            "d) Bitwise exclusive OR"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) x is 97",
            "b) x is 98",
            "c) x is 99",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">--</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">--;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3 2 3",
            "b) 2 2 3",
            "c) 3 2 2",
            "d) 2 3 3"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 1",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>b <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>%d%d%d%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6 -6 0 0",
            "b) 6 -5 0 1",
            "c) -6 -6 0 1",
            "d) 6 -6 0 1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -3",
            "b) -5",
            "c) 4",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the endianness of the machine"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) -1",
            "c) 2 31 – 1 considering int to be 4 bytes",
            "d) Either -1 or 1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>~<span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes",
            "b) no",
            "c) compile time error",
            "d) undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">!</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes",
            "b) no",
            "c) run time error",
            "d) undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">|</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"y is %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) y is 1",
            "b) 1",
            "c) run time error",
            "d) undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>y <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) true 2",
            "b) false 2",
            "c) either true 2 or false 2",
            "d) true 1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Its zero<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Its not zero<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Its not zero",
            "b) Its zero",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) None"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0 9",
            "b) 0 8",
            "c) 1 8",
            "d) 1 9"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) Junk value",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) 7"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) returns 1",
            "b) returns 2",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) Aries",
            "c) -5",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">*=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 6",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">/=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0.5",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;=</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) float",
            "c) there is no type for an assignment expression",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) True",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "Operation “a = a * b + a” can also be written as ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) a *= b + 1;",
            "b) (c = a * b)!=(a = c + a);",
            "c) a = (b + 1)* a;",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "4. What will be the final value of c in the following C statement? (Initial value: c = 2)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">c <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;&lt;=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) c = 1;",
            "b) c = 2;",
            "c) c = 3;",
            "d) c = 4;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a <span class=\"sy0\">+=</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">-=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 1",
            "b) 1 2",
            "c) 2 1",
            "d) 2 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> result <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        result <span class=\"sy0\">+=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Addition of a and n",
            "b) Subtraction of a and n",
            "c) Multiplication of a and n",
            "d) Division of a and n"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid assignment operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) a %= 10;",
            "b) a /= 10;",
            "c) a |= 10;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>y<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>  x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"kw3\">getchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Whatever character getchar function returns",
            "c) Ascii value of character getchar function returns",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"float<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"short int<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) float",
            "b) short int",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>b <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> l <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>y<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7",
            "b) 8",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) 15"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) 7",
            "c) 8",
            "d) Depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) returns 1",
            "b) returns 2",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7",
            "b) 8",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 9",
            "c) 8",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "3. What will be the final values of a and c in the following C statement? (Initial values: a = 2, c = 1)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\"> c = (c) ? a = 0 : 2;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a = 0, c = 0;",
            "b) a = 2, c = 2;",
            "c) a = 2, c = 2;",
            "d) a = 1, c = 2;"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "4. What will be the data type of the following expression? (Initial data type: a = int, var1 =  double, var2 = float)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">expression (a &lt; 50)? var1 : var2;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) float",
            "c) double",
            "d) Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) exp1",
            "b) exp2",
            "c) exp3",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "6. What will be the final value of c in the following C code snippet? (Initial values: a = 1, b = 2, c = 1)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">       c += (-c) ? a : b;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax Error",
            "b) c = 1",
            "c) c = 2",
            "d) c = 3"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        reverse<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> reverse<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">exit</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> reverse<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) 1 2 3 4",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Stack overflow"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> reverse<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        reverse<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> reverse<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> reverse<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5",
            "b) Segmentation fault",
            "c) Compilation error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "In expression i = g() + f(), first function called depends on __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compiler",
            "b) Associativiy of () operator",
            "c) Precedence of () and + operator",
            "d) Left to write of the expression"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "4. What will be the final values of i and j in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) i value is 1 and j value is 1",
            "b) i value is 0 and j value is 0",
            "c) i value is 1 and j value is undefined",
            "d) i and j value are undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "5. What will be the final values of i and j in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//bitwise or</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//bitwise or</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> g<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) i value is 1 and j value is 1",
            "b) i value is 0 and j value is 0",
            "c) i value is 1 and j value is undefined",
            "d) i and j value are undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>y <span class=\"sy0\">|=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) Undefined behaviour due to order of evaluation",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>y<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>y<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Undefined behaviour due to order of evaluation can be different",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12",
            "b) 20",
            "c) 4",
            "d) Either 12 or 20"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">/=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 4.000000",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 2 3.500000",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) false",
            "c) compile time error",
            "d) undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">/=</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">%=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Floating point exception",
            "d) Segmentation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 3",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//, y = 2;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increment of read-only location compile error",
            "b) 4",
            "c) Some garbage value",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">^</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 1 or 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">!</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> z <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ~x <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 14",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 1 6"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 10",
            "d) 9"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 2",
            "c) -2",
            "d) -3"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>b <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">--;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) 15",
            "c) 13",
            "d) 14"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        b<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9.000000",
            "b) 9",
            "c) 9.0",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -2",
            "b) Floating point Exception",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 30",
            "c) 2.000000",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.000000",
            "b) 4.000000",
            "c) 5.000000",
            "d) 1.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.000000",
            "b) 0.000000",
            "c) 7.000000",
            "d) 2.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">--;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 5",
            "d) undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 25",
            "b) -5",
            "c) 11",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">|</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 15",
            "c) 13",
            "d) 21"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> h <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>h<span class=\"sy0\">++,</span> h<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> h<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 10",
            "b) 10 9",
            "c) 9 10",
            "d) 8 10"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> h <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> h<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> h<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> h<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> h<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 11"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> h <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 33",
            "c) 34",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>  <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 11",
            "d) 9"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'0'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'m'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"st0\">'1'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) a",
            "c) 1",
            "d) m"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'A'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'B'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 65",
            "b) 58",
            "c) 64",
            "d) 59"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "Which of the following operators has an associativity from Right to Left?",
        "Options": [
            "a) <=",
            "b) <<",
            "c) ==",
            "d) +="
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "2. Which operators of the following have same precedence?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">P. \"!=\", Q. \"+=\", R. \"&lt;&lt;=\"</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) P and Q",
            "b) Q and R",
            "c) P and R",
            "d) P, Q and R"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "3. Comment on the following statement.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">   n = 1;\n   printf(\"%d, %dn\", 3*n, n++);</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output will be 3, 2",
            "b) Output will be 3, 1",
            "c) Output will be 6, 1",
            "d) Output is compiler dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "4. Which of the following option is the correct representation of the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">e = a * b + c / d * f;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) e = (a * (b +(c /(d * f))));",
            "b) e = ((a * b) + (c / (d * f)));",
            "c) e = ((a * b) + ((c / d)* f));",
            "d) Both e = ((a * b) + (c / (d * f))); and e = ((a * b) + ((c / d)* f));"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Verified by e = 1 * 2 + 3 / 4 * 5; and then using respective braces according to the option."
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "5. While swapping 2 numbers what precautions to be taken care?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">    b = (b / a);\n    a = a * b;\n    b = a / b;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data type should be either of short, int and long",
            "b) Data type should be either of float and double",
            "c) All data types are accepted except for (char *)",
            "d) This code doesn’t swap 2 numbers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        e <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> e<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7, 4",
            "b) 7, 2",
            "c) 5, 2",
            "d) Syntax error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "7. Which of the following is the correct order of evaluation for the given expression?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">a = w % x / y * z;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) % / * =",
            "b) / * % =",
            "c) = % * /",
            "d) * % / ="
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "8. Which function in the following expression will be called first?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">a = func3(6) - func2(4, 5) / func1(1, 2, 3);</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) func1();",
            "b) func2();",
            "c) func3();",
            "d) Cannot be predicted"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "Which of the following operator has the highest precedence in the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ()",
            "b) sizeof",
            "c) *",
            "d) +"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a ternary operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) &&",
            "b) >>=",
            "c) ?:",
            "d) ->"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "Which of the following are unary operators?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sizeof",
            "b) –",
            "c) ++",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "Where in C the order of precedence of operators do not exist?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Within conditional statements, if, else",
            "b) Within while, do-while",
            "c) Within a macro definition",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "Associativity of an operator is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Right to Left",
            "b) Left to Right",
            "c) Random fashion",
            "d) Both Right to Left and Left to Right"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "Which of the following method is accepted for assignment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 = a = b = c = d;",
            "b) a = b = c = d = 5;",
            "c) a = b = 5 = c = d;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT possible with any 2 operators in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Different precedence, same associativity",
            "b) Different precedence, different associativity",
            "c) Same precedence, different associativity",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "Which of the following is possible with any 2 operators in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same associativity, different precedence",
            "b) Same associativity, same precedence",
            "c) Different associativity, different precedence",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "Which of the following operators has the lowest precedence?",
        "Options": [
            "a) !=",
            "b) &&",
            "c) ?:",
            "d) ,"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">do</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Undefined behaviour",
            "b) Output will be 3",
            "c) Output will be 6",
            "d) Output will be 5"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>b <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d, %d, %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0, 4, 2, 1",
            "b) 0, 5, 2, 1",
            "c) -1, 4, 1, 1",
            "d) 0, 5, 1, 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> q <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">||</span> q <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"No Output<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 20",
            "d) No Output"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi",
            "b) hello",
            "c) no",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"how are u\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi",
            "b) how are you",
            "c) compile time error",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw2\">true</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) It will display hello",
            "b) It will throw an error",
            "c) Nothing will be displayed",
            "d) Compiler dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"how are u\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi",
            "b) how are you",
            "c) hello",
            "d) hihello"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code? (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">             <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">             <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">             <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">             <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 3:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"1\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) No Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 1 2",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 2 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Hi 2",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ch <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) false",
            "c) compile time error",
            "d) undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"inside if<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"inside else if<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"inside else<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) inside if",
            "b) inside else if",
            "c) inside else",
            "d) compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true, \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false, \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) false, 0",
            "b) true, 0",
            "c) true, 10",
            "d) compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) false",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) No print statement"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid if-else statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) if (if (a == 1)){}",
            "b) if (func1 (a)){}",
            "c) if (a){}",
            "d) if ((char) a){}"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">--</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"True\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"False\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) True False",
            "d) No Output"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"All is Well \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"I am Well<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"I am not a River<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output will be All is Well I am Well",
            "b) Output will be I am Well I am not a River",
            "c) Output will be I am Well",
            "d) Compile time errors during compilation"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\")))</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">            printf(\"</span>We are Happy<span class=\"st0\">\");</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">        else if (printf(\"</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"st0\">\"))</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">            printf(\"</span>We are Sad<span class=\"st0\">\");</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"st0\">    }</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0We are Happy",
            "b) 1We are Happy",
            "c) 1We are Sad",
            "d) compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 3:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"1\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 1 2",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 2 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) hi 2",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?  (Assuming that we have entered the value 1 in the standard input)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a value between 1 to 2:\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ch <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes",
            "b) no",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) yes no"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes",
            "b) yes no",
            "c) Duplicate case value error",
            "d) Character case value error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu16\">1.0</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"default<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes",
            "b) yes default",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>  b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes no",
            "b) yes",
            "c) no",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define max(a) a</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> max<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> max<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes no",
            "b) yes",
            "c) no",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Do\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"First<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Second<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Default<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Do",
            "b) DoFirst",
            "c) DoSecond",
            "d) DoDefault"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "4. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No error, output is 1111",
            "b) No error, output is 1",
            "c) Compile time error, no break statements",
            "d) Compile time error, case label outside switch statement"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Question": "Which datatype can accept the switch statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) char",
            "c) long",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Case A \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">           <span class=\"kw1\">default</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">              <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Default\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output: Case A",
            "b) Output: Default",
            "c) Output: Case A Default",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "The C code ‘for(;;)’ represents an infinite loop. It can be terminated by ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) break",
            "b) exit(0)",
            "c) abort()",
            "d) terminate"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "Which for loop has range of similar indexes of ‘i’ used in for (i = 0;i < n; i++)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) for (i = n; i>0; i–)",
            "b) for (i = n; i >= 0; i–)",
            "c) for (i = n-1; i>0; i–)",
            "d) for (i = n-1; i>-1; i–)"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be used as LHS of the expression in for (exp1;exp2; exp3)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) variable",
            "b) function",
            "c) typedef",
            "d) macros"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The control won’t fall into the for loop",
            "b) Numbers will be displayed until the signed limit of short and throw a runtime error",
            "c) Numbers will be displayed until the signed limit of short and program will successfully terminate",
            "d) This program will get into an infinite loop and keep printing numbers with no errors"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Hello is printed thrice",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu16\">3.0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) Hello is printed thrice",
            "c) Hello is printed twice",
            "d) Hello is printed infinitely"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu16\">3.0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.000000",
            "b) 4.000000",
            "c) 3.000000",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello",
            "b) Infinite hello",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In for loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"After loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Infinite loop",
            "c) After loop",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In for loop \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"After loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) In for loop after loop",
            "b) After loop",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In for loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"After loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) After loop",
            "b) In for loop after loop",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In for loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"After loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) In for loop after loop",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Infinite loop",
            "d) Depends on the value of NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In for loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) In for loop",
            "c) Depends on the standard compiler implements",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In while loop \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"After loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) In while loop after loop",
            "b) After loop",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "4. How many times i value is checked in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">do</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"in while loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "5. How many times i value is checked in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In while loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">do</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Hi Hi",
            "c) Hi",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">++</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"H\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) H",
            "b) H is printed infinite times",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">do</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) H is printed infinite times",
            "c) Hello",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">do</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Hello is printed infinite times"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> </pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hi is printed 8 times, hello 7 times and then hi 2 times",
            "b) Hi is printed 10 times, hello 7 times",
            "c) Hi is printed once, hello 7 times",
            "d) Hi is printed once, hello 7 times and then hi 2 times"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "What is an example of iteration in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) for",
            "b) while",
            "c) do-while",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "4. How many times while loop condition is tested in the following C code snippets, if i is initialized to 0 in both the cases?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">         i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    ————<span class=\"sy0\">-</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw1\">do</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">         i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;=</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) n, n",
            "b) n, n+1",
            "c) n+1, n",
            "d) n+1, n+1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"True<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"False<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True (infinite time)",
            "b) True (1 time) False",
            "c) False",
            "d) Compiler dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            j<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5, 5",
            "b) 5, 10",
            "c) 10, 10",
            "d) Syntax error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "Which loop is most suitable to first perform the operation and then test the condition?",
        "Options": [
            "a) for loop",
            "b) while loop",
            "c) do-while loop",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "Which keyword can be used for coming out of recursion?",
        "Options": [
            "a) break",
            "b) return",
            "c) exit",
            "d) both break and return"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            a<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">continue</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            a<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Question": "The keyword ‘break’ cannot be simply used within _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) do-while",
            "b) if-else",
            "c) for",
            "d) while"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "Which keyword is used to come out of a loop only for that iteration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) break",
            "b) continue",
            "c) return",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                    <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hi <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hi is printed 5 times",
            "b) Hi is printed 9 times",
            "c) Hi is printed 7 times",
            "d) Hi is printed 4 times"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                    <span class=\"kw1\">continue</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hi <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hi is printed 9 times",
            "b) Hi is printed 8 times",
            "c) Hi is printed 7 times",
            "d) Hi is printed 6 times"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello is printed 5 times",
            "b) Hello is printed 4 times",
            "c) Hello",
            "d) Hello is printed 3 times"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">continue</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello is printed infinite times",
            "b) Hello",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello is printed infinite times",
            "b) Hello",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">     <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">do</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">continue</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"In while loop \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) In while loop 2",
            "b) In while loop in while loop 3",
            "c) In while loop 3",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">switch</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span> </pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">               <span class=\"kw1\">case</span> <span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                   <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                   <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                   <span class=\"kw2\">break</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"after loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a after loop",
            "b) a a after loop",
            "c) after loop",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"before continue \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">continue</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"after continue<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Before continue after continue",
            "b) Before continue",
            "c) After continue",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l2<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l2<span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 4",
            "b) Compilation error",
            "c) 1 2 4",
            "d) 1 3 4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span>l2<span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) 1 2 3",
            "c) 1 2",
            "d) 1 3"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1 <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"3 \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3",
            "b) 1 3",
            "c) 1 3 2",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            l1 <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Loop Loop",
            "b) Compilation error",
            "c) Loop Loop Loop Loop",
            "d) Infinite Loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) loop loop",
            "b) Compilation error",
            "c) loop loop loop loop",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) loop loop",
            "b) compilation error",
            "c) oop loop loop loop",
            "d) infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> label<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        label<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Infinite Hello",
            "d) Hello"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> label<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                label<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%03d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) hi hi hi 0 0 0",
            "c) 0 hi hi hi 0 0 0",
            "d) 0 0 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        label<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> label<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) Infinite 0",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> label<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            label<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hey\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) Hey",
            "c) 5 Hey",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "goto can be used to jump from main() to within a function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) false",
            "c) depends",
            "d) varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l2<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l2<span class=\"sy0\">:</span><span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 4",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 1 2 4",
            "d) 1 3 4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span>l2<span class=\"sy0\">:</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1 2 3",
            "c) 1 2",
            "d) 1 3"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"3 \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3",
            "b) 1 3",
            "c) 1 3 2",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) loop loop",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) loop loop loop loop",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) loop loop",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) loop loop loop loop",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        l1<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"loop<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                    <span class=\"kw1\">goto</span> l1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">                <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) loop loop",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) loop loop loop loop",
            "d) Infinite loop"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 1 2 1 2",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"1 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error as foo is local to main",
            "b) 1 2",
            "c) 2 1",
            "d) Compile time error due to declaration of functions inside main"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 2",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: Even though the answer is 2, this code will compile fine only with gcc. GNU C supports nesting of functions in C as a language extension whereas standard C compiler doesn’t. "
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> n<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) hi",
            "c) Infinite hi",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) hi",
            "c) Infinite hi",
            "d) hi hi"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a correct format for declaration of function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) return-type function-name(argument type);",
            "b) return-type function-name(argument type){}",
            "c) return-type (argument type)function-name;",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "Which of the following function declaration is illegal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int 1bhk(int);",
            "b) int 1bhk(int a);",
            "c) int 2bhk(int*, int []);",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "Can we use a function as a parameter of another function? [Eg: void wow(int func())].",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes, and we can use the function value conveniently",
            "b) Yes, but we call the function again to get the value, not as convenient as in using variable",
            "c) No, C does not support it",
            "d) This case is compiler dependent"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "The value obtained in the function is given back to main by using ________ keyword.",
        "Options": [
            "a) return",
            "b) static",
            "c) new",
            "d) volatile"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "What is the return-type of the function sqrt()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) float",
            "c) double",
            "d) depends on the data type of the parameter"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code having void return-type function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) Runtime error",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "4. What will be the data type returned for the following C function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">double</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"nu16\">5.0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) int",
            "c) double",
            "d) multiple type-casting in return is illegal"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "5. What is the problem in the following C declarations?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">   int func(int);\n   double func(int);\n   int func(float);</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) A function with same name cannot have different signatures",
            "b) A function with same name cannot have different return types",
            "c) A function with same name cannot have different number of parameters",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello 5",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) Junk value",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello 5 8",
            "b) hello 5",
            "c) hello followed by garbage value",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 8",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "What is the default return type if it is not specified in function definition?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void",
            "b) int",
            "c) double",
            "d) short int"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"2 \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "Functions can return structure in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "Functions can return enumeration constants in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) false",
            "c) depends on the compiler",
            "d) depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> m<span class=\"br0\">{</span>JAN<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> FEB<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MAR<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> m foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> m i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span>  foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> JAN<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 0",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Junk value",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) 3 3",
            "c) 3 5",
            "d) 3 4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3 3",
            "b) 3 4",
            "c) 3 5",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "Functions in C are always _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal",
            "b) External",
            "c) Both Internal and External",
            "d) External and Internal are not valid terms for functions"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "Global variables are ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal",
            "b) External",
            "c) Both Internal and External",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "7. Which of the following is an external variable in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> func <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        func <span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) b",
            "c) c",
            "d) d"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">     <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 11",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> var <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> var <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> var<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 8",
            "c) Compile time error due to wrong format identifier for double",
            "d) Compile time error due to redeclaration of variable with same name"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "1.  What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">       <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%g<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">       <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 0.000000",
            "c) Garbage value",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "2. Which part of the program address space is p stored in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Code/text segment",
            "b) Data segment",
            "c) Bss segment",
            "d) Stack"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "3. Which part of the program address space is p stored in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Code/text segment",
            "b) Data segment",
            "c) Bss segment",
            "d) Stack"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "4. Can variable i be accessed by functions in another source file?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Only if static keyword is used",
            "d) Depends on the type of the variable"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "Property of the external variable to be accessed by any source file is called by the C90 standard as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) external linkage",
            "b) external scope",
            "c) global scope",
            "d) global linkage"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) true only if NULL value is 0",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"true<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) true only if NULL value is 0",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw2\">extern</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"scope rules<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) scope rules",
            "b) Compile time error due to multiple declaration",
            "c) Compile time error due to not defining type in statement extern i",
            "d) Nothing will be printed as value of i is not zero because i is an automatic variable"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code (without linking the source file in which ary1 is defined)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw2\">extern</span> ary1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"scope rules<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) scope rules",
            "b) Linking error due to undefined reference",
            "c) Compile time error because size of array is not provided",
            "d) Compile time error because datatype of array is not provided"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code (after linking to source file having definition of ary1)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw2\">extern</span> ary1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ary1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Value of ary1[0];",
            "b) Compile time error due to multiple definition",
            "c) Compile time error because size of array is not provided",
            "d) Compile time error because datatype of array is not provided"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Question": "What is the scope of an external variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Whole source file in which it is defined",
            "b) From the point of declaration to the end of the file in which it is defined",
            "c) Any source file in a program",
            "d) From the point of declaration to the end of the file being compiled"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "What is the scope of a function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Whole source file in which it is defined",
            "b) From the point of declaration to the end of the file in which it is defined",
            "c) Any source file in a program",
            "d) From the point of declaration to the end of the file being compiled"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "6. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a is out of scope when printf is called",
            "b) Redeclaration of a in same scope throws error",
            "c) Syntax error in declaration of a",
            "d) No errors, program will show the output 5"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "7. Which variable has the longest scope in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) b",
            "c) c",
            "d) Both a and b"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "8. Comment on the following 2 C programs.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt; //Program 1</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt; //Program 2</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Both are same",
            "b) Scope of c is till the end of the main function in Program 2",
            "c) In Program 1, variables a, b and c can be used anywhere in the main function whereas in Program 2, variables b and c can be used only inside their respective blocks",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "1. What will be the sequence of allocation and deletion of variables in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a->b, a->b",
            "b) a->b, b->a",
            "c) b->a, a->b",
            "d) b->a, b->a"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "Array sizes are optional during array declaration by using ______ keyword.",
        "Options": [
            "a) auto",
            "b) static",
            "c) extern",
            "d) register"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        n<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> n<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8 3",
            "b) 3 8",
            "c) 8 5",
            "d) 5 3"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 4",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8",
            "b) 0",
            "c) Undefined",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6 7",
            "b) 6 6",
            "c) 5 5",
            "d) 5 6"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Junk value",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) Junkvalue",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) 0",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Junkvalue"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Infinite calls to main",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) main is called twice"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "Which of following is not accepted in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) static a = 10; //static as",
            "b) static int func (int); //parameter as static",
            "c) static static int a; //a static variable prefixed with static",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be static in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Variables",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Structures",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code if these two files namely test.c and test1.c are linked and run?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">      <span class=\"sy0\">-------</span>file test.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"sy0\">-------</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include \"\"test.h\"\"</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">%</span>d <span class=\"st0\">\"\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"sy0\">-----</span>file test1.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"sy0\">------</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include \"\"test.h\"\"</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">%</span>d\\n<span class=\"st0\">\"\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"sy0\">-----</span>file test.<span class=\"me1\">h</span><span class=\"sy0\">-----</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 0",
            "b) 0 0",
            "c) 10 10",
            "d) Compilation Error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "Functions have static qualifier for its declaration by default.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "Is initialisation mandatory for local static variables?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">12</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11 12 11 12",
            "b) 11 13 11 14",
            "c) 11 12 11 13",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "Assignment statements assigning value to local static variables are executed only once.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the code",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "What is the format identifier for “static a = 20.5;”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %s",
            "b) %d",
            "c) %f",
            "d) Illegal declaration due to absence of data type"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "Which of the following is true for the static variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It can be called from another function",
            "b) It exists even after the function ends",
            "c) It can be modified in another function by sending it as a parameter",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output will be 0",
            "b) Output will be 20",
            "c) Output will be a garbage value",
            "d) Compile time error due to redeclaration of static variable"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Depends on whether i is actually stored in machine register",
            "b) 10 10",
            "c) 11 11",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "register keyword mandates compiler to place it in machine register.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 11"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">auto</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 11"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 11"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer:  b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "Register storage class can be specified to global variables.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "Which among the following is wrong for “register int a;”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compiler generally ignores the request",
            "b) You cannot take the address of this variable",
            "c) Access time to a is critical",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"x is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 5",
            "c) Junk value",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "When compiler accepts the request to use the variable as a register?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is stored in CPU",
            "b) It is stored in cache memory",
            "c) It is stored in main memory",
            "d) It is stored in secondary memory"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "Which data type can be stored in register?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) long",
            "c) float",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation is not possible in a register variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reading the value into a register variable",
            "b) Copy the value from a memory variable",
            "c) Global declaration of register variable",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct syntax to declare a static variable register?",
        "Options": [
            "a) static register a;",
            "b) register static a;",
            "c) Both static register a; and register static a;",
            "d) We cannot use static and register together"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "Register variables reside in ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) stack",
            "b) registers",
            "c) heap",
            "d) main memory"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Segmentation fault",
            "b) main is called twice",
            "c) main is called once",
            "d) main is called thrice"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) Junk value",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">register</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Varies",
            "b) 0",
            "c) Junk value",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "What is the scope of an automatic variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Within the block it appears",
            "b) Within the blocks of the block it appears",
            "c) Until the end of program",
            "d) Within the block it appears & Within the blocks of the block it appears"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "Automatic variables are allocated space in the form of a __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) stack",
            "b) queue",
            "c) priority queue",
            "d) random"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a storage specifier?",
        "Options": [
            "a) enum",
            "b) union",
            "c) auto",
            "d) volatile"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "If storage class is not specified for a local variable, then the default class will be auto.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">auto</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">auto</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "Automatic variables are stored in ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) stack",
            "b) data segment",
            "c) register",
            "d) heap"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "What linkage does automatic variables have?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal linkage",
            "b) External linkage",
            "c) No linkage",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">auto</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">auto</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "Automatic variables are  _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Declared within the scope of a block, usually a function",
            "b) Declared outside all functions",
            "c) Declared with the auto keyword",
            "d) Declared within the keyword extern"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "What is the scope of an automatic variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exist only within that scope in which it is declared",
            "b) Cease to exist after the block is exited",
            "c) Exist only within that scope in which it is declared & exist after the block is exited",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "Automatic variables are allocated memory in ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) heap",
            "b) Data segment",
            "c) Code segment",
            "d) stack"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "4. What will be the x in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) automatic variable",
            "b) static variable",
            "c) register variable",
            "d) global variable"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 418,
        "Question": "Automatic variables are initialized to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Zero",
            "b) Junk value",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Both Zero & Junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 419,
        "Question": "Which of the following storage class supports char data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) register",
            "b) static",
            "c) auto",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 420,
        "Question": "A local variable declaration with no storage class specified is by default _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) auto",
            "b) extern",
            "c) static",
            "d) register"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 421,
        "Question": "Property which allows to produce different executable for different platforms in C is called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) File inclusion",
            "b) Selective inclusion",
            "c) Conditional compilation",
            "d) Recursive macros"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Conditional compilation is the preprocessor facility to produce a different executable."
    },
    {
        "id": 422,
        "Question": "What is #include <stdio.h>?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Preprocessor directive",
            "b) Inclusion directive",
            "c) File inclusion directive",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 423,
        "Question": "C preprocessors can have compiler specific features.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Depends on the platform"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: #pragma is compiler specific feature. "
    },
    {
        "id": 424,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define foo(m, n) m * n = 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"in main<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) In main",
            "b) Compilation error as lvalue is required for the expression m*n=10",
            "c) Preprocessor error as lvalue is required for the expression m*n=10",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Preprocessor just replaces whatever is given compiler then checks for error at the replaced part of the code. Here it is not replaced anywhere.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm1.c\n$ a.out\nin main\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 425,
        "Question": "C preprocessor is conceptually the first step during compilation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 426,
        "Question": "Preprocessor feature that supply line numbers and filenames to compiler is called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Selective inclusion",
            "b) macro substitution",
            "c) Concatenation",
            "d) Line control"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 427,
        "Question": "#include <somefile.h> are _______ files and #include “somefile.h” ________ files.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Library, Library",
            "b) Library, user-created header",
            "c) User-created header, library",
            "d) They can include all types of file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both of these statement can be used to select any file."
    },
    {
        "id": 428,
        "Question": "What is a preprocessor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) That processes its input data to produce output that is used as input to another program",
            "b) That is nothing but a loader",
            "c) That links various source files",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A preprocessor is a program that processes its input data to produce output that is used as input to another program."
    },
    {
        "id": 429,
        "Question": "Which of the following are C preprocessors?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #ifdef",
            "b) #define",
            "c) #endif",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 430,
        "Question": "#include statement must be written __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Before main()",
            "b) Before any scanf/printf",
            "c) After main()",
            "d) It can be written anywhere"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: Using these directives before main() improves readability."
    },
    {
        "id": 431,
        "Question": "#pragma exit is primarily used for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Checking memory leaks after exiting the program",
            "b) Informing Operating System that program has terminated",
            "c) Running a function at exiting the program",
            "d) No such preprocessor exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is primarily used for running a function upon exiting the program."
    },
    {
        "id": 432,
        "Question": "4.  What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> one <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> two <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef next</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        one <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        two <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> one<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> two<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1, 1",
            "b) 1, 2",
            "c) 2, 1",
            "d) 2, 2"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 433,
        "Question": "The C-preprocessors are specified with _________symbol.",
        "Options": [
            "a) #",
            "b) $",
            "c) ” ”",
            "d) &"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: The C-preprocessors are specified with # symbol."
    },
    {
        "id": 434,
        "Question": "What is #include directive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tells the preprocessor to grab the text of a file and place it directly into the current file",
            "b) Statements are not typically placed at the top of a program",
            "c) All of the mentioned",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: The #include directive tells the preprocessor to grab the text of a file and place it directly into the current file and are statements are typically placed at the top of a program."
    },
    {
        "id": 435,
        "Question": "The preprocessor provides the ability for _______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) The inclusion of header files",
            "b) The inclusion of macro expansions",
            "c) Conditional compilation and line control",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: The preprocessor provides the ability for the inclusion of header files, macro expansions, conditional compilation, and line control."
    },
    {
        "id": 436,
        "Question": "If #include is used with file name in angular brackets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) The file is searched for in the standard compiler include paths",
            "b) The search path is expanded to include the current source directory",
            "c) The search path will expand",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: With the #include, if the filename is enclosed within angle brackets, the file is searched for in the standard compiler include paths."
    },
    {
        "id": 437,
        "Question": "What is the sequence for preprocessor to look for the file within <>?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The predefined location then the current directory",
            "b) The current directory then the predefined location",
            "c) The predefined location only",
            "d) The current directory location"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: <> first searches the predefined location for the specified file and then the current directory. "
    },
    {
        "id": 438,
        "Question": "Which directory the compiler first looks for the file when using #include?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Current directory where program is saved",
            "b) C:COMPILERINCLUDE",
            "c) S:SOURCEHEADERS",
            "d) Both C:COMPILERINCLUDE and S:SOURCEHEADERS simultaneously"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 439,
        "Question": "What would happen if you create a file stdio.h and use #include “stdio.h”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The predefined library file will be selected",
            "b) The user-defined library file will be selected",
            "c) Both the files will be included",
            "d) The compiler won’t accept the program"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 440,
        "Question": "How is search done in #include and #include “somelibrary.h” according to C standard?",
        "Options": [
            "a) When former is used, current directory is searched and when latter is used, standard directory is searched",
            "b) When former is used, standard directory is searched and when latter is used, current directory is searched",
            "c) When former is used, search is done in implementation defined manner and when latter is used, current directory is searched",
            "d) For both, search for ‘somelibrary’ is done in implementation-defined places"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 441,
        "Question": "How is search done in #include and #include”somelibrary.h” normally or conventionally?",
        "Options": [
            "a) When former is used, current directory is searched and when latter is used, standard directory is searched",
            "b) When former is used, predefined directory is searched and when latter is used, current directory is searched and then predefined directories are searched",
            "c) When former is used, search is done in implementation defined manner and latter is used to search current directory",
            "d) For both, search for somelibrary is done in implementation-defined manner"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 442,
        "Question": "Can function definition be present in header files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 443,
        "Question": "7. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include \"test.h\"</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include \"test.h\"</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co1\">//some code</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) False",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 444,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(m, n) m ## n</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> myfunc<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        myfunc<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> myfunc<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 23",
            "b) 2 3",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 445,
        "Question": "If the file name is enclosed in double quotation marks, then _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) The preprocessor treats it as a user-defined file",
            "b) The preprocessor treats it as a system-defined file",
            "c) The preprocessor treats it as a user-defined file & system-defined file",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 446,
        "Question": "If the file name is enclosed in angle brackets, then ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) The preprocessor treats it as a user-defined file",
            "b) The preprocessor treats it as a system-defined file",
            "c) The preprocessor treats it as a user-defined file & system-defined file",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 447,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code snippet?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include (stdio.h)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: File to be included must be specified either in “” or <>.\nOutput:\n$ cc pgm1.c\npgm1.c:1: error: #include expects “FILENAME” or\npgm1.c: In function ‘main’:\npgm1.c:4: warning: incompatible implicit declaration of built-in function ‘printf’ "
    },
    {
        "id": 448,
        "Question": "4. The below two lines are equivalent to ________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define C_IO_HEADER &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include C_IO_HEADER</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) #include<stdlib.h>",
            "b) #include”printf”",
            "c) #include”C_IO_HEADER”",
            "d) #include<stdio.h>"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Since C_IO_HEADER is defined to be <stdio.h>, the second line becomes #include<stdio.h>, since C_IO_HEADER is replaced with <stdio.h> "
    },
    {
        "id": 449,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include \"printf\"</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) Error",
            "c) Depends on compiler",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 450,
        "Question": "Which of the following file extensions are accepted with #include?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .h",
            "b) .in",
            "c) .com",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:  d\nExplanation: The preprocessor will include whatever file extension you specify in your #include statement. However, it is not a good practice as another person debugging it will find it difficult in finding files you have included. "
    },
    {
        "id": 451,
        "Question": "Which of the following names for files not accepted?",
        "Options": [
            "a) header.h.h",
            "b) 123header.h",
            "c) _head_er.h",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All file names are accepted as for the execution to occur. There are no constraints on giving file names for inclusion. "
    },
    {
        "id": 452,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(m, n) m ## n</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) k l",
            "b) kl",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 453,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(m, n) \" m ## n \"</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) k l",
            "b) kl",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) m ## n"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 454,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(x, y) #x #y</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> l<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) kl",
            "b) k l",
            "c) xy",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 455,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(x, y) x / y + x</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Divided by zero exception",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) -8",
            "d) -4"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 456,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(x, y) x / y + x</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -8",
            "b) -4",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 457,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#define max 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> max <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100",
            "b) Compile time error since #define cannot be inside functions",
            "c) Compile time error since max is not visible in f()",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 458,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(x, y) x / y + x</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -8 -4",
            "b) -4 divided by zero exception",
            "c) -4 -4",
            "d) Divided by zero exception"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 459,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define foo(x, y) x / y + x</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#undef foo</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -8 -4",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) -8 -8",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 460,
        "Question": "What is the advantage of #define over const?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data type is flexible",
            "b) Can have a pointer",
            "c) Reduction in the size of the program",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 461,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#define max 37;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> max<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 37",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 462,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#define max 37</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> max<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 37",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 463,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#define const int</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> max <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">32</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> max<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) 32",
            "c) int",
            "d) const"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 464,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#define max 45</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        max <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">32</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> max<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 32",
            "b) 45",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 465,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\"># define max</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        max<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) hi hi",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) hi"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 466,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define A 1 + 2</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define B 3 + 4</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> var <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> A <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> B<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> var<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 11",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 21"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 467,
        "Question": "8. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define var 20);</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> var</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No errors, it will show the output 20",
            "b) Compile time error, the printf braces aren’t closed",
            "c) Compile time error, there are no open braces in #define",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer:  d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 468,
        "Question": "Which of the following properties of #define is not true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) You can use a pointer to #define",
            "b) #define can be made externally available",
            "c) They obey scope rules",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 469,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define SYSTEM 20</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#if SYSTEM == a</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"HELLO \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#if SYSTEM == 20</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"WORLD<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) HELLO",
            "b) WORLD",
            "c) HELLO WORLD",
            "d) No Output"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 470,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define Cprog</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef Cprog</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> Cprog<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No output on execution",
            "b) Output as 1",
            "c) Output as 2",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 471,
        "Question": "The “else if” in conditional inclusion is written by?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #else if",
            "b) #elseif",
            "c) #elsif",
            "d) #elif"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 472,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define COLD</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef COLD</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"COLD<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#undef COLD</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef COLD</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"HOT<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) HOT",
            "b) COLD",
            "c) COLD HOT",
            "d) No Output"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 473,
        "Question": "In a conditional inclusion, if the condition that comes after the if is true, then what will happen during compilation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Then the code up to the following #else or #elif or #endif is compiled",
            "b) Then the code up to the following #endif is compiled even if #else or #elif is present",
            "c) Then the code up to the following #eliif is compiled",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 474,
        "Question": "Conditional inclusion can be used for ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Preventing multiple declarations of a variable",
            "b) Check for existence of a variable and doing something if it exists",
            "c) Preventing multiple declarations of same function",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 475,
        "Question": "For each #if, #ifdef, and #ifndef directive.",
        "Options": [
            "a) There are zero or more #elif directives",
            "b) Zero or one #else directive",
            "c) One matching #endif directive",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 476,
        "Question": "The #else directive is used for _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Conditionally include source text if the previous #if, #ifdef, #ifndef, or #elif test fails",
            "b) Conditionally include source text if a macro name is not defined",
            "c) Conditionally include source text if a macro name is defined",
            "d) Ending conditional text"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 477,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MIN 0</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#if MIN</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MAX<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MIN<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 478,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MIN 0</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef MIN</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MAX<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MIN<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 479,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MIN 0</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#if defined(MIN) + defined(MAX)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MAX<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MIN<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Somegarbagevalue 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 480,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MIN 0</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#if defined(MIN) - (!defined(MAX))</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MAX<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MIN<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Somegarbagevalue 0"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 481,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MIN 0</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef(MIN)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MAX<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MIN<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) Preprocessor error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 482,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MIN 0);</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef MIN</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 10</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MAX<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> MIN</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 0",
            "b) Compile time error due to illegal syntax for printf",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Compile time error due to illegal MIN value"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 483,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\" p \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"nullp\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"q<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\" nullq<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) nullp nullq",
            "b) Depends on the compiler",
            "c) x nullq where x can be p or nullp depending on the value of NULL",
            "d) p q"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 484,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Segmentation fault/runtime crash",
            "c) 10",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 485,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 10",
            "d) 0.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 486,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Segmentation fault/runtime crash since pointer to local variable is returned",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 487,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Segmentation fault/runtime crash",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: We are returning address of a local variable which should not be done. In this specific instance, we are able to see the value of 10, which may not be the case if we call other functions before calling printf() in main()."
    },
    {
        "id": 488,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) ptr is a pointer to integer, p is not",
            "b) ptr and p, both are pointers to integer",
            "c) ptr is a pointer to integer, p may or may not be",
            "d) ptr and p both are not pointers to integer"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 489,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">+=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d,%d/n\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10,10",
            "b) 10,11",
            "c) 11,10",
            "d) 11,11"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 490,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) You cannot change the value pointed by ptr",
            "b) You cannot change the pointer ptr itself",
            "c) You May or may not change the value pointed by ptr",
            "d) You can change the pointer as well as the value pointed by it"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 491,
        "Question": "Which is an indirection operator among the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a) &",
            "b) *",
            "c) ->",
            "d) ."
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 492,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not initialize ptr to null (assuming variable declaration of a as int a=0;)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int *ptr = &a;",
            "b) int *ptr = &a – &a;",
            "c) int *ptr = a – a;",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 493,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span> \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same address",
            "b) Different address",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 494,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span> \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 0xbfd605e8 0xbfd605ec",
            "d) 0xbfd605e8 0xbfd605e8"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 495,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span> \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0xbfd605e8 0xbfd605ec",
            "b) 0xbfd605e8 0cbfd60520",
            "c) 0xbfd605e8 0xbfd605e9",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 496,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) Address of 5",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 497,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Address of x",
            "b) Junk value",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 498,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Some garbage value",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Segmentation fault/code crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 499,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) Some garbage value",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Segmentation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 500,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">float</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">float</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10.000000",
            "b) 0.000000",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 97",
            "b) 2 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Segmentation fault/code crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 2",
            "b) 2 97",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Segmentation fault/code crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 10",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 10 11"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11 11 11",
            "b) 11 11 Undefined-value",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Segmentation fault/code-crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11 11",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Segmentation fault/code-crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to send an array as a parameter to function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) func(&array);",
            "b) func(#array);",
            "c) func(*array);",
            "d) func(array[size]);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "Question": "Which of the following can never be sent by call-by-value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Variable",
            "b) Array",
            "c) Structures",
            "d) Both Array and Structures"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "Question": "Which type of variables can have the same name in a different function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Global variables",
            "b) Static variables",
            "c) Function arguments",
            "d) Both static variables and Function arguments"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "Question": "Arguments that take input by user before running a program are called?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Main function arguments",
            "b) Main arguments",
            "c) Command-Line arguments",
            "d) Parameterized arguments"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "Question": "What is the maximum number of arguments that can be passed in a single function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 127",
            "b) 253",
            "c) 361",
            "d) No limits in number of arguments"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> temp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> temp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 6",
            "b) 6 5",
            "c) 5 5",
            "d) 6 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0 0 0 0 0",
            "b) 6 5 3 0 0",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) 6 5 3 junk junk"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> q<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> temp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        q <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> temp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 6",
            "b) 5 5",
            "c) 6 5",
            "d) 6 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> q<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 6 5",
            "c) 6 junk value",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> m<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m<span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 6 5",
            "c) 6 junk value",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%p\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same address is printed",
            "b) Different address is printed",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%p\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Different address is printed",
            "b) Same address is printed",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) h h",
            "c) h e",
            "d) h l"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>  s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) h e",
            "b) l l",
            "c) l o",
            "d) l e"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span>p<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) h h",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) l l",
            "d) e e"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 521,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 10",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 10 1",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 522,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ary <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Some garbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 523,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ary <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 3",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 2 4",
            "d) 2 somegarbagevalue"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 524,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Some garbage value",
            "d) Undefined variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 525,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ary <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 5",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 526,
        "Question": "4. What are the elements present in the array of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">   int a = 0,  b = 0,  c = 0;\n   int array[5] = {a, b, c};</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5, 5, 5, 5, 5",
            "b) 5, 0, 0, 0, 0",
            "c) 5, (garbage), (garbage), (garbage), (garbage)",
            "d) (garbage), (garbage), (garbage), (garbage), 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 527,
        "Question": "An array of similar data types which themselves are a collection of dissimilar data type are ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linked Lists",
            "b) Trees",
            "c) Array of Structure",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 528,
        "Question": "Comment on an array of the void data type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) It can store any data-type",
            "b) It only stores element of similar data type to first element",
            "c) It acquires the data type with the highest precision in it",
            "d) You cannot have an array of void data type"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 529,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">   int size = 3;\n   int array[size] = {1, 2, 3};</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 530,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ptr <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%u\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 102",
            "b) 104",
            "c) 108",
            "d) 116"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation:None"
    },
    {
        "id": 531,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 5",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 532,
        "Question": "What is the size of *ptr in a 32-bit machine (Assuming initialization as int *ptr = 10;)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 533,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) h e",
            "b) e l",
            "c) h h",
            "d) e e"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 534,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) e h",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) h h",
            "d) h e"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 535,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"cjn\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) h e",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) c o",
            "d) h n"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 536,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) h e",
            "b) l e",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) l h"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 537,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) l e",
            "b) h e",
            "c) l l",
            "d) h l"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 538,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Segmentation fault",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 539,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Segmentation fault",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 540,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>b<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -3",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 4",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 541,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ptr <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 542,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>  <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ptr <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 3",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 543,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ptr <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 4",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 544,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>strc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"good morning<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>strc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> strc<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello, world",
            "b) Crash/segmentation fault",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 545,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> strc<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"good morning india<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>strc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> strc<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello world",
            "b) hello worldg india",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 546,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world!!<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> strc<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"good morning<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>strc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> strc<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello, world!!",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Segmenation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 547,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'.'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello. world",
            "b) hello, world",
            "c) Compile error",
            "d) Segmentation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 548,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'.'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello. world",
            "b) hello, world",
            "c) Compile error",
            "d) Segmentation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 549,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> strary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>strary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11 11",
            "b) 12 12",
            "c) 4 12",
            "d) 4 11"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 550,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> strary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>strary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11 11",
            "b) 12 11",
            "c) 11 12",
            "d) x 11 where x can be any positive integer."
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 551,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'m'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) l",
            "b) e",
            "c) h",
            "d) o"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 552,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) h"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 553,
        "Question": "1. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"This\"</span> <span class=\"co1\">//Line 1</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Program<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//Line 2</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//Line 3</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s, %s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//Line 4</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Memory holding “this” is cleared at line 3",
            "b) Memory holding “this” loses its reference at line 3",
            "c) You cannot assign pointer like in Line 3",
            "d) Output will be This, Program"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 554,
        "Question": "What type of initialization is needed for the segment “ptr[3] = ‘3’;” to work?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char *ptr = “Hello!”;",
            "b) char ptr[] = “Hello!”;",
            "c) both char *ptr = “Hello!”; and char ptr[] = “Hello!”;",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 555,
        "Question": "What is the syntax for constant pointer to address (i.e., fixed pointer address)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) const <type> * <name>",
            "b) <type> * const <name>",
            "c) <type> const * <name>",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 556,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> add<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fn_ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        fn_ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> add<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The sum of two numbers is: %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>fn_ptr<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error, declaration of a function inside main",
            "b) Compile time error, no definition of function fn_ptr",
            "c) Compile time error, illegal application of statement fn_ptr = add",
            "d) No Run time error, output is 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 557,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) int (*fn_ptr)(int, int) = multi;",
            "b) int *fn_ptr(int, int) = multi;",
            "c) int *fn_ptr(int, int) = &multi;",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 558,
        "Question": "Calling a function f with a an array variable a[3] where a is an array, is equivalent to __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) f(a[3])",
            "b) f(*(a + 3))",
            "c) f(3[a])",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 559,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>k<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'m'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) h",
            "b) e",
            "c) m",
            "d) o;"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 560,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) h",
            "c) e",
            "d) o"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 561,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 5 5",
            "b) 5 5 junk value",
            "c) 5 junk junk",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 562,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 5 5",
            "b) 5 5 junk value",
            "c) 5 junk junk",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 563,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 6",
            "d) Junk"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 564,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">**</span>r<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Address of a",
            "d) Junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 565,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p %p\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>r<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Different address is printed",
            "b) 1 2",
            "c) Same address is printed",
            "d) 1 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 566,
        "Question": "How many number of pointer (*) does C have against a pointer variable declaration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7",
            "b) 127",
            "c) 255",
            "d) No limits"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 567,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr2 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr3 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>sptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//-Ref</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>sptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ptr2<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ptr1 points to a",
            "b) ptr1 points to b",
            "c) sptr points to ptr2",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 568,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p %p\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>r<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Different address is printed",
            "b) 1 2",
            "c) Same address is printed",
            "d) 1 1"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 569,
        "Question": "1. What substitution should be made to //-Ref such that ptr1 points to variable c in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>sptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"co1\">//-Ref</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) *sptr = &c;",
            "b) **sptr = &c;",
            "c) *ptr1 = &c;",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 570,
        "Question": "Which of the following declaration will result in run-time error?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int **c = &c;",
            "b) int **c = &*c;",
            "c) int **c = **c;",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 571,
        "Question": "3. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">-=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) You cannot apply any arithmetic operand to a pointer",
            "b) We don’t have address of an address operator",
            "c) We have address of an address operator",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 572,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 5 5",
            "b) 5 5 junk value",
            "c) 5 junk junk",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 573,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 5 5",
            "b) 5 5 junk value",
            "c) 5 junk junk",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 574,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) 6",
            "d) Junk"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 575,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">**</span>r<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Address of a",
            "d) Junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 576,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span>j<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 4 5 0",
            "b) 1 2 3 4 5 junk",
            "c) 1 2 3 4 5 5",
            "d) Run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 577,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span>j<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2 3 junk 4 5",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 1 2 3 0 4 5",
            "d) 1 2 3 3 4 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 578,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span>j<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0 3 0 0 0 0",
            "b) Junk 3 junk junk junk junk",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) All junk values"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 579,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span>j<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0 3 0 0 0 0",
            "b) Junk 3 junk junk junk junk",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) All junk values"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 580,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>j <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span>j<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0 3 0 0 0 0",
            "b) Junk 3 junk junk junk junk",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) All junk values"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 581,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) An array “a” of pointers",
            "b) A pointer “a” to an array",
            "c) A ragged array",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 582,
        "Question": "7. Comment on the following 2 arrays with respect to P and Q.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a2<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   P. <span class=\"me1\">Array</span> of pointers</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">   Q. <span class=\"me1\">Pointer</span> to an array</pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a1 is P, a2 is Q",
            "b) a1 is P, a2 is P",
            "c) a1 is Q, a2 is P",
            "d) a1 is Q, a2 is Q"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 583,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not possible statically in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Jagged Array",
            "b) Rectangular Array",
            "c) Cuboidal Array",
            "d) Multidimensional Array"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 584,
        "Question": "What is the correct syntax to send a 3-dimensional array as a parameter? (Assuming declaration int a[5][4][3];)",
        "Options": [
            "a) func(a);",
            "b) func(&a);",
            "c) func(*a);",
            "d) func(**a);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 585,
        "Question": "What are the applications of a multidimensional array?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Matrix-Multiplication",
            "b) Minimum Spanning Tree",
            "c) Finding connectivity between nodes",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 586,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span>k<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 2",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 10 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 587,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span>k<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 2",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) segmentation fault/code crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 588,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 20",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 589,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 20",
            "c) Address of j",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 590,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 591,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to declare a 3 dimensional array using pointers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char *a[][];",
            "b) char **a[];",
            "c) char ***a;",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 592,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"p\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"r\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"o\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"g\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"r\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"m\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output will be program",
            "b) Output will be p",
            "c) No output",
            "d) Compile-time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 593,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"how\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) segmentation fault",
            "b) hi hello how followed by 7 null values",
            "c) 10 null values",
            "d) depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 594,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"how\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi hello how Segmentation fault",
            "b) hi hello how followed by 7 null values",
            "c) hey hello how Segmentation fault",
            "d) depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 595,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code on a 32-bit system?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"how\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 13",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) 40"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 596,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code on a 32-bit system?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"how\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: If the system is 32-bit system, then the size of pointer will be 4 bytes. For such a system, the size of array a will be 4×10 = 40 bytes. The size of pointer is 8 bytes on a 64 bit system. For the given array a of 10 elements, it will be 8×10 = 80 bytes. "
    },
    {
        "id": 597,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"how\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hi hello how Segmentation fault",
            "b) hi hello how null",
            "c) hey hello how Segmentation fault",
            "d) hi hello how followed by 7 nulls"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: Array element a[1] is storing an address of character pointer. For a 32-bit systems its 4 bytes and for a 64-bit system, its 8 bytes. "
    },
    {
        "id": 598,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) hello",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 599,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"bye\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Address of hello"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 600,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Some garbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Some garbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 1",
            "d) Some garbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "Question": "Which of the following declaration are illegal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int a[][] = {{1, 2, 3}, {2, 3, 4, 5}};",
            "b) int *a[] = {{1, 2, 3}, {2, 3, 4, 5}};",
            "c) int a[4][4] = {{1, 2, 3}, {2, 3, 4, 5}};",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "Question": "Which is true for a, if a is defined as “int a[10][20];”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) a is true two-dimensional array",
            "b) 200 int-sized locations have been set aside",
            "c) The conventional rectangular subscript calculation 20 * row  + col is used to find the element a[row, col].",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "Question": "Which is true for b, if b is defined as “int *b[10];”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The definition only allocates 10 pointers and does not initialize them",
            "b) Initialization must be done explicitly",
            "c) The definition only allocates 10 pointers and does not initialize them & Initialization must be done explicitly",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"fellows\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) fellows",
            "b) fellow",
            "c) fello",
            "d) fell"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since every row in the array a[10][5] can contain only 5 characters, the a[2] element will hold “fello” i.e. 5 characters. There will not be any null character in a[2]. Since, the array is completely intialized, other rows (row a[3] will have only null characters. Hence, printf() using %s specifier will display fello only. "
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"fellows\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) same address is printed",
            "b) different address is printed",
            "c) hello",
            "d) hi hello fello"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"fellows\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) hellon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) hellon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) P are static, Q are static",
            "b) P are static, Q are dynamic",
            "c) P are dynamic, Q are static",
            "d) P are dynamic, Q are dynamic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code (considering sizeof char is 1 and pointer is 4)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 12",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) hi",
            "c) ello",
            "d) ello hi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) ello",
            "c) hi",
            "d) ello hi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "Question": "What is the advantage of a multidimensional array over pointer array?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Predefined size",
            "b) Input can be taken from user",
            "c) Faster Access",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation is possible using a pointer char? (Assuming the declaration is char *a;)",
        "Options": [
            "a) Input via %s",
            "b) Generation of the multidimensional array",
            "c) Changing address to point at another location",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "Question": "7. Comment on the following two operations.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">    int *a[] = {{1, 2, 3}, {1, 2, 3, 4}}; //- 1\n    int b[4][4] = {{1, 2, 3}, {1, 2, 3, 4}};//- 2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 will work, 2 will not",
            "b) 1 and 2, both will work",
            "c) 1 won’t work, 2 will work",
            "d) Neither of them will work"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "Question": "8. Comment on the following two operations.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">    int *a[] = {{1, 2, 3}, {1, 2, 3, 4}}; //- 1\n    int b[][] = {{1, 2, 3}, {1, 2, 3, 4}}; //- 2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 works, 2 doesn’t",
            "b) 2 works, 1 doesn’t",
            "c) Both of them work",
            "d) Neither of them work"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "Question": "In linux, argv[0] by command-line argument can be occupied by _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ./a.out",
            "b) ./test",
            "c) ./fun.out.out",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 621,
        "Question": "What type of array is generally generated in Command-line argument?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Single dimension array",
            "b) 2-Dimensional Square Array",
            "c) Jagged Array",
            "d) 2-Dimensional Rectangular Array"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 622,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C statement? (assuming the input is “cool brother in city”)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">  <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>s\\n”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span>argc<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) (null)",
            "b) City",
            "c) In",
            "d) Segmentation Fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: All the options mentioned (./a.out, ./test, ./fun.out.out) are simply the command without any argument. A command is always stored as argument vector zero i.e., argv[0] always contain the command where as argv[1], argv[2], etc. contains the arguments to the commands, if any."
    },
    {
        "id": 623,
        "Question": "What is the first argument in command line arguments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The number of command-line arguments the program was invoked with;",
            "b) A pointer to an array of character strings that contain the arguments",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 624,
        "Question": "What is the second argument in command line arguments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The number of command-line arguments the program was invoked with;",
            "b) A pointer to an array of character strings that contain the arguments, one per string",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 625,
        "Question": "What is argv[0] in command line arguments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The name by which the program was invoked",
            "b) The name of the files which are passed to the program",
            "c) Count of the arguments in argv[] vector",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 626,
        "Question": "A program that has no command line arguments will have argc _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Zero",
            "b) Negative",
            "c) One",
            "d) Two"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 627,
        "Question": "What is the index of the last argument in command line arguments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) argc – 2",
            "b) argc + 1",
            "c) argc",
            "d) argc – 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 628,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code (if run with no options or arguments)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> argc<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 629,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code (run without any command line arguments)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>argc<span class=\"sy0\">--</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span>argc<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Executablefilename",
            "c) Segmentation fault",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 630,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code (run without any command line arguments)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span>argc<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "b) Executable file name",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 631,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code (run without any command line arguments)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"sy0\">++</span> <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span> NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "b) Executable file name",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 632,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code (run without any command line arguments)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv  <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span>  NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>argv<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "b) Executable file name",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 633,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code (run without any command line arguments)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>argv <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span> NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>  <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>argv<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "b) Executable file name",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 634,
        "Question": "1. Which function is not called in the following C program?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> first<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"first\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> second<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        first<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> third<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        second<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> third<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Function first",
            "b) Function second",
            "c) Function third",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 635,
        "Question": "How to call a function without using the function name to send parameters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) typedefs",
            "b) Function pointer",
            "c) Both typedefs and Function pointer",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 636,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a correct syntax to pass a Function Pointer as an argument?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void pass(int (*fptr)(int, float, char)){}",
            "b) void pass(*fptr(int, float, char)){}",
            "c) void pass(int (*fptr)){}",
            "d) void pass(*fptr){}"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 637,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not possible in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Array of function pointer",
            "b) Returning a function pointer",
            "c) Comparison of function pointer",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 638,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> first<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello World\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> first<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr<span class=\"sy0\">++</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Illegal application of ++ to void data type",
            "b) pointer function initialized like a variable",
            "c) Illegal application of ++ to void data type & pointer function initialized like a variable",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 639,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> mul<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>function_pointer<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        function_pointer  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>  mul<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The product of three numbers is:%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        function_pointer<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The product of three numbers is:24",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 640,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> mul<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>function_pointer<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        function_pointer <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> mul<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The product of three numbers is:%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        function_pointer<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The product of three numbers is:24",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 641,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> myfoo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fooptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        fooptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        fooptr<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> myfoo<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> myfoo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 11",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 642,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> mul<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>function_pointer<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        function_pointer <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> mul<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The product of three numbers is:%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        function_pointer<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The product of three numbers is:24",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 643,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> sub<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>function_pointer<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        function_pointer <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>sub<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The difference of three numbers is:%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>function_pointer<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The difference of three numbers is:1",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) The difference of three numbers is:-5",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 644,
        "Question": "One of the uses for function pointers in C is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) There are no function pointers in c",
            "c) To invoke a function",
            "d) To call a function defined at run-time"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 645,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 646,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 647,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 10.000000",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 648,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> myfoo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> myfoo<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> myfoo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 10 11",
            "d) 10 Segmentation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 649,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> myfoo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> myfoo<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>foo<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        i<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> myfoo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 11",
            "b) 11",
            "c) 10",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 650,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        no <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> no<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Junk",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 651,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 652,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 653,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 654,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Junk",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 655,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Junk",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 656,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"after x<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) After x",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 657,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        y <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        y<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> foo<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2.000000",
            "b) 1 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Segmentation fault/code crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 658,
        "Question": "9. What does this declaration say?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">int (*(*y)())[2];</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) y is pointer to the function which returns pointer to integer array",
            "b) y is pointer to the function which returns array of pointers",
            "c) y is function which returns function pointer which in turn returns pointer to integer array",
            "d) y is function which returns array of integers"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 659,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> foo<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 1 2.000000",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 660,
        "Question": "11. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> foo<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 1 2.000000",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 661,
        "Question": "1. Read the following expression?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">void (*ptr)(int);</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ptr is pointer to int that converts its type to void",
            "b) ptr is pointer to function passing int returning void",
            "c) ptr is pointer to void that converts its type to int",
            "d) ptr is pointer to function passing void returning int"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 662,
        "Question": "2. Which of the following expression is true for the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">ptr is array with 3 elements of pointer to function returning pointer of int</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) int **ptr[3]();",
            "b) int *(*ptr[3])();",
            "c) int (*(*ptr[3])());",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 663,
        "Question": "3. What makes the following declaration denote?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">int **ptr;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ptr is a function pointer that returns pointer to int type",
            "b) ptr is a pointer to an int pointer",
            "c) ptr is a pointer to pointer to type int",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 664,
        "Question": "4. What makes the following declaration denote?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">char *str[5];</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) str is an array of 5 element pointer to type char",
            "b) str is a pointer to an array of 5 elements",
            "c) str is a function pointer of 5 elements returning char",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 665,
        "Question": "5. Comment on the following declaration.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">    int (*ptr)(); // i)\n    char *ptr[]; // ii)</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Both i) and ii) and cannot exist due to same name",
            "b) i) is legal, ii) is illegal",
            "c) i) is illegal, ii) is legal",
            "d) Both i) and ii) will work legal and flawlessly"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 666,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 667,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 668,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 669,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Junk",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 670,
        "Question": "10. Is the below declaration legal?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">int* ((*x)())[2];</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 671,
        "Question": "Which of the following are themselves a collection of different data types?",
        "Options": [
            "a) string",
            "b) structures",
            "c) char",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 672,
        "Question": "User-defined data type can be derived by___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) struct",
            "b) enum",
            "c) typedef",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 673,
        "Question": "Which operator connects the structure name to its member name?",
        "Options": [
            "a) –",
            "b) <-",
            "c) .",
            "d) Both <- and ."
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 674,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be a structure member?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Another structure",
            "b) Function",
            "c) Array",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 675,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 676,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 677,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 678,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">no</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Junk",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 679,
        "Question": "10. Can the following C code be compiled successfully?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> .<span class=\"me1\">f</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> .<span class=\"me1\">k</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x.<span class=\"me1\">f</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes",
            "b) No",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Depends on the platform"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 680,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> no<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        no <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> no<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Junk",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 681,
        "Question": "2. How many bytes in memory taken by the following C structure?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> test</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Multiple of integer size",
            "b) integer size+character size",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Multiple of word size"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 682,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">k</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">k</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Segmentation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 683,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">k</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">k</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 10",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 684,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        x.<span class=\"me1\">k</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x.<span class=\"me1\">k</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 10",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 685,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x.<span class=\"me1\">f</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 0.000000 10",
            "c) Somegarbage value 10",
            "d) 0 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 686,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code according to C99 standard?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> .<span class=\"me1\">f</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> .<span class=\"me1\">k</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x.<span class=\"me1\">f</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.000000",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 1.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 687,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code according to C99 standard?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> .<span class=\"me1\">k</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x.<span class=\"me1\">f</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.000000",
            "b) 0.000000",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 688,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code according to C99 standard?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x.<span class=\"me1\">f</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.000000",
            "b) Somegarbagevalue",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 689,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"newton\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"alan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"turing\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) newton alan alan",
            "b) alan newton alan",
            "c) alan alan newton",
            "d) compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 690,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"st\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Junk values",
            "d) st st"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 691,
        "Question": "Which of the following return-type cannot be used for a function in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char *",
            "b) struct",
            "c) void",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 692,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp s<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        func<span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 (Garbage Value)",
            "b) 0 10",
            "c) 10 0",
            "d) (Garbage Value) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 693,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not possible under any scenario?",
        "Options": [
            "a) s1 = &s2;",
            "b) s1 = s2;",
            "c) (*s1).number = 10;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 694,
        "Question": "Which of the following operation is illegal in structures?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Typecasting of structure",
            "b) Pointer to a variable of the same structure",
            "c) Dynamic allocation of memory for structure",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 695,
        "Question": "Presence of code like “s.t.b = 10” indicates __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Syntax Error",
            "b) Structure",
            "c) double data type",
            "d) An ordinary variable name"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 696,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"alan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"turing\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) alan",
            "b) Turing",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 697,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"equal<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not equal<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) equal",
            "c) depends on the standard",
            "d) not equal"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 698,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> notpoint</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> notpoint p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p1.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point temp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> temp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 699,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> notpoint</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> notpoint p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p1.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 700,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> notpoint</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> notpoint p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"alan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) alan",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"alan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> fun<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) alan",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "Question": "1. The correct syntax to access the member of the ith structure in the array of structures is?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">Assuming<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp\n    <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">50</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) s.b.[i];",
            "b) s.[i].b;",
            "c) s.b[i];",
            "d) s[i].b;"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "Question": "2. Comment on the output of the following C code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No Compile time error, generates an array of structure of size 3",
            "b) No Compile time error, generates an array of structure of size 9",
            "c) Compile time error, illegal declaration of a multidimensional array",
            "d) Compile time error, illegal assignment to members of structure"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "Question": "Which of the following uses structure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Array of structures",
            "b) Linked Lists",
            "c) Binary Tree",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "Question": "What is the correct syntax to declare a function foo() which receives an array of structure in function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void foo(struct *var);",
            "b) void foo(struct *var[]);",
            "c) void foo(struct var);",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code? (Assuming size of int be 4)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 12",
            "c) 16",
            "d) Can’t be estimated due to ambiguous initialization of array"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"alan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"turing\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) alan alan alan turing",
            "b) alan alan turing turing",
            "c) alan turing alan turing",
            "d) run time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"alan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        r <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) alan alan",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"alan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) alan alan",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>  <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 2",
            "b) 2 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 1 somegarbagevalue",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1 0",
            "c) 1 somegarbagevalue",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1 0",
            "c) 1 somegarbagevalue",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> point p<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1 0",
            "c) 1 somegarbagevalue",
            "d) undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 721,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 16",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 722,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">92</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">94</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">96</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"falsen\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) false"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 723,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">92</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">94</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">96</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>ptr1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) false",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 724,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">*</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">*;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">92</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">94</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">96</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        q ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Segmentation fault"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 725,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">*</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">92</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">94</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">96</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> foo<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">*</span> p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        q ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Segmentation fault",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 726,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) *my_struct.b = 10;",
            "b) (*my_struct).b = 10;",
            "c) my_struct->b = 10;",
            "d) Both *my_struct.b = 10; and (*my_struct).b = 10;"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 727,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) func(&s.a);",
            "b) func(&(s).a);",
            "c) func(&(s.a));",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 728,
        "Question": "8. Which option is not possible for the following function call?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//where s is a variable of type struct and a is the member of the struct.</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compiler can access entire structure from the function",
            "b) Individual member’s address can be displayed in structure",
            "c) Individual member can be passed by reference in a function",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 729,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> change<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        change<span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> change<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp s<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output will be 1",
            "b) Output will be 10",
            "c) Output varies with machine",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 730,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">     <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">92</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">94</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">96</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"false<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1 5",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) false"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 731,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 732,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) Segmentation fault",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 733,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) hello",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 734,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span>.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Run time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) hello"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 735,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span>.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>%p<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Different address",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Same address"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 736,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> q</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> q <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p1.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 737,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> q</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> q <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p1.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 738,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 5",
            "b) 1 3",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) 1 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 739,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">92</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">94</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">96</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p1<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 1 3",
            "d) 1 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 740,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>point<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m.<span class=\"me1\">point</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">(</span>m.<span class=\"me1\">point</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%s<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hey hi",
            "b) hi hey",
            "c) Run time error",
            "d) hey hey"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 741,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>point<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        m.<span class=\"me1\">point</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">(</span>m.<span class=\"me1\">point</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) hey",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 742,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student point<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">c</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Varies",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 743,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>point<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 9",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 744,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>point<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>m <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>student<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 745,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">ptr</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 746,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        q ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">ptr</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Address of p"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 747,
        "Question": "Presence of loop in a linked list can be tested by ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Traveling the list, if NULL is encountered no loop exists",
            "b) Comparing the address of nodes by address of every other node",
            "c) Comparing the the value stored in a node by a value in every other node",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 748,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            q ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">ptr</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 749,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            q ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">ptr</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 750,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        q ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">ptr</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Segmenation fault",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 751,
        "Question": "4. The number of distinct nodes the following struct declaration can point to is _____________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> node</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> node <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>left<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> node <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>centre<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> node <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>right<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 752,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not possible regarding the structure variable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A structure variable pointing to itself",
            "b) A structure variable pointing to another structure variable of same type",
            "c) 2 different type of structure variable pointing at each other",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 753,
        "Question": "Which of the following technique is faster for travelling in binary trees?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Iteration",
            "b) Recursion",
            "c) Both Iteration and Recursion",
            "d) Depends from compiler to compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 754,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span>.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) h",
            "b) i",
            "c) e",
            "d) y"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 755,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"this\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) Varies",
            "c) this",
            "d) Compile time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 756,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> lookup<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> lookup<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 4",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 757,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"his\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"her\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hell\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hellos\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi's\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hmm\"</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) her",
            "b) hi",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) hi’s"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 758,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>name <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"xyz\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>next <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>name<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "c) xyz",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 759,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"xyz\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">next</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>name<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Segmentation fault",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) xyz"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 760,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"xyz\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">next</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>q.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>name<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Segmentation fault/code crash",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) xyz"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 761,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"xyz\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">next</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>q.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>name<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Depends on the compiler",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) xyz"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 762,
        "Question": "Which function is responsible for searching in the table? (For #define IN 1, the name IN and replacement text 1 are stored in a “table”)",
        "Options": [
            "a) findout(s);",
            "b) lookup(s);",
            "c) find(s);",
            "d) lookfor(s);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 763,
        "Question": "Which algorithm is used for searching in the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) List search",
            "b) Informed search",
            "c) Hash search",
            "d) Adversarial search"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 764,
        "Question": "Which function is responsible for recording the name “s” and the replacement text “t” in a table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) install(s, t);",
            "b) fix(s, t);",
            "c) setup(s, t);",
            "d) settle(s, t);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 765,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Install function uses lookup",
            "b) lookup function uses install",
            "c) Install and lookup function work independently",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 766,
        "Question": "What happens when install(s, t) finds that the name being installed is already present in the table?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It doesn’t modify the name in the table",
            "b) It modifies the name with new definition",
            "c) It modifies off the new definition has higher priority",
            "d) It creates a new table and add the new definition in it"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 767,
        "Question": "In what situation, install function returns NULL?",
        "Options": [
            "a) When there is no memory for adding new name",
            "b) When the name to be defined is already present in the table",
            "c) Whenever a new name is added to the table",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 768,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 1",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 769,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"xyz\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">next</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        q.<span class=\"me1\">name</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>q.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        q.<span class=\"me1\">next</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ptrary<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>name<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Depends on the compiler",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) xyz"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 770,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>stu<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> stu s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Varies",
            "c) hi",
            "d) h"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 771,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>stu<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hey\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Varies",
            "c) he",
            "d) hey"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 772,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> integer<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> f <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        integer j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 773,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> ptrfoo<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrfoo ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ary<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 774,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptrfoo<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptrfoo ptr1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        ptr1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> ary<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ary<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 775,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p k1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k1.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 776,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p k1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k1.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 777,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>k<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        k k1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k1.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 778,
        "Question": "2. Which option should be selected to work the following C expression?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">string p = \"HELLO\";</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) typedef char [] string;",
            "b) typedef char *string;",
            "c) typedef char [] string; and typedef char *string;",
            "d) Such expression cannot be generated in C"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 779,
        "Question": "3. Which of the given option is the correct method for initialization?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">typedef char *string;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) *string *p = “Hello”;",
            "b) string p = “Hello”;",
            "c) *string p = ‘A’;",
            "d) Not more than one space should be given when using typedef"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 780,
        "Question": "Which of the following is false about typedef?",
        "Options": [
            "a) typedef follow scope rules",
            "b) typedef defined substitutes can be redefined again. (Eg: typedef char a; typedef int a;)",
            "c) You cannot typedef a typedef with other term",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 781,
        "Question": "Which of the following may create problem in the typedef program?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ;",
            "b) printf/scanf",
            "c) Arithmetic operators",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 782,
        "Question": "typedef int (*PFI)(char *, char *)creates ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) type PFI, for pointer to function (of two char * arguments) returning int",
            "b) error",
            "c) type PFI, function (of two char * arguments) returning int",
            "d) type PFI, for pointer"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 783,
        "Question": "What is typedef declaration?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Does not create a new type",
            "b) It merely adds a new name for some existing type",
            "c) Does not create a new type, It merely adds a new name for some existing type",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 784,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> student</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>stu<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        stu s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s.<span class=\"me1\">a</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>s</pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Varies",
            "c) hi",
            "d) h"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 785,
        "Question": "The size of a union is determined by the size of the __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) First member in the union",
            "b) Last member in the union",
            "c) Biggest member in the union",
            "d) Sum of the sizes of all members"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 786,
        "Question": "2. Which member of the union will be active after REF LINE in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> temp s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu16\">2.5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>’A’<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"co1\">//REF LINE</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) b",
            "c) c",
            "d) Such declaration are illegal"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 787,
        "Question": "3. What would be the size of the following union declaration?  (Assuming size of double = 8, size of int = 4, size of char = 1)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> uTemp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 40",
            "d) 80"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 788,
        "Question": "4. What type of data is holded by variable u int in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u_tag</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ival<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> fval<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>sval<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Will be large enough to hold the largest of the three types;",
            "b) Will be large enough to hold the smallest of the three types;",
            "c) Will be large enough to hold the all of the three types;",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 789,
        "Question": "Members of a union are accessed as________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) union-name.member",
            "b) union-pointer->member",
            "c) both union-name.member & union-pointer->member",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 790,
        "Question": "6. In the following C code, we can access the 1st character of the string sval by using  _______<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>name<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>sval<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span> u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> symtab<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) *symtab[i].u.sval",
            "b) symtab[i].u.sval[0].",
            "c) You cannot have union inside structure",
            "d) Both *symtab[i].u.sval & symtab[i].u.sval[0]."
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 791,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code (Assuming size of int and float is 4)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ival<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> fval<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span> u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>u<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 32"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 792,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> stu</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ival<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> fval<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> stu r<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        r.<span class=\"me1\">ival</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> r.<span class=\"me1\">ival</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) 16",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 793,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) sizeof(int) + sizeof(char)",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) sizeof(int)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 794,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">60</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) sizeof(int) + sizeof(char)",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) sizeof(char)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 795,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">60</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        b.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">12</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Depends on the compiler",
            "c) 60",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 796,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 97",
            "c) a",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 797,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span>.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 97",
            "c) a",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 798,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Implementation dependent",
            "c) 10.000000",
            "d) 0.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 799,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3 and 4",
            "b) 1 and 2",
            "c) 1 and 3",
            "d) 1, 3 and 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 800,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code? (Assuming size of char = 1, int = 4, double = 8)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> utemp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        u.<span class=\"me1\">c</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'A'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        u.<span class=\"me1\">a</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>u<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 13"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 801,
        "Question": "Which of the following data types are accepted while declaring bit-fields?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) float",
            "c) double",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 802,
        "Question": "Which of the following reduces the size of a structure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) union",
            "b) bit-fields",
            "c) malloc",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 803,
        "Question": "4. For what minimum value of x in a 32-bit Linux OS would make the size of s equal to 8 bytes?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">13</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 32"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 804,
        "Question": "5. Calculate the % of memory saved when bit-fields are used for the following C structure as compared to with-out use of bit-fields for the same structure? (Assuming size of int = 4)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 25%",
            "b) 33.3%",
            "c) 50%",
            "d) 75%"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 805,
        "Question": "6. In the following declaration of bit-fields,  the constant-expression specifies __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">    struct-declarator:\n    declarator\n    type-specifier declarator opt : constant-expression</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The width of the field in bits",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) The width of the field in bytes",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 806,
        "Question": "7. In the following declaration of bit-fields, the constant-expression must be __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">    struct-declarator:\n    declarator\n    type-specifier declarator opt : constant-expression</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Any type",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Integer value",
            "d) Nonnegative integer value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 807,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not allowed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Arrays of bit fields",
            "b) Pointers to bit fields",
            "c) Functions returning bit fields",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 808,
        "Question": "Bit fields can only be declared as part of a structure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) false",
            "b) true",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 809,
        "Question": "10. What is the order for the following C declarations?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"txt\"><pre class=\"de1\">    short a : 17;\n    int long y : 33;</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Legal, legal",
            "b) Legal, illegal",
            "c) Illegal, illegal",
            "d) Illegal, legal"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 810,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) Compile time error",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 811,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 812,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 813,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Depends  on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 814,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u u <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 815,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> u u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> u.<span class=\"me1\">p</span>.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 816,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Depends  on the compiler",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 817,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 4",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 818,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">110</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 110",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 819,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">x</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p.<span class=\"me1\">y</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Depends  on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 820,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the odd one out?",
        "Options": [
            "a) printf",
            "b) fprintf",
            "c) putchar",
            "d) scanf"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 821,
        "Question": "For a typical program, the input is taken using _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) scanf",
            "b) Files",
            "c) Command-line",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 822,
        "Question": "3. What does the following command line signify?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"text\"><pre class=\"de1\">prog1|prog2</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) It runs prog1 first, prog2 second",
            "b) It runs prog2 first, prog1 second",
            "c) It runs both the programs, pipes output of prog1 to input of prog2",
            "d) It runs both the programs, pipes output of prog2 to input of prog1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 823,
        "Question": "What is the default return-type of getchar()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) int",
            "c) char *",
            "d) reading character doesn’t require a return-type"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 824,
        "Question": "What is the value of EOF?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 825,
        "Question": "What is the use of getchar()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The next input character each time it is called",
            "b) EOF when it encounters end of file",
            "c) The next input character each time it is called EOF when it encounters end of file",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 826,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The symbolic constant EOF is defined in <stdio.h>",
            "b) The value is -1",
            "c) The symbolic constant EOF is defined in <stdio.h> & value is -1",
            "d) Only value is -1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 827,
        "Question": "What is the return value of putchar()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The character written",
            "b) EOF if an error occurs",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Both character written & EOF if an error occurs"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 828,
        "Question": "Which is true about function tolower?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The function tolower is defined in <ctype.h>",
            "b) Converts an uppercase letter to lowercase",
            "c) Returns other characters untouched",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 829,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'�'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">putchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 830,
        "Question": "putchar(c) function/macro always outputs character c to the __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) screen",
            "b) standard output",
            "c) depends on the compiler",
            "d) depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 831,
        "Question": "4.  What will be the output of the following C code if following commands are used to run (considering myfile exists)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    gcc <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>otest test.<span class=\"me1\">c</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    .<span class=\"sy0\">/</span>test <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> myfile</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'d'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">putchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error (after first command)",
            "b) d in the myfile file",
            "c) d on the screen",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 832,
        "Question": "5.  What will be the output of the following C code if following commands are used to run (considering myfile exists)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    gcc <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>otest test.<span class=\"me1\">c</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    .<span class=\"sy0\">/</span>test <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> myfile</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">     <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'d'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">putchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\" %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> argc<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) d 2 in myfile",
            "b) d 1 in myfile",
            "c) d in myfile and 1 in screen",
            "d) d in myfile and 2 in screen"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 833,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code if following commands are used to run and if myfile does not exist?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    gcc <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>o test test.<span class=\"me1\">c</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    .<span class=\"sy0\">/</span>test <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> myfile</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'d'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">putchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\" %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> argc<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) d 2 in myfile",
            "b) d 1 in myfile",
            "c) Depends on the system",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 834,
        "Question": "The statement prog < infile causes _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) prog to read characters from infile",
            "b) prog to write characters to infile",
            "c) infile to read characters from prog instead",
            "d) nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 835,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 2 4",
            "c) 10 2 2",
            "d) 10 2 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 836,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 3",
            "c) 10 3 some garbage value",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 837,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 3 3",
            "c) 10 3",
            "d) 10 3 somegarbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 838,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"myworld\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%*s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) myworld",
            "b) myworld(note: spaces to the left of myworld)",
            "c) myworld (note:followed by two spaces after myworld)",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 839,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"sy0\">**</span> argv<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"myworld\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%10.*s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) myw(note:7 spaces before myw)",
            "b) myworld(note:2 spaces before myworld)",
            "c) myworld (note:2 spaces after myworld)",
            "d) myw(note:6 spaces after myw)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: In the format represented by “%10.*s”, the width of the string will be 10 spaces which is aligned to the right, by default. Since we have asterisk (*) after the precision dot (.), the value of precision will be the value stored in the variable i. The value of i is 3, so this signifies max length of the string as 3 characters. So, the final formatted output will be a 10 character output with 3 characters “myw” printed with right alignment and the 1st 7 characters will be simply space characters. "
    },
    {
        "id": 840,
        "Question": "What is the difference between %e and %g?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %e output formatting depends on the argument and %g always formats in the format [-]m.dddddd or [-]m.dddddE[+|-]xx where no.of ds are optional",
            "b) %e always formats in the format [-]m.dddddd or [-]m.dddddE[+|-]xx where no.of ds are optional and output formatting depends on the argument",
            "c) No differences",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 841,
        "Question": "Escape sequences are prefixed with ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) %",
            "b) /",
            "c) ”",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 842,
        "Question": "What is the purpose of sprintf?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It prints the data into stdout",
            "b) It writes the formatted data into a string",
            "c) It writes the formatted data into a file",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 843,
        "Question": "The syntax to print a % using printf statement can be done by ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) %",
            "b) \\%",
            "c) ‘%’",
            "d) %%"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 844,
        "Options": [
            "a) 10 spaces before the string state is printed",
            "b) Print empty spaces if the string state is less than 10 characters",
            "c) Print the last 10 characters of the string",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 845,
        "Question": "What are the Properties of the first argument of a printf() functions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is defined by a user",
            "b) It keeps the record of the types of arguments that will follow",
            "c) There may no be first argument",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 846,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 2 4",
            "c) 10 2 2",
            "d) 10 2 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 847,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 3",
            "c) 10 3 some garbage value",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 848,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 10 3 3",
            "c) 10 3",
            "d) 10 3 somegarbage value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 849,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"myworld\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%*s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) myworld",
            "b) myworld(note: spaces to the left of myworld)",
            "c) myworld (note:followed by two spaces after myworld)",
            "d) Undefined"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 850,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> argc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>argv<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"myworld\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%10.*s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) myw(note:7 spaces before myw)",
            "b) myworld(note:2 spaces before myworld)",
            "c) myworld (note:2 spaces after myworld)",
            "d) myw(note:6 spaces after myworld)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: In the format represented by “%10.*s”, the width of the string will be 10 spaces which is aligned to the right, by default. Since we have asterisk (*) after the precision dot (.), the value of precision will be the value stored in the variable i. The value of i is 3, so this signifies max length of the string as 3 characters. So, the final formatted output will be a 10 character output with 3 characters “myw” printed with right alignment and the 1st 7 characters will be simply space characters.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 851,
        "Question": "What is the difference between %e and %g?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %e output formatting depends on the argument and %g always formats in the format [-]m.dddddd or [-]m.dddddE[+|-]xx where no.of ds are optional",
            "b) %e always formats in the format [-]m.dddddd or [-]m.dddddE[+|-]xx where no.of ds are optional and output formatting depends on the argument",
            "c) No differences",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 852,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdarg.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">13</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> func<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> number<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        va_list start<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">va_start</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>start<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>i <span class=\"sy0\">!=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            number <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">va_arg</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>start<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            i<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> number<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 7",
            "d) 11"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 853,
        "Question": "Which of the following function with ellipsis are illegal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void func(…);",
            "b) void func(int, …);",
            "c) void func(int, int, …);",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 854,
        "Question": "Which of the following data-types are promoted when used as a parameter for an ellipsis?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) short",
            "c) int",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 855,
        "Question": "Which header file includes a function for variable number of arguments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdlib.h",
            "b) stdarg.h",
            "c) ctype.h",
            "d) both stdlib.h and stdarg.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 856,
        "Question": "Which of the following macro extracts an argument from the variable argument list (ie ellipsis) and advance the pointer to the next argument?",
        "Options": [
            "a) va_list",
            "b) va_arg",
            "c) va_end",
            "d) va_start"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 857,
        "Question": "The type va_list in an argument list is used ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) To declare a variable that will refer to each argument in turn;",
            "b) For cleanup",
            "c) To create a list",
            "d) There is no such type"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 858,
        "Question": "In a variable length argument function, the declaration “…” can _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Appear anywhere in the function declaration",
            "b) Only appear at the end of an argument list",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 859,
        "Question": "Each call of va_arg _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Returns one argument",
            "b) Steps va_list variable to the next",
            "c) Returns one argument & Steps va_list variable to the next",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 860,
        "Question": "The standard header _______ is used for variable list arguments (…) in C.",
        "Options": [
            "a) <stdio.h >",
            "b) <stdlib.h>",
            "c) <math.h>",
            "d) <stdarg.h>"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 861,
        "Question": "What is the purpose of va_end?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cleanup is necessary",
            "b) Must be called before the program returns",
            "c) Cleanup is necessary & Must be called before the program returns",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 862,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> chr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 97",
            "d) a"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 863,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdarg.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>...<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>...<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        va_list li<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">va_arg</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 97",
            "d) a"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 864,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdarg.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">98</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        va_list li<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">va_start</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">va_arg</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">va_end</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) a",
            "d) b"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 865,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdarg.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">98</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        va_list li<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">va_start</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">va_arg</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">va_end</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) a",
            "d) b"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 866,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdarg.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">97</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">98</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ...<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        va_list li<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">va_start</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">va_arg</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">va_end</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>li<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 97.000000",
            "d) 98.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 867,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Undefined behavior",
            "c) Whatever user types",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 868,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Undefined behavior",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 869,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%hd\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%hd\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Undefined behavior",
            "c) Whatever user types",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: The array n contains a string which has a newline character in between the strings “hello” and “world”. A newline character is considered as a whitespace character for inputs for the scanf(), sscanf() and fscanf() functions. So, the sscanf() function will only copy upto the string “hello” into the array s. Hence, the output of the printf() function be only the string “hello”. "
    },
    {
        "id": 870,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%*d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%hd\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Somegarbage value",
            "c) Whatever user types",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 871,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%*hd\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%hd\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Somegarbage value",
            "c) Whatever user types",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 872,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%h*d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%hd\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Undefined behavior",
            "c) Somegarbage value",
            "d) Depends on the standard."
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 873,
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a delimiter for an input in scanf?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enter",
            "b) Space",
            "c) Tab",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 874,
        "Question": "If the conversion characters of int d, i, o, u and x are preceded by h, it indicates?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A pointer to int",
            "b) A pointer to short",
            "c) A pointer to long",
            "d) A pointer to char"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 875,
        "Question": "Which of the following doesn’t require an & for the input in scanf()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char name[10];",
            "b) int name[10];",
            "c) float name[10];",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 876,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an invalid method for input?",
        "Options": [
            "a) scanf(“%d%d%d”,&a, &b, &c);",
            "b) scanf(“%d %d %d”, &a, &b, &c);",
            "c) scanf(“Three values are %d %d %d”,&a,&b,&c);",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 877,
        "Question": "Which of the following represents the function for scanf()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void scanf(char *format, …)",
            "b) int scanf(char *format, …)",
            "c) char scanf(int format, …)",
            "d) char *scanf(char *format, …)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 878,
        "Question": "What does scanf() function return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of successfully matched and assigned input items",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Number of characters properly printed",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 879,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prints the number that was entered",
            "b) Segmentation fault",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Varies"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 880,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scans the string according to the format in format and stores the resulting values through arg1, arg2, etc",
            "b) The arguments arg1,arg2 etc must be pointers",
            "c) Scans the string according to the format in format and stores the resulting values through arg1, arg2, etc, those arguments arg1,arg2 etc must be pointers",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 881,
        "Question": "The conversion characters d, i, o, u, and x may be preceded by h in scanf() to indicate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A pointer to short",
            "b) A pointer to long",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 882,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code (when 4 and 5 are entered)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter a number\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 4 junkvalue",
            "c) Junkvalue 5",
            "d) 4 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 883,
        "Question": "What are the first and second arguments of fopen?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A character string containing the name of the file & the second argument is the mode",
            "b) A character string containing the name of the user & the second argument is the mode",
            "c) A character string containing file pointer & the second argument is the mode",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 884,
        "Question": "For binary files, a ___ must be appended to the mode string.",
        "Options": [
            "a)  Nothing",
            "b) “b”",
            "c) “binary”",
            "d) “01”"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 885,
        "Question": "What will fopen will return, if there is any error while opening a file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nothing",
            "b) EOF",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) Depends on compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 886,
        "Question": "What is the return value of getc()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The next character from the stream is not referred by file pointer",
            "b) EOF for end of file or error",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 887,
        "Question": "When a C program is started, O.S environment is responsible for opening file and providing pointer for that file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Standard input",
            "b) Standard output",
            "c) Standard error",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 888,
        "Question": "In C language, FILE is of which data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) char *",
            "c) struct",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 889,
        "Question": "7. What is meant by ‘a’ in the following C operation?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fopen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Random.txt\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Attach",
            "b) Append",
            "c) Apprehend",
            "d) Add"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 890,
        "Question": "Which of the following mode argument is used to truncate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) f",
            "c) w",
            "d) t"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 891,
        "Question": "Which type of files can’t be opened using fopen()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) .txt",
            "b) .bin",
            "c) .c",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 892,
        "Question": "Which of the following fopen() statements are illegal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fp = fopen(“abc.txt”, “r”);",
            "b) fp = fopen(“/home/user1/abc.txt”, “w”);",
            "c) fp = fopen(“abc”, “w”);",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 893,
        "Question": "2. What does the following segment of C code do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Copying!\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) It writes “Copying!” into the file pointed by fp",
            "b) It reads “Copying!” from the file and prints on display",
            "c) It writes as well as reads “Copying!” to and from the file and prints it",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 894,
        "Question": "What is FILE reserved word?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A structure tag declared in stdio.h",
            "b) One of the basic data types in c",
            "c) Pointer to the structure defined in stdio.h",
            "d) It is a type name defined in stdio.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 895,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> stdin<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">45</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) 45",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 896,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> stdout<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">45</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) 45",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 897,
        "Question": "stdout, stdin and stderr are ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) File pointers",
            "b) File descriptors",
            "c) Streams",
            "d) Structure"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 898,
        "Question": "Which of the following statements about stdout and stderr are true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Same",
            "b) Both connected to screen always",
            "c) Both connected to screen by default",
            "d) stdout is line buffered but stderr is unbuffered"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 899,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> stdout<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">45</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stderr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">65</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 45 65",
            "b) 65 45",
            "c) 65",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 900,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> stdout<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span> \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">45</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stderr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">65</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 45 65",
            "b) 65 45",
            "c) 65",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 901,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> stdout<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">45</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fflush</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stdout<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stderr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">65</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 45 65",
            "b) 65 45",
            "c) 45",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 902,
        "Question": "1. What is the output of the following C code if there is no error in stream fp?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fopen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"newfile\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"w\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">ferror</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) Any nonzero value"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 903,
        "Question": "Within main, return expr statement is equivalent to ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) abort(expr)",
            "b) exit(expr)",
            "c) ferror(expr)",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 904,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fopen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"newfile1.txt\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"r\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">!</span><span class=\"kw3\">feof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">getc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">putc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdout<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Prints to the screen content of newfile1.txt completely",
            "c) Prints to the screen some contents of newfile1.txt",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 905,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> stdout<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        stderr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> fp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stderr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) hello",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 906,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> buf<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">12</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        stderr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> stdin<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fscanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stderr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> buf<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> buf<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) Whatever user types",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 907,
        "Question": "stderr is similar to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdin",
            "b) stdout",
            "c) both stdout and stdin",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 908,
        "Question": "7. What happens when we use the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stderr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"error: could not open filen\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The diagnostic output is directly displayed in the output",
            "b) The diagnostic output is pipelined to the output file",
            "c) The line which caused error is compiled again",
            "d) The program is immediately aborted"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 909,
        "Question": "Which of the following function can be used to terminate the main function from another function safely?",
        "Options": [
            "a) return(expr);",
            "b) exit(expr);",
            "c) abort();",
            "d) both exit(expr); and abort();"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 910,
        "Question": "Which of the following causes an error?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trying to read a file that doesn’t exist",
            "b) Inability to write data in a file",
            "c) Failure to allocate memory with the help of malloc",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 911,
        "Question": "2. What is the purpose of the C function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">ferror</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) They check for input errors",
            "b) They check for output errors",
            "c) They check for all types of errors",
            "d) They check for error in accessing the file"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 912,
        "Question": "stderr is similar to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdin",
            "b) stdout",
            "c) Both stdout and stdin",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: stderr is not exactly the same as stdout, but similar in the sense that both puts the output or error to the monitor."
    },
    {
        "id": 913,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">fprintf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>stderr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"error: could not open filen\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The diagnostic output is directly displayed in the output",
            "b) The diagnostic output is pipelined to the output file",
            "c) The line which caused error is compiled again",
            "d) The program is immediately aborted"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 914,
        "Question": "Which of the following function can be used to terminate the main() function from another function safely?",
        "Options": [
            "a) return(expr);",
            "b) exit(expr);",
            "c) abort();",
            "d) both exit(expr); and abort();"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 915,
        "Question": "Which of the following causes an error?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trying to read a file that doesn’t exist",
            "b) Inability to write data in a file",
            "c) Failure to allocate memory with the help of malloc",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 916,
        "Question": "7. What is the purpose of the C function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">ferror</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) They check for input errors",
            "b) They check for output errors",
            "c) They check for all types of errors",
            "d) They check for error in accessing the file"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 917,
        "Question": "The syntax of fgets is char *fgets(char *line, int maxline, FILE *fp). Which is true for fgets?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Returns line on success",
            "b) On end of file or error it returns NULL",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Both returns line on success & On end of file or error it returns NULL"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 918,
        "Question": "fputs() function writes a string to a file that only ends with a newline.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 919,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;string.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> line<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fgets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>line<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdin<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>line<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Any length since line did not end with null character",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 920,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;string.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> line<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        fp <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fopen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"newfile.txt\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"r\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">fgets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>line<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fputs</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>line<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdout<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Infinite loop",
            "c) Segmentation fault",
            "d) No.of lines present in file newfile"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 921,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code if 2 characters is typed by the user?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;string.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> line<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fgets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>line<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdin<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> line<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 0",
            "d) 10(ascii value of newline character)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 922,
        "Question": "fputs() adds newline character.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 923,
        "Question": "puts() function adds newline character.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 924,
        "Question": "gets() function checks overflow run.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 925,
        "Question": "puts() does the following when it writes to stdout.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deletes everything",
            "b) Adds ‘t’ to the line written",
            "c) Deletes the terminating ‘n’",
            "d) Adds ‘n’ to the line written"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 926,
        "Question": "What is the size of array “line” used in fgets(line, maxline, *fp) function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) maxline – 1",
            "b) maxline",
            "c) maxline + 1",
            "d) Size is dynamic"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 927,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C function when EOF returns?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">   <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fputs</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>line<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ‘�’ character of array line is encountered",
            "b) ‘n’ character in array line is encountered",
            "c) ‘t’ character in array line is encountered",
            "d) When an error occurs"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 928,
        "Question": "3. Identify X library function for line input and output in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> X<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>iop<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">while</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">++</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">putc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> iop<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"kw3\">ferror</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>iop<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> EOF <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) getc",
            "b) putc",
            "c) fgets",
            "d) fputs"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 929,
        "Question": "Which function has a return type as char pointer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) getline",
            "b) fputs",
            "c) fgets",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 930,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the right declaration for fgets() inside the library?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int *fgets(char *line, int maxline, FILE *fp);",
            "b) char *fgets(char *line, int maxline, FILE *fp);",
            "c) char *fgets(char *line, FILE *fp);",
            "d) int *fgets(char *line, FILE *fp);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 931,
        "Question": "what is the return value of fputs()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) EOF if an error occurs",
            "b) Non-negative if no error",
            "c) EOF if an error occurs & Non-negative if no error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 932,
        "Question": "gets() and puts() operate on ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdin and stdout",
            "b) files",
            "c) stderr",
            "d) nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 933,
        "Question": "gets() does the following when it reads from stdin.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deletes the ‘t’",
            "b) Puts adds it.",
            "c) Deletes the terminating ‘n’",
            "d) Nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 934,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">strcmp</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"equal\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"unequal\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) equal",
            "b) unequal",
            "c) Compilation error",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 935,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">15</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello wo 9\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Segmentation Fault",
            "c) hello, world",
            "d) hello, wo 9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 936,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;string.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strncpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello, world 11",
            "b) hello, wor 9",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 937,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello, world<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">&nbsp;</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compilation error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 13",
            "d) 11"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 938,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">11</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strcat</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) helloworld 0",
            "b) helloworld anyvalue",
            "c) worldhello 0",
            "d) Segmentation fault/code crash"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 939,
        "Question": "Strcat() function adds null character.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only if there is space",
            "b) Always",
            "c) Depends on the standard",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 940,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">strncat</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) helloworld",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) helloworl",
            "d) hellowor"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 941,
        "Question": "What type of return-type used in String operations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void only",
            "b) void and (char *) only",
            "c) void and int only",
            "d) void, int and (char *) only"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 942,
        "Question": "String operation such as strcat(s, t), strcmp(s, t), strcpy(s, t) and strlen(s) heavily rely upon.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Presence of NULL character",
            "b) Presence of new-line character",
            "c) Presence of any escape sequence",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 943,
        "Question": "Which pre-defined function returns a pointer to the last occurence of a character in a string?",
        "Options": [
            "a) strchr(s, c);",
            "b) strrchr(s, c);",
            "c) strlchr(s, c);",
            "d) strfchr(s, c);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 944,
        "Question": "Which of the following function compares 2 strings with case-insensitively?",
        "Options": [
            "a) strcmp(s, t)",
            "b) strcmpcase(s, t)",
            "c) strcasecmp(s, t)",
            "d) strchr(s, t)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 945,
        "Question": "5. What will be the value of var for the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">var <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strcmp</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"World\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) strcmp has void return-type"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 946,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strrchr</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">'l'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">++</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) l",
            "b) o",
            "c) e",
            "d) Compilation error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 947,
        "Question": "Which of the following library function is not case-sensitive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) toupper()",
            "b) tolower()",
            "c) isdigit()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 948,
        "Question": "2. The following C expression can be substituted for?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isalpha</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class=\"kw3\">isdigit</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) if (isalnum(c))",
            "b) if (isalphanum(c))",
            "c) if (isalphanumeric(c))",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 949,
        "Question": "Which of the following will return a non-zero value when checked with isspace(c)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) blank",
            "b) newline",
            "c) return",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 950,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;ctype.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isdigit</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"digit<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not digit<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) digit",
            "b) not digit",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 951,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;ctype.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isdigit</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"digit<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not digit<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) digit",
            "b) not digit",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 952,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'9'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isdigit</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"digit<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not digit<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) digit",
            "b) not digit",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 953,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;ctype.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isspace</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"space<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not space<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) space",
            "c) not space",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: The value of variable i is 0 which is the NULL character in ASCII. Hence, the output will be printed as “not space”."
    },
    {
        "id": 954,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;ctype.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">32</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isspace</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"space<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">else</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"not space<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) space",
            "c) not space",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: The ASCII value of space character is 32. Since the variable i stores 32, the output will be printed as “space”."
    },
    {
        "id": 955,
        "Question": "1. Which is true about isaplpha(c), where c is an int that can be represented as an unsigned?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> or EOF.<span class=\"kw3\">isalpha</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span> returns</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Non-zero if c is alphabetic",
            "b) 0 if c is not alphabetic",
            "c) Both Non-zero if c is alphabetic & 0 if c is not alphabetic",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 956,
        "Question": "2. Which is true about isupper(c), where c is an int that can be represented as an unsigned?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> or EOF.<span class=\"kw3\">isupper</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span> returns</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Non-zero if c is upper case",
            "b) 0 if c is not upper case",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) Both Non-zero if c is upper case & 0 if c is not upper case"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 957,
        "Question": "3. Which is true about isalnum(c), where c is an int that can be represented as an unsigned?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> or EOF.<span class=\"kw3\">isalnum</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span> returns</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Non-zero if isalpha(c) or isdigit(c)",
            "b) 0 if not isalpha(c) or not isdigit(c)",
            "c) Both Non-zero if isalpha(c) or isdigit(c) & 0 if not isalpha(c) or not isdigit(c)",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 958,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;ctype.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'t'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">isspace</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Non-zero number",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) Error",
            "d) t"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 959,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;ctype.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'t'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"is :%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">tolower</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'A'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) A",
            "b) a",
            "c) Non-zero number",
            "d) Zero"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 960,
        "Question": "Which types of input are accepted in toupper(c)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) char *",
            "c) float",
            "d) Both char and char *"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 961,
        "Question": "What is the difference in the ASCII value of capital and non-capital of the same letter is?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 32",
            "d) Depends with compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 962,
        "Question": "ungetc() can be used only with getc().",
        "Options": [
            "a) true",
            "b) false",
            "c) depends on the standard",
            "d) depends on the platform"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 963,
        "Question": "Which character of pushback is guaranteed per file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the platform"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 964,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">ungetc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdin<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Whatever is typed by the user first time",
            "c) Whatever is typed by the user second time",
            "d) Undefined behaviour"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 965,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> n<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fgets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">19</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdin<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">ungetc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdin<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Whatever string user types second time",
            "c) Whatever string user types first time",
            "d) First character of whatever user types first time and whatever user types second time"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 966,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code considering user typed jkl?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> n<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">fgets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">19</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdin<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">ungetc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stdin<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) jkl",
            "b) kl",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) jk"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 967,
        "Question": "How many characters for pushback is guaranteed per file while using ungetc(c, fp);?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Only 1 character",
            "b) Characters within 1 word",
            "c) Characters within 1st new-line",
            "d) All characters upto NULL character"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 968,
        "Question": "7. Which of the following is the correct syntax for calling function ungetc?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">Assume <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c and FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp</pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ungetc(c,*fp);",
            "b) ungetc(c, fp);",
            "c) ungetc(fp, c);",
            "d) ungetc(*fp,c);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 969,
        "Question": "ungetc() is used __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) to get a char",
            "b) to get an int",
            "c) to push a character back to file",
            "d) nothing"
        ],
        "Answer": " Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 970,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct declaration for ungetc?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int ungetc(int c, FILE fp);",
            "b) int ungetc(int *c, FILE fp);",
            "c) int ungetc(int c, FILE *fp);",
            "d) int ungetc(int *c, FILE *fp);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 971,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be used with ungetc()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) scanf",
            "b) getc",
            "c) getchar",
            "d) printf"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 972,
        "Question": "3. What does the ungetc function return for the following C expression?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">ungetc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span><span class=\"co1\">//where declarations are int c and FILE *fp</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) It returns character c",
            "b) It returns EOF for an error",
            "c) Both returns character c and returns EOF for an error",
            "d) Either returns character c or returns EOF for an error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 973,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">ungetc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>fp<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Either c or EOF for an error",
            "b) Nothing",
            "c) fp",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 974,
        "Question": "Only _____character of pushback is guaranteed per file when ungetc is used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Two",
            "b) One",
            "c) Many",
            "d) Zero"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 975,
        "Question": "ungetc() may be used with ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) scanf",
            "b) getc",
            "c) getchar",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 976,
        "Question": "What is the syntax of ungetc()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void ungetc(int c, FILE *fp)",
            "b) int ungetc(int c, FILE *fp)",
            "c) int ungetc(String c, FILE *fp)",
            "d) int getc(int c, FILE *fp)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 977,
        "Question": "The function ____ obtains a block of memory dynamically.",
        "Options": [
            "a) calloc",
            "b) malloc",
            "c) both calloc & malloc",
            "d) free"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 978,
        "Question": "void * malloc(size_t n) returns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pointer to n bytes of uninitialized storage",
            "b) NULL if the request can be satisfied",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 979,
        "Question": "calloc() returns storage that is initialized to.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Zero",
            "b) Null",
            "c) Nothing",
            "d) One"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 980,
        "Question": "In function free(p), p is a _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) pointer returned by malloc()",
            "c) pointer returned by calloc()",
            "d) pointer returned by malloc() & calloc()"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 981,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">calloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"welcome\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Segmentation fault",
            "b) Garbage",
            "c) Error",
            "d) welcome"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 982,
        "Question": "Memory allocation using malloc() is done in _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Static area",
            "b) Stack area",
            "c) Heap area",
            "d) Both Stack & Heap area"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 983,
        "Question": "7. Why do we write (int *) before malloc?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ip <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is for the syntax correctness",
            "b) It is for the type-casting",
            "c) It is to inform malloc function about the data-type expected",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 984,
        "Question": "Which of the following is used during memory deallocation in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) remove(p);",
            "b) delete(p);",
            "c) free(p);",
            "d) terminate(p);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 985,
        "Question": "Which of the following will return a result most quickly for searching a given key?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Unsorted Array",
            "b) Sorted Array",
            "c) Sorted linked list",
            "d) Binary Search Tree"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 986,
        "Question": "On freeing a dynamic memory, if the pointer value is not modified, then the pointer points to.",
        "Options": [
            "a) NULL",
            "b) Other dynamically allocated memory",
            "c) The same deallocated memory location",
            "d) It points back to the location it was initialized with"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 987,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">calloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>next <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">calloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Somegarbage value",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 988,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">     <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">*</span> p1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        p1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>next <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>next<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Somegarbage value",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 989,
        "Question": "calloc() initialize memory with all bits set to zero.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the compiler",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 990,
        "Question": "7. What if size is zero in the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">realloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> size<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Allocate a memory location with zero length",
            "b) Free the memory pointed to by ptr",
            "c) Undefined behaviour",
            "d) Doesn’t do any reallocation of ptr i.e. no operation"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 991,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;math.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">90</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">sin</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Undefined behaviour",
            "c) 0.893997",
            "d) 1.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 992,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;math.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fabs</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) -1",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 993,
        "Question": "function fabs defined math.h header file takes the argument of type integer.",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the implementation",
            "d) Depends on the standard"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 994,
        "Question": "log(x) function defined in math.h header file is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Natural base logarithm",
            "b) Logarithm to the base 2",
            "c) Logarithm to the base 10",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 995,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;math.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">log10</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) 1.000000",
            "c) 2.302585",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 996,
        "Question": "What type of inputs are accepted by mathematical functions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) short",
            "b) int",
            "c) float",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 997,
        "Question": "In linux, apart from including math header file, the program is successfully executed by which of the following?",
        "Options": [
            "a) cc filename.c",
            "b) cc filename.c -lc",
            "c) cc -math filename.c",
            "d) cc -lm filename.c"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 998,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a valid mathematical function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) frexp(x);",
            "b) atan2(x,y);",
            "c) srand(x);",
            "d) fmod(x);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 999,
        "Question": "Which of the following mathematical function requires 2 parameter for successful function call?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fmod();",
            "b) div();",
            "c) atan2();",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 1000,
        "Question": "Which mathematical function among the following does NOT require int parameters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) div(x, y);",
            "b) srand(x);",
            "c) sqrt(x);",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1001,
        "Question": "What will sin(x) returns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sine of x where x is in radians",
            "b) sine of x where x is in degree",
            "c) cosine of x where x is in radians",
            "d) cosine of x where x is in degree"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1002,
        "Question": "What will cos(x) return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sine of x where x is in radians",
            "b) sine of x where x is in degree",
            "c) cosine of x where x is in radians",
            "d) cosine of x where x is in degree"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1003,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;math.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">pow</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) 8",
            "c) -1",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1004,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;math.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fabs</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">87</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -87",
            "b) 87",
            "c) 78",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1005,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;math.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> k <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">sqrt</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> k<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -2",
            "b) 2",
            "c) Compile time error",
            "d) NaN"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1006,
        "Question": "Which among the following mathematical function do not have a “double” return-type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) srand(x);",
            "b) ceil(x);",
            "c) floor(x);",
            "d) both ceil(x); and floor(x);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1007,
        "Question": "What is function srand(unsigned)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sets the seed for rand",
            "b) Doesn’t exist",
            "c) Is an error",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1008,
        "Question": "Which is the best way to generate numbers between 0 to 99?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rand()-100",
            "b) rand()%100",
            "c) rand(100)",
            "d) srand(100)"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1009,
        "Question": "Which is the correct way to generate numbers between minimum and maximum(inclusive)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) minimum + (rand() % (maximum – minimum));",
            "b) minimum + (rand() % (maximum – minimum + 1));",
            "c) minimum * (rand() % (maximum – minimum))",
            "d) minimum – (rand() % (maximum + minimum));"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1010,
        "Question": "rand() and srand() functions are used _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) To find sqrt",
            "b) For and operations",
            "c) For or operations",
            "d) To generate random numbers"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1011,
        "Question": "What is the return type of rand() function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) short",
            "b) int",
            "c) long",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1012,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be used for random number generation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) random()",
            "b) rnd()",
            "c) rndm()",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1013,
        "Question": "Which of the following snippet will effectively generate random numbers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rand();",
            "b) rand(10);",
            "c) rand(time(NULL));",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1014,
        "Question": "Which among the following is correct function call for rand() and random()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rand() and random();",
            "b) rand() and random(1);",
            "c) rand(1) and random(1);",
            "d) rand(1) and random();"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1015,
        "Question": "For the function call time(), what type of parameter is accepted?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) int *",
            "c) time_t",
            "d) time_t *"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1016,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">rand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1000</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) An integer between 0-1000",
            "c) An integer between 0-999 including 0 and 999",
            "d) An integer between 0-1000 including 1000"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1017,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">srand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">9000</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">rand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) An integer in the range 0 to RAND_MAX",
            "c) A double in the range 0 to 1",
            "d) A float in the range 0 to 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1018,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">srand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">9000</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) An integer in the range 0 to 9000",
            "c) A float in the range 0 to 1",
            "d) A double in the range 0 to 9000"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1019,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">srand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">rand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) An integer in the range 0 to RAND_MAX",
            "c) A double in the range 0 to 1",
            "d) A float in the range 0 to 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1020,
        "Question": "5. In the below C program, every time program is run different numbers are generated.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">rand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 1021,
        "Question": "6. In the following C program, every time program is run different numbers are generated.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">srand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">rand</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) True",
            "b) False",
            "c) Depends on the platform",
            "d) Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1022,
        "Question": "Which of these is a correct way to generate numbers between 0 to 1(inclusive) randomly?",
        "Options": [
            "a) rand() / RAND_MAX",
            "b) rand() % 2",
            "c) rand(0, 1)",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1023,
        "Question": "The syntax of printf() function is printf(“control string”, variable list) ;what is the prototype of the control string?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %[flags][.precision][width][length]specifier",
            "b) %[flags][length][width][.precision]specifier",
            "c) %[flags][width][.precision][length]specifier",
            "d) %[flags][.precision][length][width]specifier"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The prototype of control string is %[flags][width][.precision][length]specifier. Each control string must begin with % sign.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1024,
        "Question": "The parameter control string in the printf () is a C String that contains text to be __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) taken from a standard output device",
            "b) written on to the standard output device",
            "c) received from the standard output device",
            "d) nothing can be said"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: After the control string, the function can have many additional arguments as specified in the control string, this parameter contains the text to be written on to the standard output device."
    },
    {
        "id": 1025,
        "Question": "Output justification such as decimal point, numerical sign, trailing zeros or octal are specified.",
        "Options": [
            "a) specifier",
            "b) flags",
            "c) precision",
            "d) decimal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Flags specify output justification such as Left-justify within the data given field width, Displays the data with its numeric sign, used to provide additional specifiers like o, x, X for octal, left padding of a number."
    },
    {
        "id": 1026,
        "Question": "What symbol is used to Left-justify within the data given field width?",
        "Options": [
            "a) -(minus sign)",
            "b) +(plus sign)",
            "c) #",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To left-justify the data use minus sign(-) in the flags field."
    },
    {
        "id": 1027,
        "Question": "What specifies the minimum number of characters to print after being padded with zeros or blank spaces?",
        "Options": [
            "a) flags",
            "b) length",
            "c) width",
            "d) precision"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: width specifies the minimum number of positions in the output."
    },
    {
        "id": 1028,
        "Question": "The maximum number of characters to be printed is specified by __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) precision",
            "b) width",
            "c) length",
            "d) flags"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Precision specifies the maximum number of characters to print."
    },
    {
        "id": 1029,
        "Question": "________is used to define the type and the interpretation of the value of the corresponding argument.",
        "Options": [
            "a) precision",
            "b) specifiers",
            "c) flags",
            "d) decimal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Specifiers is used to define the type and the interpretation of the value of the corresponding argument. Example: c for a single character, d for decimal values etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 1030,
        "Question": "A conversion specification %7.4f means ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) print a floating point value of maximum 7 digits where 4 digits are allotted for the digits after the decimal point",
            "b) print a floating point value of maximum 4 digits where 7digits are allotted for the digits after the decimal point",
            "c) print a floating point value of maximum 7 digits",
            "d) print a floating point value of minimum 7 digits where 4 digits are allotted for the digits after the decimal point"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The conversion specification %7.4f means that it will print floating point number maximum of 7 digits and 4 digits after the decimal point."
    },
    {
        "id": 1031,
        "Question": "Choose the correct description for control string %-+7.2f.",
        "Options": [
            "a) – means display the sign, + means left justify, 7 specifies the width and 2 specifies the precision",
            "b) – means left justify, + means display the sign, 7 specifies the width and 2 specifies the precision",
            "c) – means display the sign, + means left justify, 7 specifies the precision and 2 specifies the width",
            "d) – means left justify, + means display the sign, 7 specifies the precision and 2 specifies the width"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The given control string %-+7.2f means that – is for left justify, + to display sign, 7 specifies the precision and 2 specifies the width."
    },
    {
        "id": 1032,
        "Question": "What error is generated on placing an address operator with a variable in the printf statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) compile error",
            "b) run-time error",
            "c) logical error",
            "d) no error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Placing an address operator with a variable in the printf statement will generate a run-time error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1033,
        "Question": "If by mistake you specify more number of arguments, the excess arguments will ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) be ignored",
            "b) produce compile error",
            "c) produce run-time error",
            "d) produce logical error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The excess arguments will simply be ignored."
    },
    {
        "id": 1034,
        "Question": "What happens when zero flag is used with left justification?",
        "Options": [
            "a) data is padded with zeros",
            "b) zero flag is ignored",
            "c) data is padded with blank spaces",
            "d) will give error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Zero flag is not considered when used with left justification because adding zeros after a number changes its value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1035,
        "Question": "For floating point numbers, the precision flag specifies the number of decimal places to be printed. When no precision modifier is specified, printf() prints _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) six decimal positions",
            "b) five decimal positions",
            "c) four decimal positions",
            "d) three decimal positions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Its format can be given as “. m”, where m specifies the number of decimal digits when no precision modifier is specified, printf prints six decimal positions."
    },
    {
        "id": 1036,
        "Question": "What will the given code result in printf(“\\n you are\\”awesome \\\" \");?",
        "Options": [
            "a) compile error",
            "b) run-time error",
            "c) you are \"awesome\"",
            "d) you are awesome"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The above given code uses \\”<word>\\” to display the word within double inverted commas on standard output screen."
    },
    {
        "id": 1037,
        "Question": "What will be the output for the given code printf(“\\n The number is %07d”,1212);",
        "Options": [
            "a) The number is 0001212",
            "b) The number is 1212",
            "c) The number is 1212",
            "d) The number is 1212000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 0 in the above code is Flags. The number is left-padded with zeros(0) instead of spaces."
    },
    {
        "id": 1038,
        "Question": "7. Select the right explanation to the given code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%*</span>. <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>f”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">5700</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) the minimum field width has to be 4, the precision is given to be 5, and the value to be displayed is 5700",
            "b) the minimum field width is 5, the precision is 4, and the value to be displayed is 5700",
            "c) compile error",
            "d) run-time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the given code each argument is printed on a new line due to control character \\n. Width mentioned in the above code is 1,3,5 hence the character is printed on a new line after being padded with blank spaces."
    },
    {
        "id": 1039,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>Hello Nancy“<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“\\n <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>.7s”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello Nan",
            "b) Hello",
            "c) Hello N",
            "d) Hello Nancy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The minimum field width and precision specifiers are usually constants. They can also be provided by arguments to printf(). This is done by using * modifier as shown in the given code."
    },
    {
        "id": 1040,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>”Too Good”<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“\\n <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>7s”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Too Good",
            "b) Too G",
            "c) Too Go",
            "d) Too"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output for the code must be 7 characters including white spaces."
    },
    {
        "id": 1041,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“\\n Output<span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>5d \\t <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>x \\t <span class=\"sy0\">%</span><span class=\"co2\">#x”, 234,234,234);</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output:234EA0xEA",
            "b) Output:00234 EA 0xEA",
            "c) Output:    234 EA 0xEA",
            "d) ERROR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The complete string “Too Good” is printed. This is because if data needs more space than specified, then printf overrides the width specified by the user."
    },
    {
        "id": 1042,
        "Question": "The syntax of the scanf() is scanf(“control string “, arg1,arg2,arg3,….,argn); the prototype of control string is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) [=%[width][modifiers]type=] ",
            "b) [=%[modifiers][width]type=] ",
            "c) [=%[width] [modifiers]] ",
            "d) [width][modifiers]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: scanf() starts with the symbol % followed by the width, modifier, type of the argument."
    },
    {
        "id": 1043,
        "Question": "What is the use of symbol * in the control string as shown [=%[*][width] [modifiers] type=]?",
        "Options": [
            "a) * is optional and used when the data should be read from the stream but ignored",
            "b) * is not optional, used to read data from the stream but it is not ignored",
            "c) * is not optional, it is used to read data stream but ignored",
            "d) * is optional and used to read data from stream but it is not ignored"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: * is an optional argument, it indicates that data should be read from the steam but ignored (not stored in a memory location)"
    },
    {
        "id": 1044,
        "Question": "What action is carried out by scanf if a user enters any blank spaces, tabs, and newlines?",
        "Options": [
            "a) consider as input",
            "b) ignores it",
            "c) produces error",
            "d) nothing can be said"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The scanf() function ignores any blank spaces, tabs, and newlines entered by the user. This scanf() function just returns the number of input fields successfully scanned and stored."
    },
    {
        "id": 1045,
        "Question": "What error will generate if the read and write parameters are not separated by commas?",
        "Options": [
            "a) run-time error",
            "b) compile error",
            "c) logical error",
            "d) no error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A compile error will be generated if the read and write parameters are not separated by commas."
    },
    {
        "id": 1046,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>”Good”<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>s”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) compile error",
            "b) run-time error",
            "c) good",
            "d) logical error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: String can be read from the stream without the use of address of operator (&)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1047,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“ <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>d <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>d <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>d”<span class=\"sy0\">,&amp;</span>amp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>n1<span class=\"sy0\">,&amp;</span>amp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>n2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) read data for two",
            "b) generate error",
            "c) read data for three",
            "d) nothing can be said"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The following scanf() statement will generate an error as no variable address is given for the third conversion specification."
    },
    {
        "id": 1048,
        "Question": "7. What form the data must be entered for the given C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>d <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"sy0\">%</span>d”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>amp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>n1<span class=\"sy0\">,&amp;</span>amp<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>n2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6  9",
            "b) 6/9",
            "c) compile error",
            "d) run-time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The slash in the control String are neither white space characters nor a part of conversion specification, so the user must enter data of the form 6/9."
    },
    {
        "id": 1049,
        "Question": "Explain the format string \"%5d%s %c\"",
        "Options": [
            "a) five characters as a decimal integer, then reads the remaining as a string and then scans the first non-whitespace character",
            "b) compile error",
            "c) run-time error",
            "d) read first five characters as a decimal and ignore the rest"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An error will be generated if the format string %s is ended with white space character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1050,
        "Question": "_____ is an optional argument that gives the maximum number of characters to be read.",
        "Options": [
            "a) modifiers",
            "b) width",
            "c) precision",
            "d) length"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above format string reads the first five characters as a decimal integer, then reads the remaining as a string until a space, newline or tab is found, then reads the first non-whitespace character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1051,
        "Question": "Select the correct value of i from given options i=scanf(\"%d %d\", &a, &b);",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) No value assigned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: i stores the number of read data from the stream. It is useful for detecting an error in data input."
    },
    {
        "id": 1052,
        "Question": "2. If the user enters 1 3.2 s, what value will be returned by the scanf()?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %f %c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>s1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>s2<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>s3<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) No return value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When the scanf() function completes reading all the data values, it returns number of values that are successfully read."
    },
    {
        "id": 1053,
        "Question": "3. If the user enters 1 s 3.2, what value will be returned by the scanf()?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d %f %c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) no return value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: scanf() returns the number of values that are successfully read. In the above statement, only integer value is read successfully."
    },
    {
        "id": 1054,
        "Question": "What error will be generated on using incorrect specifier for the datatype being read?",
        "Options": [
            "a) compile error",
            "b) run-time error",
            "c) logical error",
            "d) no error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Using an incorrect specifier for the datatype being read will generate a run-time error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1055,
        "Question": "What is the prototype of scanf function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) scanf(\"controlstring\",arg1,arg2,arg3,….,argn);",
            "b) scanf(\"control string\", variable list);",
            "c) scanf(\" varible list,\", control string);",
            "d) scanf(\"arg1,arg2,arg3,….,argn\", control string);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The syntax of the scanf() can be given as,scanf(\"control string\", arg1,arg2,arg3,….,argn);"
    },
    {
        "id": 1056,
        "Question": "What is the qualifying input for the type specifier G?",
        "Options": [
            "a) floating point numbers",
            "b) floating point numbers in exponential format",
            "c) floating point numbers in the shorter of exponential format",
            "d) not a type specifier"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The control string specifies the type and format of the data that has to be obtained from the keyboard and store in the memory locations pointed by the arguments arg1,arg2….argn."
    },
    {
        "id": 1057,
        "Question": "scanf() is a predefined function in______header file.",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdlib. h",
            "b) ctype. h",
            "c) stdio. h",
            "d) stdarg. h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: G is a type specifier used to take an input of floating point numbers in the shorter of exponential format."
    },
    {
        "id": 1058,
        "Question": "9. What does the C statement given below says?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%7s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) read string with minimum 7 characters.",
            "b) read string with maximum 7 characters",
            "c) read string exactly to 7 characters",
            "d) read string with any number of characters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: scanf() is a predefined function in \"stdio.h\" header file.printf and scanf() carry out input and output functions in C. These functions statements are present in the header file stdio.h."
    },
    {
        "id": 1059,
        "Question": "10. What is the meaning of the following C statement?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%[^<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>]s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) read all character except new line",
            "b) read all characters",
            "c) read only new line character",
            "d) syntax error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the above statement the control string specifies the size of string to be 7(i.e only 7 characters can be entered in a string)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1060,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is correct syntax for opening  a file.",
        "Options": [
            "a) FILE *fopen(const *filename, const char *mode)",
            "b) FILE *fopen(const *filename)",
            "c) FILE *open(const *filename, const char *mode)",
            "d) FILE open(const*filename)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: fopen() opens the named file, and returns a stream, or NULL of the attempt fails."
    },
    {
        "id": 1061,
        "Question": "What is the function of the mode ‘ w+’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) create text file for writing, discard previous contents if any",
            "b) create text file for update, discard previous contents if any",
            "c) create text file for writing, do not  discard previous contents if any",
            "d) create text file for update, do not discard previous contents if any"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: w+ is a mode used to open a text file for update (i. e., writing and reading), discard previous contents if any."
    },
    {
        "id": 1062,
        "Question": "If the mode includes b after the initial letter, what does it indicates?",
        "Options": [
            "a) text file",
            "b) big text file",
            "c) binary file",
            "d) blueprint text"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the mode consists of letter b after the first letter as in, “rb” or “w+b”, it indicates binary file."
    },
    {
        "id": 1063,
        "Question": "fflush(NULL)  flushes all ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) input streams",
            "b) output streams",
            "c) previous contents",
            "d) appended text"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: fflush(FILE *stream) – fflush() causes any buffered but unwritten to be written on an Output stream. On an input stream, the effect is undefined. fflush(NULL)  flushes all output streams."
    },
    {
        "id": 1064,
        "Question": "_____removes the named file, so that a subsequent attempt to open it will fail.",
        "Options": [
            "a) remove(const *filename)",
            "b) remove(filename)",
            "c) remove()",
            "d) fclose(filename)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: remove(const *filename)  removes the named file, so that a subsequent attempt to open it will fail. It returns non-zero of the attempt fails."
    },
    {
        "id": 1065,
        "Question": "What is the function of FILE *tmpfile(void)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) creates a temporary file of mode “wb+”",
            "b) creates a temporary file of mode “wb”",
            "c) creates a temporary file of mode ” w”",
            "d) creates a temporary file of mode “w+”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A temporary file is created by tmpfile()  function of mode   “wb+” that will be automatically removed when closed or when the program terminates normally."
    },
    {
        "id": 1066,
        "Question": "What does tmpfile() returns when it could not create the file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stream and NULL",
            "b) only stream",
            "c) only NULL",
            "d) does not return anything"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: tmpfile() returns a stream or NULL  if it could not create the file."
    },
    {
        "id": 1067,
        "Question": "Choose the right statement for fscanf() and  scanf()",
        "Options": [
            "a) fscanf() can read from standard input whereas scanf() specifies a stream from which to read",
            "b) fscanf() can specifies a stream from which to read whereas scanf() can read only from standard input",
            "c) fscanf() and scanf() has no difference in their functions",
            "d) fscanf() and scanf() can read from specified stream"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The fscanf() is similar to the scanf() function, except that the first argument of fscanf() specifies a stream from which to read whereas scanf() can read from standard input."
    },
    {
        "id": 1068,
        "Question": "EOF is an integer type defined in stdio. hand has a value ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) NULL",
            "d) – 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: EOF is an integer type defined in stdio. hand has a value  – 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 1069,
        "Question": "what is the function of fputs()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) read a line from a file",
            "b) read a character from a file",
            "c) write a character to a file",
            "d) write a line to a file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The fputs()  is used to write a line to a file. fputs()  syntax can be written as\nint fputs(const char *str, FILE *stream);"
    },
    {
        "id": 1070,
        "Question": "2. What does the following C code snippet mean?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw3\">gets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) reads the next input line into the array s",
            "b) writes the line into the array s",
            "c) reads the next input character into the array s",
            "d) write a character into the array"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: gets() reads the next input line into the array s, terminating newline is replaced with ‘\\0’.It returns s, or NULL if end of file or error occurs."
    },
    {
        "id": 1071,
        "Question": "Which function will return the current file position for stream?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fgetpos()",
            "b) fseek()",
            "c) ftell()",
            "d) fsetpos()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  The current file position is returned by ftell() function for stream, or -1L on error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1072,
        "Question": "4.  Select the right explanation for the following C code snippet.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fgetpos</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>stream<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fpos_t <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) records the current position in stream in *s",
            "b) sets the file position for stream in *s",
            "c) positions stream at the position recorded in *s",
            "d) reads from stream into the array ptr"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:fgetpos() records the current position in stream in *s, for subsequent use by fsetpos() . The type fpost_t is suitable for recording such values."
    },
    {
        "id": 1073,
        "Question": "Which  functions is declared in <errno. h>?",
        "Options": [
            "a) fseek()",
            "b) ftell()",
            "c) ferror()",
            "d) fsetpos()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ferror()  is declared under <errno. h>. ferror()  returns non-zero if the error indicator for stream is set."
    },
    {
        "id": 1074,
        "Question": "The______function reads atmost one less than the number of characters specified by size from the given stream and it is stored in the string str.",
        "Options": [
            "a) fget()",
            "b) fgets()",
            "c) fput()",
            "d) fputs()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: setvbuf() and setbuf() controls buffering for the stream. If buff is NULL, buffering is turned off for the stream."
    },
    {
        "id": 1075,
        "Question": "9. What does the following C code snippet mean?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">ungetc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> FILE <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>stream<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) pushes c back onto a stream",
            "b) deletes c from the stream",
            "c) reads frequency of c in stream",
            "d) no action is taken by the command"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The functions vprintf() , vfprintf() , and vsprintf() are similar to the corresponding printf() functions except  that the variable argument list is replaced by arg."
    },
    {
        "id": 1076,
        "Question": "Choose the correct difference between getc() and fgetc().",
        "Options": [
            "a) If it is not a macro, it may evaluate stream more than once",
            "b) if it is amacro, it may not evaluate stream more than once",
            "c) if it is a macro, it may evaluate stream more than once",
            "d) no difference between fgetc() and getc()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The fgets() function reads one less than the number of characters indicated by the size from the given stream and it is stored in the string str. The fgets() terminates as soon as it encounters either a newline character, EOF, or other error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1077,
        "Question": "How many digits are present after the decimal in float value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 3",
            "c) 6",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1078,
        "Question": "Which among the following is never possible as an output for a float?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.666666",
            "b) 3.666",
            "c) 3",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1079,
        "Question": "In a 32-bit compiler, which 2 types have the same size?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char and short",
            "b) short and int",
            "c) int and float",
            "d) float and double"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1080,
        "Question": "What is the size of float in a 32-bit compiler?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1081,
        "Question": "Loss in precision occurs for typecasting from____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) char to short",
            "b) float to double",
            "c) long to float",
            "d) float to int"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1082,
        "Question": "6. In the following C code, the union size is decided by?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) int",
            "c) float",
            "d) both int and float"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1083,
        "Question": "%f access specifier is used for ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Strings",
            "b) Integral types",
            "c) Floating type",
            "d) All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 1084,
        "Question": "Select the odd one out with respect to type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) int",
            "c) long",
            "d) float"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1085,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%.0f\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu16\">2.89</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.890000",
            "b) 2.89",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1086,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">2.455555555555</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.455555",
            "b) 2.455556",
            "c) 2.456",
            "d) 2.46"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 1087,
        "Question": "Which of the following % operation is invalid?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 % 4;",
            "b) 2 % 4l;",
            "c) 2 % 4f;",
            "d) Both 2 % 4l; and 2 % 4f;"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1088,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) float",
            "c) double",
            "d) both float and double"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1089,
        "Question": "Modulus for float could be achieved by?",
        "Options": [
            "a) a % b",
            "b) modulus(a, b);",
            "c) fmod(a, b);",
            "d) mod(a, b);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1090,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) long",
            "c) float",
            "d) double"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 1091,
        "Question": "%lf is used to display?",
        "Options": [
            "a) float",
            "b) long float",
            "c) double",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1092,
        "Question": "What is the sizeof(char) in a 32-bit C compiler?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 bit",
            "b) 2 bits",
            "c) 1 Byte",
            "d) 2 Bytes"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1093,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 4",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1094,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) sizeof(a);",
            "b) sizeof(*a);",
            "c) sizeof(a[10]);",
            "d) 10 * sizeof(a);"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1095,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1096,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an operator in C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ,",
            "b) sizeof()",
            "c) ~",
            "d) None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None."
    },
    {
        "id": 1097,
        "Question": "Which among the following has the highest precedence?",
        "Options": [
            "a) &",
            "b) <<",
            "c) sizeof()",
            "d) &&"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1098,
        "Question": "What is the sizeof(void) in a 32-bit C?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: b\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1099,
        "Question": "What type of value does sizeof return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char",
            "b) short",
            "c) unsigned int",
            "d) long"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1100,
        "Options": [
            "a) sizeof(P) is greater than sizeof(Q)",
            "b) sizeof(P) is less than sizeof(Q)",
            "c) sizeof(P) is equal to sizeof(Q)",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1101,
        "Question": "",
        "Options": [
            "a) sizeof(P) is greater than sizeof(Q)",
            "b) sizeof(P) is equal to sizeof(Q)",
            "c) sizeof(P) is less than to sizeof(Q)",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1102,
        "Question": "3. What will be the size of the following C structure?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> temp</pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 11",
            "c) 41",
            "d) 44"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1103,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"size of a is %d, \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">++</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"value of a is %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) size of a is 4, value of a is 1",
            "b) size of a is 4, value of a is 2",
            "c) size of a is 2, value of a is 2",
            "d) size of a is 2, value of a is 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1104,
        "Question": "Which among the following statement is right?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sizeof(struct stemp*) > sizeof(union utemp*) > sizeof(char *)",
            "b) sizeof(struct stemp*) < sizeof(union utemp*) < sizeof(char *)",
            "c) sizeof(struct stemp*) = sizeof(union utemp*) = sizeof(char *)",
            "d) the order Depends on the compiler"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: c\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1105,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"HELLOWORLD\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output, 4",
            "b) Output, 10",
            "c) Output, 16",
            "d) Error, sizeof cannot evaluate size of a function"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1106,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be used inside sizeof?",
        "Options": [
            "a) pointers",
            "b) functions",
            "c) macro definition",
            "d) none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: d\nExplanation: None. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1107,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><ol><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span> <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"co2\">#define PI 3.14</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">{</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>PI<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></li><li class=\"li1\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Output is 8",
            "b) Output is 4",
            "c) Output is 1",
            "d) Error, we can’t use sizeof on macro-definitions"
        ],
        "Answer": "  Answer: a\nExplanation: None.  "
    },
    {
        "id": 1108,
        "Question": "A user defined data type, which is used to assign names to integral constants is called ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Union",
            "b) Array",
            "c) Structure",
            "d) Enum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Enumeration (enum) is a user defined data type in C. It is used to assign names to integral constants. The names make a program easy to read and maintain."
    },
    {
        "id": 1109,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> colour\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    blue<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> red<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> yellow\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> colour c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    c<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>yellow<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 0",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Enum variables are automatically assigned values if no value is specified. The compiler by default assigns values starting from 0. Therefore, in the above code, blue gets 0, red gets 1 and yellow gets 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 1110,
        "Question": "3. Point out the error (if any) in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> hello\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> hello m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No error",
            "b) Error in the statement: a,b,c;",
            "c) Error in the statement: enum hello m;",
            "d) Error in the statement: printf(“%d”,m);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the above code, there is a semi colon given at the end of the list of variables. This results in an error. Semi colon is to be put only after the closing brace of the enum, not after the list of variables."
    },
    {
        "id": 1111,
        "Question": "Pick the incorrect statement with respect to enums.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Two enum symbols cannot have the same value",
            "b) Only integer constants are allowed in enums",
            "c) It is not possible to change the value of enum symbols",
            "d) Enum variables are automatically assigned values if no value is specified"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Enumerated types are not strings. Hence it is not possible to use string handling functions with enumerated data types."
    },
    {
        "id": 1112,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu16\">3.56</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2\t3",
            "b) 0\t1",
            "c) 2\t3.56",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: We can assign values to some of the symbol names in any order. All unassigned names get the value as the value of previous name plus one."
    },
    {
        "id": 1113,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> class\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> class m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) Same as the size of an integer",
            "c) 3 times the size of an integer",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The statement that two enum symbols cannot have the same value is incorrect. Any number of enum symbols can have the same value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1114,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> hi<span class=\"br0\">{</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> hello<span class=\"br0\">{</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>e<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> hi h<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    h<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>h<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 1",
            "c) Error",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The above code will result in an error because 3.56 is not an integer constant. Only integer constants are allowed in enums."
    },
    {
        "id": 1115,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    c<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 6",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output will be the same as the size of an integer, that is 4 on a 32 bit platform."
    },
    {
        "id": 1116,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> resut <span class=\"br0\">{</span>pass<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> fail<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> result s1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>s2<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    s1<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>pass<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    s2<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>fail<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>s1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) pass",
            "c) fail",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The code shown above results in an error, stating : storage size of s1 and s2 unknown. There is an error in the declaration of these variables in the statement: enum result s1,s2;"
    },
    {
        "id": 1117,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> example <span class=\"br0\">{</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> example example1 <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> example answer<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> example1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n&nbsp;\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   <span class=\"br0\">(</span>answer<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">?</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">:</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) yes",
            "b) no",
            "c) 2",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the code shown above, the value of example1 is returned by the function answer. The ternary statement prints yes if this value is equal to that of ‘a’ and no if the value is not equal to that of ‘a’. Since the value of ‘a’ is 1 and that returned by the function is 2, therefore no is printed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1118,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define MAX 4</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>MAX<span class=\"sy0\">!=</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n        printtf<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"welcome\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) hello",
            "c) welcome",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output will be welcome. The value of the macro MAX is 4. Since 4 is equal to the value of c, welcome is printed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1119,
        "Question": "5.  Point out the error( if any) in the following code.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry g<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    g<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>g<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error in the statement: a,b,c",
            "b) Error in the statement: enum sanfoundry g;",
            "c) Error in the statement: g++",
            "d) No error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Arithmetic operations such as addition, subtraction, multiplication and division are allowed on enumerated constants. Valid arithmetic operators are +, -, *, / and %."
    },
    {
        "id": 1120,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code if input given is 2?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> day\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>e\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Enter the value for a\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 3",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above does not result in any error. This is because, although the value of enum constants cannot be changed, yet it is possible to modify the value of the enum instance variable(that is ‘g’ in this case)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1121,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code if the code is executed on a 32 bit platform?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    c <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n    d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n    h <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>\n    s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n&nbsp;\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n        a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Size of enum variable = %d bytes\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Size of enum variable = 2 bytes",
            "c) Size of enum variable = 4 bytes",
            "d) Size of enum variables = 8 bytes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above results in an error. This is because memory is not allocated for constants in enum. Thereore ampersand(&) cannot be used with them. Also, a value has already been assigned to ‘a’, which cannot be changed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1122,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>e\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>e<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 7",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The size of an enum variable is equal to the size of an integer. The size of an integer on a 32 bit platform is equal to 4 bytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 1123,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    b<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since arithmetic operations are allowed on enum constants, hence the expression given is evaluates. b*c+e-d = 2*3+5-4 = 6+5-4 = 7"
    },
    {
        "id": 1124,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry1\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry1 s1<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry1 s<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw2\">enum</span> sanfoundry s2<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>s1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>s2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 011",
            "c) 110",
            "d) 101"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above code results in an error. This is because it is not possible to change the values of enum constants. In the code shown above, the statement: b=10; causes the error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1125,
        "Question": "Which of the following keywords is used to define an alternate name for an already existing data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) default",
            "b) volatile",
            "c) typedef",
            "d) static"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The keyword typedef is used to define an alternate name for an already existing data type. It is mostly used for used defined data types."
    },
    {
        "id": 1126,
        "Question": "We want to create an alias name for an identifier of the type unsigned long. The alias name is: ul. The correct way to do this using the keyword typedef is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) typedef unsigned long ul;",
            "b) unsigned long typedef ul;",
            "c) typedef ul unsigned long;",
            "d) ul typedef unsigned long;"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The syntax of the keyword typedef is: keyword <existing_name> <alias_name>;\nHence if we want to create an alias name (ul) for an identifier of type unsigned long, the correct way to do this would be: typedef unsigned long ul;"
    },
    {
        "id": 1127,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    a b<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    d<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">/</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 8",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the code shown above, the keyword typedef is used to give an alias name (a) to an identifier of the type int.  The expression on evaluation gives the answer 10. Hence the output of the code shown above is 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 1128,
        "Question": "4. WWhat will be the output of the following C code? (If the name entered is: Sanfoundry)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;string.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> employee\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span>  name<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">50</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span>   salary<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span> e1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Enter Employee name\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>e1.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>e1.<span class=\"me1\">name</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sanfoundry.name",
            "b) nSanfoundry",
            "c) Sanfoundry",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above will result in an error because we have used the data type e1 (defined using the keyword typedef) in the form of an identifier."
    },
    {
        "id": 1129,
        "Question": "6. What is the size of myArray in the code shown below? (Assume that 1 character occupies 1 byte)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> x<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nx myArray<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 bytes",
            "b) 10 bytes",
            "c) 40 bytes",
            "d) 50 bytes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The statement given in the question is incorrect. The keyword typedef can be used to give an alias name to all data types as well as pointers."
    },
    {
        "id": 1130,
        "Question": "Consider this statement: typedef enum good {a, b, c} hello;                                                                                 Which of the following statements is incorrect about hello?",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello is a typedef of enum good",
            "b) hello is a structure",
            "c) hello is a variable of type enum good",
            "d) the statement shown above is erroneous"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The size of myArray will be equal to 50 bytes. In the code shown above, we have defined a character array x, of size 10. Hence the output of the code shown above is 10*5 = 50 bytes."
    },
    {
        "id": 1131,
        "Question": "One of the major difference between typedef and #define is that typedef interpretation is performed by the _________________ whereas #define interpretation is performed by the _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) pre-processor, compiler",
            "b) user, pre-processor",
            "c) compiler, pre-processor",
            "d) compiler, user"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It shows the correct way to declare x, y and z as pointers of type int using the keyword typedef. The advantage of using typedef with pointers is that we can declare any number of pointers in a single statement."
    },
    {
        "id": 1132,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">union</span> a\n    <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n        <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n        <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> ch<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>hello<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    hello u<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    u.<span class=\"me1\">ch</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    u.<span class=\"me1\">ch</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d, %d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> u.<span class=\"me1\">ch</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> u.<span class=\"me1\">ch</span><span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2, 3",
            "b) 3, 2",
            "c) 32",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The keyword typedef is used to give an alternate name to an existing data type. Hence hello is the new name for enum good."
    },
    {
        "id": 1133,
        "Question": "There are two groups of string functions defined in the header <string.h>. What are they?",
        "Options": [
            "a) first group names beginning with str; second group names beginning  with mem",
            "b) first group names beginning with str; second group names beginning with is",
            "c) first group names beginning with string; second group names beginning with mem",
            "d) first group names beginning with str; second group names beginning with type"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are two groups of string functions declared under the header <string.h>. The first have names beginning with str and second have names beginning with mem."
    },
    {
        "id": 1134,
        "Question": "What is the use of function char *strchr(ch, c)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) return pointer to first occurrence of ch in c or NULL if not present",
            "b) return pointer to first occurrence of c in ch or NULL if not present",
            "c) return pointer to first occurrence of ch in c or ignores if not present",
            "d) return pointer to first occurrence of cin ch or ignores if not present"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The given code char *strchr(ch, c)  return pointer to first occurrence of c in ch or NULL if not present."
    },
    {
        "id": 1135,
        "Question": "Which code from the given option return pointer to last occurrence of c in ch or NULL if not present?",
        "Options": [
            "a) char *strchr(ch, c)",
            "b) char *strrchr(ch, c)",
            "c) char *strncat(ch, c)",
            "d) char *strcat(ch, c)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The function char *strrchr(ch, c)  returns pointer to last occurrence of c in ch or NULL if not present."
    },
    {
        "id": 1136,
        "Question": "Which among the given options compares atmost n characters of string ch to string s?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int strncmp(ch, s, n)",
            "b) int strcmp(ch, s)",
            "c) int strncmp(s, ch, n)",
            "d) int strcmp(s, ch)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: int strncmp(ch, s, n)  is used to compare at most n characters of string ch to string s; return <0 if ch0 of ch >s."
    },
    {
        "id": 1137,
        "Question": "Which among the given options is the right explanation for the statement size_t strcspn(c, s)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) return length of prefix of s consisting of characters not in c",
            "b) return length of prefix of s consisting of characters present in c",
            "c) return length of prefix of c consisting of characters not in s",
            "d) return length of prefix of c consisting of characters present in s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The function size_t strcspn(c, s)  is used to return length of prefix of c consisting of characters not in s."
    },
    {
        "id": 1138,
        "Question": "The mem functions are meant for _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) returning a pointer to the token",
            "b) manipulating objects as character arrays",
            "c) returning a pointer for implemented-defined string",
            "d) returning a pointer to first occurrence of string in another string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mem functions is used for manipulating objects as character arrays."
    },
    {
        "id": 1139,
        "Question": "What is the function of void *memset(s, c, n)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) places character s into first n characters of c, return c",
            "b) places character c into first n characters of s, return s",
            "c) places character s into first n characters of c, return s",
            "d) places character c into first n character of s, return c"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The void *memset(s, c, n)  places character c into first n characters of s, return s."
    },
    {
        "id": 1140,
        "Question": "Functions whose names begin with “strn”",
        "Options": [
            "a) manipulates sequences of arbitrary characters",
            "b) manipulates null-terminated sequences of characters",
            "c) manipulates sequence of non – null characters.",
            "d) returns a pointer to the token"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Functions whose names begin with “strn”  manipulates the sequence of non-null characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 1141,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the right syntax to copy n characters from the object pointed to by s2 into the object pointed to by s1?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void *memcpy(void *s1,const void *s2,size_t n);",
            "b) void *memcpy(void  *s2, const void *s1, size_t n);",
            "c) void memcpy(void  *s1,const void *s2, size_t n);",
            "d) void memcpy(void *s2,const void *s1,size_t n);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The memcpy() function copies n characters from the object pointed to by s2 into the object pointed to by s1. If copying takes place between objects that overlap, the behavior is undefined."
    },
    {
        "id": 1142,
        "Question": "What does the following function returns void *memmove(void *s1,const void s2, size_t n);?",
        "Options": [
            "a) returns the value of s1",
            "b) returns the value of s2",
            "c) doesn’t return any value",
            "d) returns the value of s1 and s2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The memmove() function copies n characters from the object pointed to by s2 into the object pointed to by s1.The memmove() function returns the value of s1."
    },
    {
        "id": 1143,
        "Question": "Which among the following is Copying function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) memcpy()",
            "b) strcopy()",
            "c) memcopy()",
            "d) strxcpy()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The memcpy() function is used to  copy n characters from the object.\nThe code is void *memcpy(void *s1,const void *s2, size_t n)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1144,
        "Question": "Which function will you choose to join two words?",
        "Options": [
            "a) strcpy()",
            "b) strcat()",
            "c) strncon()",
            "d) memcon()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The strcat() function is used for concatenating two strings, appends a copy of the string.\nchar *strcat(char *s1,const char *s2);"
    },
    {
        "id": 1145,
        "Question": " The ______ function appends not more than n characters.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strcat()",
            "b) strcon()",
            "c) strncat()",
            "d) memcat()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The strncat() function appends not more than n characters from the array(s2) to the end of the string(s1).char *strncat(char *s1, const char *s2,size_t n);"
    },
    {
        "id": 1146,
        "Question": "What will strcmp() function do?",
        "Options": [
            "a) compares the first n characters of the object",
            "b) compares the string",
            "c) undefined function",
            "d) copies the string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The strcmp() function compares the string s1 to the string s2.\nint strcmp(const char *s1,const char *s2);"
    },
    {
        "id": 1147,
        "Question": "What is the prototype of strcoll() function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int strcoll(const char *s1,const char *s2)",
            "b) int strcoll(const char *s1)",
            "c) int strcoll(const *s1,const *s2)",
            "d) int strcoll(const *s1)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The prototype of strcoll() function is int strcoll(const char *s1,const char *s2)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1148,
        "Question": "What is the function of strcoll()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) compares the string, result is dependent on the LC_COLLATE",
            "b) copies the string, result is dependent on the LC_COLLATE",
            "c) compares the string, result is not dependent on the LC_COLLATE",
            "d) copies the string, result is not dependent on the LC_COLLATE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The strcoll() function compares the string s1 to the string s2, both interpreted as appropriate to the LC_COLLATE category of the current locale."
    },
    {
        "id": 1149,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the variable type defined in header string. h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sizet",
            "b) size",
            "c) size_t",
            "d) size-t"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: This is the unsigned integral type and is the result of the sizeof keyword."
    },
    {
        "id": 1150,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> pla<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"string1\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> src<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"string2\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Before memmove place= %s, src = %s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> pla<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> src<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">memmove</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>pla<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> src<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">7</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"After memmove place = %s, src = %s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> pla<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> src<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Before memmove place= string1, src = string2 After memmove place = string2, src = string2",
            "b) Before memmove place = string2, src = string2 After memmove place= string1, src = string2",
            "c) Before memmove place = string2, src = string1 After memmove place= string2, src =string2",
            "d) Before memmove place= string1, src = string2 After memmove place=string1, src = string1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: NULL macro is the value of a null pointer constant."
    },
    {
        "id": 1151,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"st0\">\"ABCDEF1234567\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"269\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nlen <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strcspn</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"First matching character is at %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> len <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) First matching character is at 8",
            "b) First matching character is at 7",
            "c) First matching character is at 9",
            "d) First matching character is at 12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the C library function void *memmove(void *str1, const void *str2, size_t n) copies n characters from str2 to str1."
    },
    {
        "id": 1152,
        "Question": "What is the return value of strxfrm()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) length of the transformed string, not including the terminating null-character",
            "b) length of the transformed string, including the terminating null-character",
            "c) display the transformed string, not including the terminating null character",
            "d) display the transformed string, not including the terminating null-character"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This function returns the length of the transformed string, not including the terminating null character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1153,
        "Question": " The C library function _________ breaks string s1 into a series of tokens using the delimiter s2.",
        "Options": [
            "a) char *strtok(char *s1,const char *s2);",
            "b) char  *strtok(char *s2,const char *s1);",
            "c) char *strstr(char *s1,const char *s2);",
            "d) char *strstr(char *s2,const char *s1);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This function returns a pointer to the first occurrence in s1 of any of the entire sequence of characters specified in s2, or a null pointer if the sequence is not present in s1.\nchar *strstr(const char *s1, const char *s2)"
    },
    {
        "id": 1154,
        "Question": "The______function returns a pointer to the first character of a token.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strstr()",
            "b) strcpy()",
            "c) strspn()",
            "d) strtok()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The C library function char *strtok(char *s1, const char *s2) breaks string s1 into a series of tokens using the delimiter s2."
    },
    {
        "id": 1155,
        "Question": "which of the following function returns a pointer to the located string or a null pointer if string is not found.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strtok()",
            "b) strstr()",
            "c) strspn()",
            "d) strrchr()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The strtok() function returns a pointer to the first character of a token, if there is no token then a null pointer is returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 1156,
        "Question": "Which of the given function is used to return a pointer to the located character?",
        "Options": [
            "a) strrchr()",
            "b) strxfrm()",
            "c) memchar()",
            "d) strchar()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The strstr() function is used to return a pointer to the located string, or if string is not found a null pointer is returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 1157,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"abcdef\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"fgha\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>mat<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmat<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strpbrk</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>mat<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"First matching character: %c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>mat<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Character not found\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) g",
            "b) a",
            "c) h",
            "d) f"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The strchr() function is used to return a pointer to the located character if character does not occur then a null pointer is returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 1158,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Helloworld \"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nlen <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strspn</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Length of initial segment matching %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> len <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 4",
            "d) no match"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: char *strpbrk(const char *s1,const char *s2);\nThe first occurrence in the string s1 of any character from the string s2 is done by strpbrk()."
    },
    {
        "id": 1159,
        "Question": "The______ function returns the number of characters that are present before  the terminating null character.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strlength()",
            "b) strlen()",
            "c) strlent()",
            "d) strchr()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The strpbrk() function is used to locate the first occurrence in the string str1 of any character from the string str2."
    },
    {
        "id": 1160,
        "Question": "1. What will be returned in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">size<span class=\"sy0\">-</span> t <span class=\"kw3\">strlen</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>sc<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">for</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>sc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>sc<span class=\"sy0\">!=</span> <span class=\"st0\">' \\ O '</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>sc<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">return</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>sc <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> s<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) number of characters equal in sc",
            "b) length of string s",
            "c) doesn’t return any value",
            "d) displays string s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The strlen() function is used to return the length of the string s."
    },
    {
        "id": 1161,
        "Question": "3. What will the following C code do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strrchr</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c <span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> ch <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>sc<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">for</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>sc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>s<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\nSC <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">9</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\ni f <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">==</span><span class=\"st0\">'\\O'</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> s<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) find last occurrence of c in char s[ ].",
            "b) find first occurrence of c in char s[ ].",
            "c) find the current location of c in char s[ ].",
            "d) There is error in the given code"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Both strcspn() and strpbrk() perform the same function. Only strspn() the return values differ. The function strspn() is the complement of strcspn() ."
    },
    {
        "id": 1162,
        "Question": "This function offers the quickest way to determine whether two character sequences of the same known length match character for the character up to and including any null character in both.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strcmp()",
            "b) memcmp()",
            "c) strncmp()",
            "d) no such function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:The strrchr() function locates the last occurrence of c (converted to a char) in the string pointed to by s. String contains null character as a terminating part of it."
    },
    {
        "id": 1163,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">15</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">15</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> mat<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"abcdef\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str2<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"ABCDEF\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmat<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strncmp</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str2<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>mat<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"str1 is not greater than str2\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span> <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>mat<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"str2 is is not greater than str1\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"both are equal\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) str1 is not greater than str2",
            "b) str2 is not greater than str1",
            "c) both are equal",
            "d) error in given code"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The strncmp() function is used to compare not more than n characters (characters that follow a null character are not compared) from the array pointed to by one, to the array pointed to by other."
    },
    {
        "id": 1164,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw3\">memset</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> size<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>t n<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> ch <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>su<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">for</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>su <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"sy0\">++</span>su<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">--</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>br<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>su <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span>br<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) store c throughout unsigned char s[n] ",
            "b) store c throughout signed char s[n] ",
            "c) find first occurrence of c in s[n] ",
            "d) find last occurrence of c in s[n]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The C library function int strncmp(const char *str1, const char *str2, size_t n) is used to compare at most the first n bytes of str1 and str2."
    },
    {
        "id": 1165,
        "Question": "Use_______to determine the null-terminated message string that corresponds to the error code errcode.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strerror()",
            "b) strstr()",
            "c) strxfrm()",
            "d) memset()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This is the safe way to store the same value throughout a contiguous sequence of elements in a character array."
    },
    {
        "id": 1166,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str1<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Helloworld\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"world\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>mat<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmat <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strstr</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The substring is:%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> mat<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The substring is:world",
            "b) The substring is:Hello",
            "c) The substring is:Helloworld",
            "d) error in the code"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Use strerror (errcode) to determine the null-terminated message string that corresponds to the error code errcode."
    },
    {
        "id": 1167,
        "Question": "void *memcpy(void *dest, const void *src, size_t n)  What does the following code do?",
        "Options": [
            "a) copies n characters from src to dest",
            "b) copies n character from dest to src",
            "c) transform n character from dest to src",
            "d) transform n character from src to dest"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The C library function char *strstr(const char *str1, const char *str2) is used to find the first occurrence of the substring str2 in the string str1.The terminating ‘\\0’ characters are not compared."
    },
    {
        "id": 1168,
        "Question": "10. What will the given C code do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">memcmp</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>str2<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">size_t</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) compares the first n bytes of str1 and str2",
            "b) copies the first n bytes of str1 to str2",
            "c) copies the first n bytes of str2 to str1",
            "d) invalid function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the C library function memcpy() is used to copy n characters from memory area src to memory area dest."
    },
    {
        "id": 1169,
        "Question": "Which header declares several functions useful for testing and mapping characters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) assert.h",
            "b) stdio.h",
            "c) ctype.h",
            "d) errno.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The header <ctype.h> declares several functions useful for testing and mapping characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 1170,
        "Question": "The______function tests for any character for which isalpha or isdigit is true.",
        "Options": [
            "a) isxdigit()",
            "b) isspace()",
            "c) isalnum()",
            "d) isupper()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: int isalnum(int c)\nThe isalnum function tests for any character for which isalpha or isdigit is true."
    },
    {
        "id": 1171,
        "Question": "3. What does the following C code do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">iscntrl</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) checks if character is upper case",
            "b) checks if character is lower case",
            "c) tests for any control character",
            "d) no function as such"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:\nint iscntrl( int c);\nThe iscntrl function tests for any control character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1172,
        "Question": "4. What do the following C function do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">isgraph</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) tests for only space character",
            "b) tests for only digit",
            "c) tests for only lower case",
            "d) tests for any printing character"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: int isgraph(int c);\nThe isgraph function tests for any printing character except space."
    },
    {
        "id": 1173,
        "Question": "Which function returns true only for the characters defined as lowercase letters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) islow()",
            "b) islower()",
            "c) isalpa()",
            "d) isalnum()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: int isdigit(int c);\nThis function checks whether the passed character is a decimal digit."
    },
    {
        "id": 1174,
        "Question": "This function checks whether the passed character is white-space.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ispunct()",
            "b) isgraph()",
            "c) isspace()",
            "d) isalpha()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: int islower( int c);\nThe islower function tests for any character that is a lowercase letter."
    },
    {
        "id": 1175,
        "Question": "Which function tests for any character that is an uppercase letter.",
        "Options": [
            "a) iscntrl()",
            "b) ispunct()",
            "c) isdigit()",
            "d) isupper()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The isspace function tests for any character that is a standard white-space character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1176,
        "Question": "The______function tests for any hexadecimal-digit character.",
        "Options": [
            "a) iscntrl()",
            "b) ispunct()",
            "c) isgraph()",
            "d) isxdigit()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The isspace function tests for any character that is a standard white-space character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1177,
        "Question": "The________function converts an uppercase letter to the corresponding lowercase letter.",
        "Options": [
            "a) islower()",
            "b) isupper()",
            "c) toupper()",
            "d) tolower()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If the argument is a character for which isupper() is true and  islower() is true for another set of character, the tolower() function returns the corresponding character;otherwise, the argument is returned unchanged."
    },
    {
        "id": 1178,
        "Question": "The toupper() function converts a ______ to the corresponding ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) uppercase, lowercase",
            "b) lowercase, uppercase",
            "c) binary, decimal",
            "d) decimal, binary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The toupper() function is used to convert a lowercase letter to the corresponding uppercase letter.\nIf the value is a character for which islower() is true and isupper () is true for another set of characters, the toupper() function returns the corresponding character, otherwise, the value is returned unchanged."
    },
    {
        "id": 1179,
        "Question": "fgetc, getc, getchar are all declared in ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdio. h",
            "b) ctype. h",
            "c) assert. h",
            "d) stdarg. h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The functions getc, fgetc, getchar are all declared in stdio.h header file."
    },
    {
        "id": 1180,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">' '</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isgraph</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"ch = %c can be printed <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"ch=%c cannot be printed <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ch = ‘ ‘ can be printed",
            "b) ch = ‘ ‘ cannot be printed",
            "c) compile error",
            "d) run-time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: isalpha() function is used to test for letters in the local alphabet. For the locale, the local alphabet consists of  26 English letters, in each of two cases."
    },
    {
        "id": 1181,
        "Question": "The C library function checks whether the passed character is printable.",
        "Options": [
            "a) isgraph()",
            "b) isalpha()",
            "c) isprint()",
            "d) ispunct()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  void isgraph()  function is used to check if the character has graphical representation. Graphical representations  character are all those characters that can be printed except for whitespace characters, which is not considered as isgraph characters."
    },
    {
        "id": 1182,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> ch<span class=\"br0\">[</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"0xC\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isxdigit</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">[</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"ch = %s is hexadecimal character <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"ch = %s is not hexadecimal character <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ch = 0xC is hexadecimal character",
            "b) ch = 0xC is not hexadecimal character",
            "c) compile error",
            "d) run-time error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  int isprint(int c) function is used to check whether the passed character can be printed.A control character is not a printable character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1183,
        "Question": "Which among the following option is the full set of character class Hexadecimal digits?",
        "Options": [
            "a) { 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 A B C D E F }",
            "b) { 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 a b c d e f }",
            "c) { 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 A B C D E F a b c d e f }",
            "d) { 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9}"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The C library function isxdigit checks whether the passed character is a hexadecimal digit."
    },
    {
        "id": 1184,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Little Star\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">while</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">putchar</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">toupper</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">[</span>i<span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\ni<span class=\"sy0\">++;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) little star",
            "b) lITTLE sTAR",
            "c) LITTLE STAR",
            "d) Little Star"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: digit or one of the first letters of the alphabet in either case,  ‘a’ through ‘f’ and ‘A’ through ‘F’ is contained in the character class Hexadecimal digits."
    },
    {
        "id": 1185,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> ch <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">'<span class=\"es1\">\\t</span>'</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">isprint</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"ch = |%c| printable  <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"ch= |%c| not printable <span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ch = |\\t| printable",
            "b) ch = |\\t| not printable",
            "c) ch = |    | printable",
            "d) ch = |    | not printable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The C library function toupper converts the lowercase letter to uppercase."
    },
    {
        "id": 1186,
        "Question": "_______ occurs when a result is too large in magnitude to represent errors as a floating-point value of the required type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) underflow",
            "b) signiﬁcance loss",
            "c) domain",
            "d) overflow"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An overflow occurs when a result is too large in magnitude to represent errors as a floating-point value of the required type."
    },
    {
        "id": 1187,
        "Question": "What occurs when a result has nowhere near the number of signiﬁcant digits indicated by its type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) domain",
            "b) underflow",
            "c) overflow",
            "d) signiﬁcance loss"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A signiﬁcance loss occurs when a result has nowhere near the number of signiﬁcant digits indicated by its type."
    },
    {
        "id": 1188,
        "Question": "What error occurs when a result is undeﬁned for a given argument value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) signiﬁcance loss",
            "b) underflow",
            "c) overflow",
            "d) domain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A domain error occurs when a result is undeﬁned for a given argument value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1189,
        "Question": "4.______ is reported on a domain error.",
        "Options": [
            "a) EDOM",
            "b) ERANGE",
            "c) Signiﬁcance loss",
            "d) Underflow"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: EDOM is reported on a domain error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1190,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">errno <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\ny <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">sqrt</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>errno <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> EDOM<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>Invalid value\\n<span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>Valid value\\n<span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Invalid value",
            "b) Valid value",
            "c) No output",
            "d) Compile error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: This macro represents a range error, which occurs if an input argument is outside the range, over which the mathematical function is deﬁned and errno is set to ERANGE."
    },
    {
        "id": 1191,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">errno <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\ny <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">sqrt</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>errno <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> EDOM<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>Invalid value \\n<span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>Valid value\\n<span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>quot<span class=\"sy0\">;</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Invalid value",
            "b) Valid value",
            "c) No output",
            "d) Compile error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The C library macro EDOM represents a domain error, which occurs if an input argument is outside the domain, over which the mathematical function is deﬁned and errno is set to EDOM."
    },
    {
        "id": 1192,
        "Question": "__________ tells the compiler that this data is deﬁned somewhere and will be connected with the linker.",
        "Options": [
            "a) errno",
            "b) extern",
            "c) variable",
            "d) yvals"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The C library macro EDOM represents a domain error, which occurs if an input argument is outside the domain, over which the mathematical function is deﬁned and errno is set to EDOM."
    },
    {
        "id": 1193,
        "Question": "Which of the following header declares mathematical functions and macros?",
        "Options": [
            "a) math.h",
            "b) assert.h",
            "c) stdmat. h",
            "d) stdio. h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The header ﬁle math.h declares all the mathematical functions and macros."
    },
    {
        "id": 1194,
        "Question": "All the functions in this library take as a parameter and return as the output.",
        "Options": [
            "a) double, int",
            "b) double, double",
            "c) int, double",
            "d) int, int"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: All the function in this math library takes double as a parameter and gives double as the result.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1195,
        "Question": "HUGE_VAL macro is used when the output of the function may not be ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) floating point numbers",
            "b) integer number",
            "c) short int",
            "d) long int"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: HUGE_VAL macro is used when the result of a function may not be representable as a floating point number."
    },
    {
        "id": 1196,
        "Question": "What error occurs if an input argument is outside the domain over which the mathematical function is deﬁned?",
        "Options": [
            "a) domain error",
            "b) range error",
            "c) no error",
            "d) domain and range error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A domain error occurs if an input argument is outside the domain over which the mathematical function is deﬁned."
    },
    {
        "id": 1197,
        "Question": "A range error occurs if the result of the function cannot be represented as a value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) short int",
            "c) double",
            "d) float"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: if the result of the function cannot be represented as a double value, a range error occurs. If the result overflows (the magnitude of the result is so large that it cannot be represented in an object of the speciﬁed type), the function returns the value of the macro HUGE_VAL, with the same sign as the correct value of the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1198,
        "Question": "If the result overflows, the function returns the value of the macro HUGE_VAL, carrying the same sign except for the _________ function as the correct value of the function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sin",
            "b) cos",
            "c) cosec",
            "d) tan"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If the result overflows i.e the magnitude of the result is too large to be represented in an object of the speciﬁed type, the function returns the value of the macro HUGE_VAL, with the same sign except for the tan function as the correct value of the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1199,
        "Options": [
            "a) range error",
            "b) domain error",
            "c) no error",
            "d) domain and range error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the result underflows i.e the magnitude of the result is very small to be represented in an object of the speciﬁed type, the function returns zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 1200,
        "Question": "Which function returns the arc sine in the range [-pi/2, +pi/2] radians?",
        "Options": [
            "a) arcsin()",
            "b) asin()",
            "c) sin()",
            "d) asine()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The acos() function is used to compute the principal value of the inverse of cosine of x. A domain error occurs for arguments not in the range [-1, +1]."
    },
    {
        "id": 1201,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> deg<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> rad<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nx <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">1.0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nval <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">180.0</span> <span class=\"sy0\">/</span> <span class=\"nu16\">3.14</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\ndeg <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">atan</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> val<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The arc tangent of %lf is %lf degrees\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> deg<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The arc tangent of 1.000000 is 45.000000 degrees",
            "b) The arc tangent of 1.000 is 45.000degrees",
            "c) The arc tangent of 1 is 45 degrees",
            "d) The arc tangent of 1.0000is 45.0000degrees"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The asin() function is used to compute the principal value of the inverse of sine of x. A domain error occurs for arguments not in the range [-1, +1]."
    },
    {
        "id": 1202,
        "Question": "1. What does the given C code do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"kw3\">atan2</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The atan2 function returns the arc tangent of x/y",
            "b) The atan2 function returns the arc tangent of x",
            "c) The atan2 function returns the arc tangent of y/x",
            "d) The atan2 function returns the arc tangent of y"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The atan2 function returns the arc tangent of y/x, in the range [-pi,+pi] radians."
    },
    {
        "id": 1203,
        "Question": "The cos function computes the cosine of x.",
        "Options": [
            "a) measured in radians",
            "b) measured in degrees",
            "c) measured in gradian",
            "d) measured in milliradian"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The cos function computes the cosine of x (measured in radians)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1204,
        "Question": "The function computes the hyperbolic cosine of x.",
        "Options": [
            "a) cos(x)",
            "b) cosine(x)",
            "c) cosh(x)",
            "d) cosineh(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The cosh() function computes the hyperbolic cosine of x. The cosh function returns the hyperbolic cosine value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1205,
        "Question": "What error occurs if the magnitude of x is too large in sinh(double x)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) domain error",
            "b) range error",
            "c) no error",
            "d) zero is returned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:The sinh() function computes the hyperbolic sine of x. A range error occurs if the magnitude of x is too large.If the result overflows i.e the magnitude of the result is too large to be represented in an object of the speciﬁed type)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1206,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct code?",
        "Options": [
            "a) tanh(double x)",
            "b) tanh double x",
            "c) tanhdouble x",
            "d) tanhdoublex"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The correct code is tanh(double x). The tanh() function computes the hyperbolic tangent of x."
    },
    {
        "id": 1207,
        "Question": "Name the function that breaks a floating-point number into a normalized fraction and an integral power of 2.",
        "Options": [
            "a) exp()",
            "b) frexp()",
            "c) Idexp()",
            "d) modf()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The frexp() function breaks a floating-point number into a normalized fraction and an integral power of 2."
    },
    {
        "id": 1208,
        "Question": "The function computes the exponential function of x.",
        "Options": [
            "a) exp(x)",
            "b) frexp(x)",
            "c) frexp x",
            "d) exp x"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The exp(x) function computes the exponential function of x."
    },
    {
        "id": 1209,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"kw3\">log</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) returns natural logarithm of x",
            "b) range error",
            "c) domain error",
            "d) returns natural logarithm of -x"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: double ldexp(double x, int exp);\nThe ldexp function multiplies a floating-point number by an integral power of 2. A range error may occur. The ldexp() function returns the value of x times 2 raised to the power exp."
    },
    {
        "id": 1210,
        "Question": "Which of the given function is a library function under the header math.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) log10()",
            "b) log20()",
            "c) log30()",
            "d) log50()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The log() function is used to compute the natural logarithm of x. If the argument is negative, a domain error occurs. A range error may occur if the argument is zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 1211,
        "Question": "1. Which of the following statement is correct?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> z<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    x <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">5.123456</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    z<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">modf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) y stores integer part of x, z returns fractional part of x",
            "b) y stores integer part of x, z returns integer part of x",
            "c) y stores fractional part of x, z returns integer part of x",
            "d) y stores fractional part of x, z returns fractional part of x"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: double modf(double x, double *y)\nThis function returns the fractional part of x, with the same sign. modf() function breaks the argument value into integer and fraction parts, each of which has the same sign as the argument. It stores the integer part as a double in the object pointed to by y."
    },
    {
        "id": 1212,
        "Question": "A function is declared as sqrt(-x) under the header file math.h, what will the function return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) square root of x",
            "b) complex number",
            "c) domain error",
            "d) range error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The pow() function computes x raised to the power y. A domain error occurs if x is negative and y is not an integral value. A domain error occurs if the result cannot be represented when x is zero and y is less than or equal to zero. A range error may occur."
    },
    {
        "id": 1213,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu16\">1.2</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%.1lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">ceil</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 1.0",
            "d) 2.0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: double sqrt (double x);\nThe sqrt function computes the nonnegative square root of x. A domain error occurs if the argument is negative."
    },
    {
        "id": 1214,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">    <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>y<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span> <span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf %lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fabs</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw3\">fabs</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3  6",
            "b) -3  6",
            "c) 3.0  6.0",
            "d) 3.000000  6.000000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ceil function returns the smallest integral value not less than x, expressed as a double."
    },
    {
        "id": 1215,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu16\">1.8</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%.2lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw3\">floor</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.0",
            "b) 2.00",
            "c) 1.0",
            "d) 1.00"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: double fabs(double x);\nThe fabs function computes the absolute value of a floating-point number X."
    },
    {
        "id": 1216,
        "Question": "double ______ (double x, double y) computes the floating-point remainder of x/y.",
        "Options": [
            "a) modf",
            "b) fmod",
            "c) ceil",
            "d) floor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: double floor(double x);\nThe floor function computes the largest integral value not greater than x."
    },
    {
        "id": 1217,
        "Question": "9. Which of the given C function can be used instead of the apparent identity pointed to by y?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"kw4\">double</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu16\">0.5</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">exp</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> <span class=\"kw3\">exp</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>x<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) cos(x)",
            "b) cosh(x)",
            "c) fmod(x)",
            "d) modf(x)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: double fmod(doublr x, double y);\nThe fmod() function computes the floating-point remainder of x/y."
    },
    {
        "id": 1218,
        "Question": "Which function is used to recombine the fraction and exponent parts of a floating-point value after you have worked on them separately?",
        "Options": [
            "a) frexp()",
            "b) exp()",
            "c) modf()",
            "d) Idexp()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: sqrt(x) function is generally much faster than the apparent equivalent pow (x, 0.5)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1219,
        "Question": "_______variable type defined in the header stdlib.h is an integer type of the size of a wide character constant.",
        "Options": [
            "a) size_t",
            "b) wchar_t",
            "c) div_t",
            "d) ldiv_t"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: wchar_t\nThis is an integer type of the size of a wide character constant defined under the header stdlib.h ."
    },
    {
        "id": 1220,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct description of EXIT_FAILURE?",
        "Options": [
            "a) This is the value for the exit function to return in case of failure",
            "b) This is the value for the exit function to terminate the program",
            "c) This is the value for the exit function to return in case of success",
            "d) This is the value for the exit function to return in case it is the maximum value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macros defined is EXIT-FAILURE which expand to integral expressions that may be used as the argument to the exit function to return unsuccessful."
    },
    {
        "id": 1221,
        "Question": "Which of the given function converts the string pointed to, by the argument str to a floating-point number?",
        "Options": [
            "a) atof(const char *str)",
            "b) strtod(const char *str, char **endptr)",
            "c) atoi(const char *str)",
            "d) atol(const char *str)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: RAND_MAX is the macro which expands to an integral constant expression, the value of which is the maximum value returned by the rand function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1222,
        "Question": "The_______function converts the initial portion of the string pointed to by, to int representation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) atof()",
            "b) atoi()",
            "c) strtod()",
            "d) atol()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The atof function converts the initial portion of the string pointed to by str to double representation. Except for the behavior on the error, it is equivalent to strtod (nptr, (char **)NULL)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1223,
        "Question": "atol(const char *str) Converts the string pointed to, by the argument str.",
        "Options": [
            "a) to a long integer",
            "b) to a integer",
            "c) to a floating point number",
            "d) to a unsigned long integer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: int atoi(const char *str); The C library function int atoi(const char *str) converts the string argument str to an integer (type int)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1224,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nstr<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"123546\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> res<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">atof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"String value = %s, Float value = %f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> res<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) String value = 123546, Float value = 123546.0",
            "b) String value = 123546 , Float value = 123546.000000",
            "c) String value = 123546 , Float value = 0.000000",
            "d) String value = 123546 , Float value = 123546.000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: long int atol(conat char *str);\nThe atol() function converts the initial portion of the string pointed to by str to long int representation. Except for the behavior on error, it is equivalent to strtol (nptr, (char **)NULL, 10)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1225,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \nres <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">atof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"String value = %s, Float value = %f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> res<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) String value = Hello, Float value = 0.000000",
            "b) String value = Hello, Float value = 0",
            "c) String value = “Hello” , Float value = 0.000000",
            "d) String value = “Hello” , Float value = 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: atof() function returns the converted floating point number as a double value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1226,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"123456\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \nres <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">atoi</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s  %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> res<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 123456  0",
            "b) 123456  0.0",
            "c) 123456  123456",
            "d) 123456 123456.0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: atof() function returns the converted floating point number as a double value. If no valid conversion could be performed, it returns zero (0.0)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1227,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span>  \n<span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \nres <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">atoi</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\" %s  %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> res<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello  0.000000",
            "b) “Hello”  0.000000",
            "c) Hello   0",
            "d) “Hello” 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: atoi() function returns the converted integral number as an int value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1228,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> word<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span> <span class=\"br0\">]</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"1.234555 WELCOME\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>w<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> <span class=\"kw4\">double</span> dis<span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \ndis<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strtod</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>word<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>w<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The number is %lf<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> dis<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"String  is |%s|\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> w<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) The number is 1.234555 String  is |WELCOME|",
            "b) The number is 1.2345550 String  is |WELCOME|",
            "c) The number is 1.234555 String  is |1.234555 WELCOME|",
            "d) Errror"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: strtod() function is used to return the converted floating point number as a double value, else zero value (0.0) is returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 1229,
        "Question": "2. Which statement is correct work reference to endptr?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">double</span> <span class=\"kw3\">strtod</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>nptr<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">**</span>endptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) A pointer to the starting string is stored in the object pointed to by endptr, provided that endptr is a null pointer",
            "b) A pointer to the ﬁnal string is stored in the object pointed to by endptr, provided that endptr is not a null pointer",
            "c)  A pointer to the final string is stored in the object pointed to by endptr, provided that endptr is a null pointer",
            "d)  A pointer to the starting string is stored in the object pointed to by endptr, provided that endptr is not a null pointer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If endptr is not NULL then endptr stores the pointer to a character after the last character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1230,
        "Question": " Which of the following functions decomposes the input string into three pans: an initial, possibly empty, sequence of white-space characters?",
        "Options": [
            "a) strtod()",
            "b) atof()",
            "c) atol()",
            "d) strtol()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The strtol() function is used to convert the initial portion of the string pointed to by, to long int representation. First, it decomposes the input string into three pans: an initial, empty, white-space characters (as speciﬁed by the isspace function). "
    },
    {
        "id": 1231,
        "Question": "The______function is used to convert the initial portion of the string pointed to by, to unsigned long int representation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) strtod()",
            "b) atol()",
            "c) strtoul()",
            "d) strtol()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: unsigned long int strtoul(const char *p, char **ptr, int base) function is used to  convert the initial part of the string in p to an unsigned long int value according to the given base,it must be between 2 and 36 inclusive, or be the special value 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 1232,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax of the function strtoul()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) unsigned long int strtoul(const char *n, char **ptr, int base)",
            "b) unsigned long int strtoul(const char *n, char **ptr)",
            "c) unsigned long int strtoul(const char *n)",
            "d) int strtoul(const char *n)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: usigned long int strtoul(conmt char *n, char **ptr, int base); The strtoul() function is used to convert the initial portion of the string pointed to by n to unsigned long int representation."
    },
    {
        "id": 1233,
        "Question": "Select the right statement with reference to malloc() and calloc().",
        "Options": [
            "a) malloc() does not set the memory to zero whereas calloc() sets allocated memory to zero",
            "b) malloc() sets the memory to zero whereas calloc() does not set allocated memory to zero",
            "c) malloc() sets the memory to zero whereas calloc() sets allocated memory to zero",
            "d) malloc() does not set the memory to zero whereas calloc() does not set allocated memory to zero"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The difference in malloc() and calloc() is that calloc() sets the memory to zero whereas malloc()does not sets allocated memory to zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 1234,
        "Question": "Which among the given function does not return a value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) strtoul()",
            "b) strtol()",
            "c) rand()",
            "d) srand()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: void *calloc(size-t n, size-t size);\nThis function is used to allocate the requested memory and returns a pointer to it."
    },
    {
        "id": 1235,
        "Question": "Which function returns a pseudo-random integer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) srand()",
            "b) rand()",
            "c) malloc()",
            "d) alloc()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: void *calloc(size_t n, size_t size) The calloc() function allocates space for an array of n objects, each of whose size is given by size. The space is initialized to all bits zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 1236,
        "Question": " void free(void *ptr) deallocates the memory previously allocated by a call to _______  ________  or _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) malloc,getenv,abort",
            "b) calloc,malloc,exit",
            "c) calloc,malloc,realloc",
            "d) exit,getenv,abort"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The free() function causes the space to be deallocated that are pointed to by ptr, that is, made available for further allocation. No action occurs if ptr is a null pointer. Otherwise, if the argument does not match a pointer earlier returned by the calloc. malloc, or realloc function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1237,
        "Question": "The ________ function returns no value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) malloc()",
            "b) realloc()",
            "c) free()",
            "d) calloc()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The calloc() function is used to return either a null pointer or a pointer to the allocated space. The malloc() function is used to return either a null pointer or a pointer to the allocated space. The realloc() function is used to return either a null pointer or a pointer to the possibly moved allocated space. The free() function returns no value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1238,
        "Question": " What is returned by the function if the space cannot be allocated by the function malloc(), realloc() and calloc()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) value",
            "b) error",
            "c) null pointer",
            "d) no value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The pointer returned points to the lowest byte address of the allocated space. A null pointer is returned, if the space cannot be allocated."
    },
    {
        "id": 1239,
        "Question": "What is the function of the void *realloc(void *str, size-t size);?",
        "Options": [
            "a) allocates space for an array of str objects, each of whose size is size",
            "b) allocates space for an object whose size is specified by size and whose value is indeterminate",
            "c) changes the size of the object pointed to by str to the size specified by size",
            "d) causes the space pointed to by str to be deallocated, that is, made available for further allocation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: void *realloc(void *str, size-t size);\nThe realloc() function is used to change the size of the object which is pointed to by str to the size specified by size."
    },
    {
        "id": 1240,
        "Question": "Which among the  given function causes abnormal program termination ?",
        "Options": [
            "a) exit()",
            "b) abort()",
            "c) atexit()",
            "d) getenv()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: void abort (void);\nThe abort() function causes abnormal program termination to occur, and comes out directly from that place."
    },
    {
        "id": 1241,
        "Question": "Which of the given statement is true with respect to the function atexit()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The atexit() function cannot return to its caller",
            "b) The atexit() function  is used to return zero if the registration succeeds, nonzero if it fails",
            "c) The atexit() function returns no value",
            "d) The atexit() function causes abnormal program termination to occur"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The prototype of function is  int atexit (void (*func) (void) );\nThe atexit() function is used to register the function pointed to by func, to be called without arguments at normal program termination."
    },
    {
        "id": 1242,
        "Question": "Which function searches an environmenr list that are provided by the host environment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) getenv()",
            "b) system()",
            "c) srand()",
            "d) rand()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The exit() function causes normal program termination to occur. The behavior is undefined if more than one call to the exit function is executed by a program."
    },
    {
        "id": 1243,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> rc<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    rc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">system</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"time\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">exit</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) produces error",
            "b) no value is returned",
            "c) returns the time",
            "d) nothing can be said"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The getenv() searches for the environment string pointed to, by name and returns the associated value to the string.The syntax of function is char *getenv(const char *name)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1244,
        "Question": "Which of the given function is used for searching?",
        "Options": [
            "a) lsearch()",
            "b) bsearch()",
            "c) csearch()",
            "d) qsearch()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: bsearch() function is used to  search an array of objects, the initial element is pointed by base, for an element that matches the object is pointed  by key. The size of each element of the array is specified by size."
    },
    {
        "id": 1245,
        "Question": "Which function is called repeatedly by bsearch() to compare search elements against the elements in the array?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mblem()",
            "b) wctomb()",
            "c) compar()",
            "d) labs()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: void *bsearch(const void *key, const void *base, size_t nitems, size_t size, int (*compar)(const void *, const void *))\nThe comparison function pointed to by compar() is called with two arguments that point to the key object to be searched and to an array element, in that order. The function shall return a < 0, = 0, or > 0 if the key object is considered, respectively, to be less than, to match, or to be greater than the array element."
    },
    {
        "id": 1246,
        "Question": "The _______ function sorts an array of objects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bsort()",
            "b) hsort()",
            "c) ssort()",
            "d) qsort()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: void qsort(void *base, size_t nmemb, size_t size, int (*compar)(const void *, const void*))\nThe qsort() function is used to sort an array of nmemb objects, the initial element of array is pointed to by base. The size of each object in array is specified by size. The contents of the array are sorted into ascending order according to a comparison function pointed to by compar."
    },
    {
        "id": 1247,
        "Question": "Choose the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bsearch() returns no value to the function",
            "b) getenv() returns no value to the function",
            "c) qsort() returns no value to the function",
            "d) realloc() returns no value to the function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The qsort() function does not return any value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1248,
        "Question": "Which statement is true regarding abs() and labs()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The abs() function is similar to the labs() function, except that the argument and the returned value each of them have type long int",
            "b) The abs() function is not similar to the labs() function, except that the argument and the returned value in both functions have type long int",
            "c) The abs() function is similar to the labs() function, except that the argument and the returned value each have type short int",
            "d) The abs() function is not similar to the labs() function, except that the argument and the returned value in both function have type short int"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: long int labs(long int i);\nThe abs() function is similar to the labs() function, except that the returned value and argument each are of type long int."
    },
    {
        "id": 1249,
        "Question": "The abs() function computes the absolute value __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) a floating number",
            "b) an integer number",
            "c) a double number",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: int abs (int i);\nThe abs() function is used to compute the absolute value of an integer i. If the result cannot be represented, the behavior is undefined."
    },
    {
        "id": 1250,
        "Question": "Which function will return the quotient and remainder on division of numerator with denominator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) div()",
            "b) div_t()",
            "c) ldiv_t()",
            "d) labs()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: div_t div(int num, int den);\nThe div () function is used to compute the quotient and remainder of the division of the numerator num by the denominator den.div_t is the structure which contains a quotient member and a remainder member."
    },
    {
        "id": 1251,
        "Question": "What members do the structure returned by function div() contains?",
        "Options": [
            "a) int quot and int rem",
            "b) float quot and float rem",
            "c) double quot and double rem",
            "d) no members are returned by div()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A structure of type div_t is returned by the function div(), contains both the quotient and the remainder. The structure  contains two members,\n int quot; /* quotient */\nint rem; /* remainder */ "
    },
    {
        "id": 1252,
        "Question": "Which of the given structure is returned by the function ldiv()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) div_t",
            "b) ldiv_t",
            "c) div_i",
            "d) ldiv_i"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ldiv_t is  the structure returned by the function div(). ldiv() function is similar to the function div() except that the argument and the returned value is of type long int."
    },
    {
        "id": 1253,
        "Question": "Select the multibyte character function defined under the header file stdlib.h.",
        "Options": [
            "a) wctomb()",
            "b) mblen()",
            "c) mbtowc()",
            "d) all of the mentioned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: wctomb(), mblen() and mbtowc() are multibyte character function defined under the header file stdlib.h. The LC_CTYPE category of the current locale affects the behaviour of these function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1254,
        "Question": "The number of bytes contained in the multibyte character pointed to by a character is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) getenv()",
            "b) bsearch()",
            "c) mblen()",
            "d) qsort()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: int mblen(const char *s, size-t n);\nIf s is not a null pointer, the mblen() function is used to determine the number of bytes contained in the multibyte character pointed to by s."
    },
    {
        "id": 1255,
        "Question": "The pointer used in the mblen() function points to the _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) first byte of multibyte character",
            "b) last byte of multibyte character",
            "c) middle byte of multibyte character",
            "d) no pointer is used in mblen function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The prototype of the functon mblen() is int mblen(const char *s,size_t n); The pointer ‘s’ points to the first byte of the multibyte character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1256,
        "Question": "What is the name of the function that is used to convert multibyte character to wide character?",
        "Options": [
            "a) mblen()",
            "b) mbtowc()",
            "c) mbstowcs()",
            "d) wcstombs()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: mbtowc() function is used to convert the multibyte character to wide character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1257,
        "Question": "Which function converts the wide-character string to a multibyte string?",
        "Options": [
            "a) wcstombs()",
            "b) mbstowcs()",
            "c) mbtowc()",
            "d) mblen()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The C library function size_t wcstombs(char *ptr, const wchar_t *ws, size_t n)  is used to convert the wide-character string was to a multibyte string starting at ptr. At most n bytes are written to ptr."
    },
    {
        "id": 1258,
        "Question": "The C library function _____________function converts the wide character to its multibyte representation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) mblen()",
            "b) mbtowc()",
            "c) wcstombs()",
            "d) wctomb()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: wctomb() is a C Library function which converts the wide character into its multibyte representation. It is stored at the beginning of the character array pointed to by the respective pointer."
    },
    {
        "id": 1259,
        "Question": "7. What will the given C code do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt; </span>\n_Mbsave_Mbxlen<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>mblen<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw4\">size_t</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">return</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>_Mbtowc<span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL s<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">,&amp;</span>_Mbxlen<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) determine length of next multibyte code",
            "b) determine next multibyte code",
            "c) translate multibyte string to wide char string",
            "d) translate wide character to multibyte string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: mbstowcs() function returns the number of array elements that are modified. It does not return a terminating zero code if any. The mbstowcs() function is used to convert a sequence of multibyte characters that begins in the initial shift state from the array pointed to by, into a sequence of corresponding codes."
    },
    {
        "id": 1260,
        "Question": "8. What is the purpose of the given C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt; </span>\n_Mbsave _Mbxtowc <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">{</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>  \n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>mbtowc<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">wchar_t</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>pwc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">size_t</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span>Mbtowc <span class=\"br0\">(</span>pwc<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> s<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">&amp;-</span>Mbxtowc<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) determine length of next multibyte code",
            "b) translates multibyte character to wide character",
            "c) translate multibyte string to wide char string",
            "d) translate wide character to multibyte string"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: mblen() function is used to return the length of a multi-byte character pointed to, by the argument s. The data objects _Mbxlen and _Mbxtowc both have names with external linkage."
    },
    {
        "id": 1261,
        "Question": "9. What is “a” in the given C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">size_t</span> wcstombs<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">const</span> <span class=\"kw4\">wchar_t</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">size_t</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) “a” is wide character string to be converted",
            "b) “a” is pointer to an array of char elements",
            "c) “a” is pointer to the first byte of a multi-byte character",
            "d) “a” C multibyte character string to be interpreted"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: int mbtowc(whcar_t *pwc, const char *a, size_t n)\nThe given function is used to convert a multibyte sequence to a wide character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1262,
        "Question": "3. What will the following C code do on compilation?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> com<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">50</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>  \n   <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span> com<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"dir\"</span> <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n   <span class=\"kw3\">system</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>com<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) lists down all the files and directories in the current directory under windows machine",
            "c) terminates the calling process immediately",
            "d) calls specified function and terminates it at the end of the program"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: int atexit(void (*func)(void)) calls the specified function func when the program terminates. we can register termination function anywhere in the program, but it will be called at the time of the program termination."
    },
    {
        "id": 1263,
        "Question": "Initial seed is ________ for the function srand(unsigned int seed).",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 00",
            "d) 01"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: int system(const char *command) function is used to pass the command name or the program name specified by command to the host environment to be executed by the command processor and returns after the command has been completed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1264,
        "Question": "Which statement is true with respect to RAND_MAX?",
        "Options": [
            "a) specifies value for status argument to exit indicating failure",
            "b) specifies value for status argument to exit indicating success",
            "c) specifies maximum value returned by rand()",
            "d) specifies maximum value returned by srand()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: div_t div(int n, int d) used to divide n (numerator) by d (denominator). div_t is a structure defined in <cstdlib>,which has two members\nint quot;\nin rem;"
    },
    {
        "id": 1265,
        "Question": "Which of the given function differs from the statement’errno is not neccessarily set on conversion error’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) atof()",
            "b) atoi()",
            "c) atol()",
            "d) strtod()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: void srand(unsigned int seed);\nThis function returns a new sequence of pseudo-random numbers using the specified seed.Initial seed is 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 1266,
        "Question": "void free(void *p) performs which of the following functions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) returns pointer to allocated space for existing contents of p",
            "b) de-allocates space to which p points",
            "c) to abnormally terminate the program",
            "d) no such function defined in stdlib.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: RAND_MAX specifies maximum value that has to returned by the function rand().\nrand() function returns a pseudo-random number in the range 0 to RAND_MAX."
    },
    {
        "id": 1267,
        "Question": "Which of the given option is declared under the header file stdlib.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SEEK_CUR",
            "b) SEEK_END",
            "c) CLOCKS_PER_SEC",
            "d) EXIT_SUCCESS"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  The function atoi() and atol() are similar to strtol(), atof() is similar to strtod() except that errono is not necessarily set on conversion error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1268,
        "Question": "The header file assert.h of the C Standard Library defines ________ macro.",
        "Options": [
            "a) stderr",
            "b) stdarg",
            "c) setjmp",
            "d) assert"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The header file assert.h of the C Standard Library defines a macro called assert is used to verify assumptions made by the program and print a diagnostic message if this assumption is false."
    },
    {
        "id": 1269,
        "Question": "What is the name of the macro that is referred by assert macro defined in assert .h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) STDARG",
            "b) SETJMP",
            "c) NDEBUG",
            "d) STDERR"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The header file <assert. h> defines the assert macro and refers to another macro, NDEBUG which is not defined by <assert.h>."
    },
    {
        "id": 1270,
        "Question": "The assert shall be implemented as a ______ not as an actual ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) function, macro",
            "b) macro, function",
            "c) header, macro",
            "d) macro, header"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If NDEBUG is defined as a macro name at the point in the source file where  is included, then the assert macro is defined as #define assert(ignore) ((void)0) ."
    },
    {
        "id": 1271,
        "Question": "The assert macro returns__________value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) integer",
            "b) float",
            "c) double",
            "d) no"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: assert shall be implemented as a macro and not a function, which is used to add diagnostics information in your C program. The behavior is undefined if the macro definition is suppressed to access an actual function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1272,
        "Question": "The macro void assert(int expression) allows the diagnostic information to be written in which of the following files?",
        "Options": [
            "a) standard error file",
            "b) output file",
            "c) string file",
            "d) character file"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: No value is returned by the macro assert."
    },
    {
        "id": 1273,
        "Question": "Which is the correct declaration of macro assert?",
        "Options": [
            "a) void assert(int expression);",
            "b) void assert(float expression);",
            "c) void assert(double expression);",
            "d) void assert( expression);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macro assert prints diagnostic information on the standard error file(stderr). The assert macro writes the information about the particular call that failed (including the text of the argument, name of the source file and the source line number) on the standard error file in an implementation-defined format."
    },
    {
        "id": 1274,
        "Question": "void assert(int expression) when the expression is evaluated to true?",
        "Options": [
            "a) assert returns integer value",
            "b) assert displays error message",
            "c) assert returns nothing",
            "d) assert displays pattern"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The right declaration of the macro assert defined under the header file assert.h is void assert(int expression), expression can be any variable."
    },
    {
        "id": 1275,
        "Question": "Which function is called by macro assert to terminate the execution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) exit()",
            "b) atexit()",
            "c) abort()",
            "d) no function called"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When the expression in the macro void assert(int expression) is zero then the macro displays error message on stderr."
    },
    {
        "id": 1276,
        "Options": [
            "1. The following message is displayed in stderr.",
            "Assertion failed: expression, file filenum, line nmn",
            "a) true",
            "b) false"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The message written might be of the form\nAssertion failed: expression, file filename, line nmn\nThis message is displayed on stderr only when the expression in the statement void assert(int expression) is zero.nmn is the line number."
    },
    {
        "id": 1277,
        "Question": "The source filename and line number come from the preprocessor macros ________ and ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) _ _FILE_ _ and _ _LINE_ _",
            "b) _ _NAME_ _ and _ _NUMBER_ _",
            "c) _ _FILENAME_ _ and _ _NMN_ _",
            "d) _ _FILE_ _ and _ _NUM_ _"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The source filename and line number come from the preprocessor macros\n_ _FILE_ _ and _ _LINE_ _. Filename and line number are displayed in the error message when the expression of the assert is zero. It is displayed as\nAssertion failed: expression, file filename, line nmn."
    },
    {
        "id": 1278,
        "Question": "The function abort() is defined in which of the following header file?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdio.h",
            "b) stdarg.h",
            "c) stdlib.h",
            "d) assert.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: abort() function is declared inside the header file stdlib.h .This function is used to terminate the program abnormally."
    },
    {
        "id": 1279,
        "Question": "6. Which line from the given code is the passive form?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#undef assert </span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#ifdef NDEBUG </span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define assert (test) ( (void) 0) </span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#else </span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define assert (test)  </span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#endif</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) #define assert(test)",
            "b) #define assert(test) ((void)0)",
            "c) #ifdef NDEBUG",
            "d) #undef assert"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: you can turn assertions on and off at various places throughout a source file, so to turn assertions on, you write: \n#undef NDEBUG \n#include  \n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1280,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;assert. h&gt; </span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio . h&gt;</span>\n <span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt; </span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span>Assert <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>mesg<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">fputs</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>mesg<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stderr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n   <span class=\"kw3\">fputs</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\" -- assertion failed<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span> <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> stderr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n   <span class=\"kw3\">abort</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) prints only assertion message",
            "b) program is just aborted",
            "c) prints assertion message and aborts",
            "d) no action takes place"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: you can turn assertions on and off at various places throughout a source file, so to turn assertions off, you write: \n#define NDEBUG \n#include   \n"
    },
    {
        "id": 1281,
        "Question": "Which macro can be used to detect and report exceptional conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) extern",
            "b) edom",
            "c) assert",
            "d) lbdl_min 1e-37"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the given code, the line #define assert (test)((void)0) is in the pasive form."
    },
    {
        "id": 1282,
        "Question": "How many macros are defined in the header file stdarg.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) one",
            "b) two",
            "c) three",
            "d) four"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The header file stdarg.h has three macros defined in it."
    },
    {
        "id": 1283,
        "Question": "The header file stdarg.h defines a variable type ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) va_list",
            "b) v_list",
            "c) size_t",
            "d) var_list"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The variable type declared under the header file stdarg.h is va_list. This holds information required by three macros."
    },
    {
        "id": 1284,
        "Question": "The three macros defined by stdarg.h is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) start(), arg() and end()",
            "b) var_start(), var_arg() and var_end()",
            "c) va_start(), va_arg() and va_end()",
            "d) v_start(), v_arg() and v_end()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The header file stdarg.h has three macros defined in it. They are va_start(), va_arg() and va_end(). va_list  is a variable type that holds information needed by the three macros."
    },
    {
        "id": 1285,
        "Question": "If access to the varying arguments is desired then the called function shall declare ________ having type va_list.",
        "Options": [
            "a) class",
            "b) object",
            "c) function",
            "d) variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: An object of type va_list has to be created in order to access the varying arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 1286,
        "Question": "Which  macro retrieves the next argument in the parameter list of the function with type type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) type va_arg(va_list ap, type)",
            "b) type var_arg(va_list ap, type)",
            "c) type v_arg(va_list ap, type)",
            "d) type val_arg(va_list ap, type)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: type va_arg(va_list ap,type)\nThis macro is used to retrieve the next argument in the parameter list of the function with type type."
    },
    {
        "id": 1287,
        "Question": "The _______ macro shall be invoked before any access to the unnamed arguments.",
        "Options": [
            "a) va_arg",
            "b) va_end",
            "c) va_list",
            "d) va_start"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: va_start macro shall be invoked before any access to the unnamed arguments.void va-start (va-list ap, p); The va-start macro initializes ap for subsequent use by va-arg and va-end."
    },
    {
        "id": 1288,
        "Question": "______ macro must be called before using ______ and ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) va_arg, va_end and va_start",
            "b) va_start, va_end and va_arg",
            "c) va_end, va_arg and va_start",
            "d) v_arg, v_end and v_start"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: va_start macro must be called before using macros va_end and va_arg.\nThe macro void va_start(va_list p, last_arg) initializes p variable to be used with the va_arg and va_end macros."
    },
    {
        "id": 1289,
        "Question": "The C library macro type _________ retrieves the next argument in the parameter list of the function with type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) va_end",
            "b) va_arg",
            "c) va_start",
            "d) no macros"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: va_arg is the C library macro defined under stdarg.h which retrieves the next argument in the parameter list of the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1290,
        "Question": "9. What is the role of the given C function?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"kw3\">va_end</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>va_list ap<span class=\"br0\">)</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) allows a function with variable arguments which used the va_start macro to return",
            "b) retrieves the next argument in the parameter list",
            "c) initializes ap variable to be used with the va_arg and va_start macros",
            "d) returns the next additional argument as an expression"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: void va_end(va_list ap) defined under the header file stdarg allows a function with variable arguments which used the va_start macro to return.\nThe result is undefined if va_end is not called before returning from the function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1291,
        "Question": "Which header file should be included if a function has to be defined such that it can accept variable number of arguments?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdlib.h",
            "b) stdarg.h",
            "c) assert.h",
            "d) setjmp.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: stdarg.h is the header file which should be included if a function has to be defined such that it can accept variable number of arguments."
    },
    {
        "id": 1292,
        "Question": "Which header file is used to define data formats and currency symbols?",
        "Options": [
            "a) setjmp.h",
            "b) locale.h",
            "c) stdarg.h",
            "d) assert.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: locale. h is the header file which defines the location specific settings, such as data formats and currency location."
    },
    {
        "id": 1293,
        "Question": "Which among the given macros is defined in the header file locale.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SCHAR_MAX",
            "b) FLT_RADIX 2",
            "c) EDOM",
            "d) LC_CTYPE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: LC_CTYPE is the macro defined under header file locale.h. This macro affects all character functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 1294,
        "Question": "Which macro sets everything defined under locale. h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LC_ALL",
            "b) LC_COLLATE",
            "c) LC_SET",
            "d) LC_TIME"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LC_ALL is the macro which sets everything. It is defined under header file locale.h. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1295,
        "Question": "Select the function that reads or sets location dependent information.",
        "Options": [
            "a) longjmp()",
            "b) setlocale()",
            "c) assert()",
            "d) toupper()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: setlocale()  function reads or sets location dependent information.\nThe function declaration is as follows:\nchar *setlocale(int category, const char loc). "
    },
    {
        "id": 1296,
        "Question": "Select the correct statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LC_MONETARY affects the monetary information",
            "b) LC_MONETARY does not affect the monetary information",
            "c) LC_ALL does not set everything",
            "d) LC_CTYPE affects only one character functions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LC_MONETARY is the macro defined under header file locale.h which affects the monetary information provided by localeconv function. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1297,
        "Question": "Which macro is used in the setlocale() function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LC_SET",
            "b) FLT_RADIX 2",
            "c) LC_MESSAGES",
            "d) SHRT_MAX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: LC_MESSAGES in the function char *setlocale(char category, const char loc) is used for system responses. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1298,
        "Question": "Which macro affects the strftime() function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) LC_TIME",
            "b) LC_SEC",
            "c) LC_MIN",
            "d) LC_SET"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LC_COLLATE is the macro defined under header file locale.h. It affects strcoll() and strxfrm() functions. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1299,
        "Question": "Select the macro that affects the information provided by localeconv function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) LC_ALL",
            "b) LC_COLLATE",
            "c) LC_NUMERIC",
            "d) LC_CTYPE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: LC_TIME is the macro defined under locale. h which affects the strftime() function. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1300,
        "Question": "What is returned by the function localeconv()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) current location value",
            "b) past location value",
            "c) pointer to the last location",
            "d) pointer to the current location"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: LC_NUMERIC is the macro defined under the header file locale.h which affects decimal point formatting and informations provided by localeconv function. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1301,
        "Question": "Which of the following header file defines one function longjmp(), and one variable type jmp_buf?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdarg.h",
            "b) locale.h",
            "c) setjmp.h",
            "d) stdlib.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: setjmp.h header file defines the macro setjmp(), one function longjmp(), and one variable type jmp_buf."
    },
    {
        "id": 1302,
        "Question": "Which of the given options is an array type used for holding information?",
        "Options": [
            "a) longjmp",
            "b) setjmp",
            "c) jmp_buf",
            "d) no such variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: jmp_buf is an array type used for holding information of macro setjmp() and function longjmp().This is a variable type defined under the header file setjmp.h."
    },
    {
        "id": 1303,
        "Question": "Which macro saves the current environment into the variable environment for later use by the function longjmp().",
        "Options": [
            "a) setjmp",
            "b) longjmp",
            "c) jmp",
            "d) set_jmp"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The setjmp() macro saves its calling environment in its jmp-buf argument to be used later by the longjmp() function. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1304,
        "Question": "If setjmp() macro returns directly from the macro invocation, it______",
        "Options": [
            "a) returns zero",
            "b) returns non-zero",
            "c) produces error",
            "d) nothing can be said"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The setjmp() macro returns zero if the return is from a direct invocation."
    },
    {
        "id": 1305,
        "Question": "Select the correct declaration of setjmp().",
        "Options": [
            "a) int setjmp(jmp_buf environment)",
            "b) int setjmp(long_jmp environment)",
            "c) int setjmp(jmp_buf )",
            "d) int setjmp(long_jmp)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The setjmp() macro returns a nonzero value, if the return is from a call to the longjmp() function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1306,
        "Question": "How many times can the macro setjmp() return?",
        "Options": [
            "a) one time",
            "b) two times",
            "c) three times",
            "d) many times"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Declaration of the macro setjmp() is int setjmp(jmp_buf environment). ’environment’ is a the object of type jmp_buf."
    },
    {
        "id": 1307,
        "Question": "Which function restores the environment saved by the most recent invocation of the setjmp() macro in the same invocation of the program?",
        "Options": [
            "a) jmp_buf",
            "b) longjmp",
            "c) jmpbuf",
            "d) long_jmp"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: setjmp() macro returns twice. First time, setjmp() returns zero on its direct invocation. Second time macro returns when longjmp is called with the information written to the environment; now, it returns the value passed to longjmp as second argument."
    },
    {
        "id": 1308,
        "Question": "Choose the right declaration of longjmp() function.",
        "Options": [
            "a) void longjmp(jmp_buf environment, int value)",
            "b) void longjmp(setjmp environment, int value)",
            "c) void longjmp(int value, jmp_buf environment)",
            "d) void longjmp(int value, setjmp environment)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The only function defined under the header file setjmp.h is longjmp().LONGJMP() resets the registers to the values saved in an environment."
    },
    {
        "id": 1309,
        "Question": "The header file setjmp.h is used to __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) set location specific information",
            "b) control low-level calls and returns to and from functions",
            "c) handle signals reported during a program’s execution",
            "d) manipulate strings (character arrays)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The header file setjmp.h is used to control low-level calls and returns to and from functions."
    },
    {
        "id": 1310,
        "Question": "The void longjmp( jmp-buf env, int val) function causes setjmp() macro to return _______ value; if val is 0.",
        "Options": [
            "a) zero",
            "b) one",
            "c) null",
            "d) no return"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The longjmp() function cannot cause the setjmp() to return value zero,if the variable val is zero. It always return one when the value of val is 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 1311,
        "Question": "Which is the true statement with respect to the function longjmp()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) the function where setjmp() was called has terminated, then the results are undefined",
            "b) the function where setjmp() was called has terminated, then the results are defined",
            "c) the function where jmp_buf was called has terminated, then the results are undefined",
            "d) the function where jmp_buf was called has terminated, then the results are defined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The longjmp() function restores the environment saved by the most recent invocation of the set jmp macro in the same invocation of the program, with the corresponding jmp buf argument. The behavior is undefined, if there has been no such invocation, or if the function containing the invocation of the setjmp() macro has terminated execution in the interim."
    },
    {
        "id": 1312,
        "Question": "Which of the given statement is not true with respect to void longjmp( jmp-buf env, int val)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The variable value cannot be zero",
            "b) env is the object containing information to restore the environment at the jmp_buf’s calling point",
            "c) This function does not return any value",
            "d) This function restores the environment saved by the most recent call to setjmp() macro"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the function void longjmp( jmp-buf env, int val), env is the object containing information to restore the environment at the setjmp’s calling point."
    },
    {
        "id": 1313,
        "Question": "What is the function of the given longjump(jmp_buf buf, i)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) go back to place buf is pointing to and return i",
            "b) go back to place buf is pointing to and return 0",
            "c) uses buf to remember current position and returns 0",
            "d) uses buf to remember current position and returns i"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the given function longjmp(jmp_buf buf,i), it goes back to place buf is pointing to and return i.setjmp(jmp_buf  buf) uses buf to remember current position to and return 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 1314,
        "Question": "How many times does the function longjmp() returns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) once",
            "b) twice",
            "c) thrice",
            "d) never"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: longjmp() function defined under setjmp.h header file does not return any value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1315,
        "Question": "A less common use of setjmp.h is to create syntax similar to ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) errno",
            "b) variable arguments",
            "c) coroutines",
            "d) retval"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: setjmp.h is sometime is used to create syntax similar to coroutines. Coroutines are computer program components."
    },
    {
        "id": 1316,
        "Question": "8. What will the following C statement do?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt; setjmp.h &gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"kw3\">setjmp</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>jmp_buf env<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) save the current state of the registers into env",
            "b) resets the registers to the values saved in env",
            "c) provides a definition for env structure",
            "d) accept variable(env) argument lists to be written"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The given statement is used to save the current state of the registers into env. The state of the program is dependent on the contents of its memory(code, stack, globals and heap) and the contents of its registers."
    },
    {
        "id": 1317,
        "Question": "What are the contents of the register?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sp, fp only",
            "b) sp only",
            "c) fp, pc only",
            "d) sp, fp, pc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The contents of the registers includes sp, fp and cp. sp, fp and pc stands for stack pointer, frame pointer, and program counter."
    },
    {
        "id": 1318,
        "Question": "Select the right statement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) synchronous signal occurs because of the action that your program takes",
            "b) synchronous signal occurs because of action outside your program",
            "c) asynchronous signal occurs because of the action that your program takes",
            "d) division by zero is asynchronous"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Synchronous signal occurs because of the actions that your program takes."
    },
    {
        "id": 1319,
        "Question": "What does raise functions declared in signal.h do?",
        "Options": [
            "a) reports a synchronous signal",
            "b) let’s you specify handling of signals",
            "c) reports a asynchronous signal",
            "d) doesn’t let you specify handling of signals"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function raise defined under the header file signal. h reports a synchronous signal."
    },
    {
        "id": 1320,
        "Question": "What is the type declared by the header file signal.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) sig_atomic_t",
            "b) sig_signal_t",
            "c) sig_signal_h",
            "d) sig_stomic_h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The only type declared in signal.h is sig_atomic_h.\nThis is of int type and used as a variable in signal handling."
    },
    {
        "id": 1321,
        "Question": "Which among the given header file is used to handle different signals reported during program execution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdarg.h",
            "b) assert.h",
            "c) signal.h",
            "d) setjmp.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: signal.h is the header file that defines one type and two functions and many macros to handle different signals reported during the execution of the program. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1322,
        "Question": "Select the macro that abnormally terminates the program.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SIGILL",
            "b) SIGTERM",
            "c) SIGABRT",
            "d) SIGFPE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer:  c\nExplanation: SIGABRT is the macro defined under the header file signal.h which terminates the program abruptly."
    },
    {
        "id": 1323,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the correct description of the macro SIGFPE?",
        "Options": [
            "a) erroneous arithmetic operation such as zero divide",
            "b) invalid access to storage",
            "c) termination request sent to the program",
            "d) receipt of the interactive attention signal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SIGFPE is the macro defined under the header file signal.h which is an erroneous arithmetic operation such as zero divide, or operation resulting in overflow. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1324,
        "Question": "_________ gives receipt of an interactive attention signals.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SIGILL",
            "b) SIGTERM",
            "c) SIGINT",
            "d) SIGFPE"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: SIGINT gives receipt of an interactive attention signals. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1325,
        "Question": "The sig argument specifies the signal, which may be any signal except _______ and _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) SIG_DFL, SIG_IGN",
            "b) SIGKILL, SIGSTOP",
            "c) SIG_KILL, SIG_STOP",
            "d) SIGCHLD, SIG_IGN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The sigset() function is used to modify signal dispositions. The sig argument specifies the signal, it can be any signal except SIGKILL and SIGSTOP. "
    },
    {
        "id": 1326,
        "Question": "void (*signal(int sig, void (*func)(int)))(int);If the value of func is SIG_IGN then _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) the signal will be ignored",
            "b) default handling for that signal will occur",
            "c) The signal() function will fail to execute",
            "d) the signal will be ignored"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  SIG_IGN is one of the ways in signal() function in which receipt of the signal number sig is subsequently handled. The signal will be ignored if the value of func is SIG_IGN."
    },
    {
        "id": 1327,
        "Question": "In the c library function void (*signal(int sig, void (*func)(int)))(int), which statement is true with respect to func?",
        "Options": [
            "a) func is a pointer to the function",
            "b) func is pointer to sig",
            "c) func is a static variable",
            "d) func is a pointer that points to all type of data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The declaration of the function signal() is given by\nvoid (*signal(int sig, void (*func)(int)))(int). In this ‘func’ is a pointer to the function defined by the programmer or one of the following predefined functions:\nSIG_DFL and SIG_IGN."
    },
    {
        "id": 1328,
        "Question": "size_t is of ______________ type.",
        "Options": [
            "a) signed integer",
            "b) signed character",
            "c) unsigned integer",
            "d) unsigned character"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are some types and macros which are defined under various other header files, in addition to being defined under stddef.h. For example, the type size_t is defined under stdio.h, stdlib.h, string.h etc in addition to being defined under stddef.h."
    },
    {
        "id": 1329,
        "Question": "Which of the following returns a signed integer type on finding the difference between two pointers to elements in the same array?",
        "Options": [
            "a) __cptrdiff__",
            "b) cptrdiff_t",
            "c) __ptrdiff__",
            "d) ptrdiff_t"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: size_t, defined under stddeh, is of the type unsigned integer. It is returned by the sizeof() operator."
    },
    {
        "id": 1330,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stddef.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> num<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p1<span class=\"sy0\">=&amp;</span>num<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">14</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p2<span class=\"sy0\">=&amp;</span>num<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">19</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    ptrdiff_t a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>p2<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) -5",
            "c) error",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ptrdiff_t is used for pointer arithmetic and array indexing. Only pointers to elements of the same array may be subtracted from each other."
    },
    {
        "id": 1331,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stddef.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> num<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">15</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p1<span class=\"sy0\">=&amp;</span>num<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p2<span class=\"sy0\">=&amp;</span>num<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"st0\">'A'</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    ptrdiff_t d <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> p1<span class=\"sy0\">-</span>p2<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15",
            "b) -32",
            "c) 32",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The type ptrdiff_t, defined under the file stddef is used to find the difference between two pointers pointing to elements of the same array. Hence the output of the above code is -5."
    },
    {
        "id": 1332,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not defined under the header file stddef.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) size_t",
            "b) ptrdiff_t",
            "c) exp_t",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ASCII value ‘a’ is 97 and that of ‘A’ is 65. Their difference is equal to 32. Hence the output of the code shown above is 32."
    },
    {
        "id": 1333,
        "Question": "7. Point out the error (if any) in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span> p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> S <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>s <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>f<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">double</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">15</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>ptr <span class=\"sy0\">==</span> NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span> <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Out of memory\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">free</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error in the statement: void(*f)(int, double) = NULL;",
            "b) Error in the statement: char *ptr = malloc(15);",
            "c) Error in the statement: struct S*s = NULL;",
            "d) No error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: size_t, ptrdiff_t and NULL are defined under the file stddef.h. There is no type called exp_t c language."
    },
    {
        "id": 1334,
        "Question": "A type whose alignment requirement is at least as large as that of every data type ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) max_align_t",
            "b) ptrdiff_t",
            "c) size_t",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above does not result in an error. However, since ptr is not equal to NULL, it does not print anything."
    },
    {
        "id": 1335,
        "Question": "The macro offset expands to a constant of type __________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) size_t",
            "b) print_t",
            "c) ptrdiff_t",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The alignment of the type max_align_t is at least as great as that supported by the compiler in all contexts. An extended alignment is greater than the alignment of max_align_t type. A type having an extended alignment requirement is also called over aligned."
    },
    {
        "id": 1336,
        "Question": "When we use multiple alignas specifiers in the same declaration, the ____________ one is used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) first",
            "b) strictest",
            "c) last",
            "d) middle"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: offsetof expands to a constant of type size_t. It retuns the offset of the field member from the start to of the structure type."
    },
    {
        "id": 1337,
        "Question": "Which of the following library functions returns the time in UTC (Greenwich mean time) format?",
        "Options": [
            "a) localtime()",
            "b) gettime()",
            "c) gmtime()",
            "d) settime()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The library function gmtime() returns the time in UTC format. To find the current time, we use the function localtime()."
    },
    {
        "id": 1338,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code? (By date we mean: date, month and year)<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    time_t ct<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw3\">ctime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) only current date",
            "b) only current date and current time",
            "c) current date, current time and the day of the week",
            "d) only current time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The code shown above will print the current date, current time and the day of the week as output."
    },
    {
        "id": 1339,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code if the current system date is 6/22/2017?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    time_t ct<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>mt<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>mt<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span> tm_mon<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8",
            "b) 7",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the given date is 22nd of June, 2017. Since June is the sixth month of the year, the output will be 5. (0-Jan, 1-Feb, 2-March, 4-April, 5-May, 6-June……..)"
    },
    {
        "id": 1340,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code if the current system date is 6/22/2017?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">typedef</span> <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm tm<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    time_t ct<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>mt<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>mt<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span> tm_year<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 17",
            "b) 2017",
            "c) error",
            "d) 117"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is the number of the current year, counted from the year 1900. Hence, since the current year is 2017, the output will be: 2017-1900 = 117."
    },
    {
        "id": 1341,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code if the current system date is 6/22/2017?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    time_t ct<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>mt<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>mt<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span> tm_date<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 22",
            "b) 6",
            "c) 22/6",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above results in an error. This is because tm_date is not a specified function under time.h."
    },
    {
        "id": 1342,
        "Question": "The purpose of the function ctime() is that ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) it returns a string representing the local time",
            "b) it returns a void string",
            "c) it returns a string representing the time in UTC format",
            "d) it returns a string representing the time stored in a structure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The library function ctime() returns a string representation of the local time. The function asctime() returns a string representing the time stored in a structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 1343,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> n <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%.2f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span> <span class=\"sy0\">,</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) time in seconds from 1 January, 1970",
            "b) time in minutes from 1 January, 1970",
            "c) time in seconds from 1 January, 1980",
            "d) time in minutes from 1 January, 1980"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above will be the time in seconds from 1 January, 1970."
    },
    {
        "id": 1344,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code if the system date is 6/2/2017(Friday)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>gm<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    local<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>tm_wday<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 5",
            "c) error",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the given question has clearly specified that the current weekday at the time of execution of the code is Friday, the output of the code shown above is 5. (0-Sunday, 1-Mon, 2-Tue, 3-Wed, 4 – Thurs, 5-fri, 6-Sat)"
    },
    {
        "id": 1345,
        "Question": "Which of the following functions returns a pointer to a string representing the date and time stored in a structure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ctime()",
            "b) time()",
            "c) asctime()",
            "d) localtime()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The function asctime() returns a pointer to a string representing the date and time stored in a structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 1346,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code if it is executed on 2nd January, 2017 (system date)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>gm<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\t\n    local<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>tm_yday<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is 1. In the question, it is given that the current date is 2nd January, 2017. (1st Jan – 0, 2nd Jan – 1, 3rd Jan – 2)"
    },
    {
        "id": 1347,
        "Question": "Which of the following format specifiers is used to represent the name of the time zone?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %A",
            "b) %B",
            "c) %H",
            "d) %Z"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The format specifier %Z is used to specify the name of the time zone. %A- full weekday, %B- full month name, %H-hours(0-23)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1348,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code if the system time is 4:27 PM?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">strftime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%H %p %M minutes\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 16 27 minutes",
            "b) 4 27 minutes",
            "c) 16 PM 27 minutes",
            "d) 4 PM 27 minutes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: %H is a format specifier used to represent the hours (0-23) and %I specifies the hours in the format(0-12), %p is used to specify AM or PM, %M is used to specify the minutes. Hence output will be: 16 PM 27 minutes"
    },
    {
        "id": 1349,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code if the system date is 8/22/2016?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">strftime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%B\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9",
            "b) August",
            "c) Aug",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: %B is a format specifier which is used to specify the full month name. Hence the output will be August."
    },
    {
        "id": 1350,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code  if the system date is 6/2/2017 (Friday)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">strftime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%A\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Fri",
            "c) Friday",
            "d) 6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: %A specifies the full weekday. Hence the output is Friday."
    },
    {
        "id": 1351,
        "Question": "Which of the following library functions is used to read location dependent information?",
        "Options": [
            "a) localtime()",
            "b) localeconv()",
            "c) localcon()",
            "d) local()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: localeconv() is used to read the location dependent information. The function used to find the current time is localtime()."
    },
    {
        "id": 1352,
        "Question": "Which of the following functions is used to convert the date and time into a calendar format?",
        "Options": [
            "a) difftime()",
            "b) clock()",
            "c) mktime()",
            "d) ctime()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The function mktime() is used to convert the date and time into a calendar format. The function difftime() is used to find the difference between two specified timings, the function clock() is used to return the number of ticks."
    },
    {
        "id": 1353,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t tc<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t.<span class=\"me1\">tm_year</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">2017</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1900</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t.<span class=\"me1\">tm_mday</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">25</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t.<span class=\"me1\">tm_mon</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t.<span class=\"me1\">tm_hour</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t.<span class=\"me1\">tm_min</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">30</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t.<span class=\"me1\">tm_sec</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t.<span class=\"me1\">tm_isdst</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    tc<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">mktime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw3\">ctime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>tc<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sun Jun 25 01:30:00 2017",
            "b) Sun June 25 1:30 2017",
            "c) Sun Jun 25 1:30 117",
            "d) Sun June 25 1:30:00 117"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The function mktime() converts the time and date into a calendar format. Hence the output of the code shown above is: Sun Jun 25 1:30:00 2017."
    },
    {
        "id": 1354,
        "Question": "The value of tm_isdst is ____ when DST( Daylight Savings Time) is in effect, ______ when DST is not in effect and ______ when the DST status is unknown.",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1, 1, 0",
            "b) 1, 0, -1",
            "c) 0, 1, -1",
            "d) 1, -1, 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The value of tm_isdst is 1 when Daylight Savings Time is in effect, 0 when DSP is not in the effect and -1 when DST status is not known."
    },
    {
        "id": 1355,
        "Question": "The library function clock() returns the number of _________ elapsed since the start of the program.",
        "Options": [
            "a) minutes",
            "b) clock ticks",
            "c) milli-seconds",
            "d) micro-seconds"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The library function clock() returns the number of clock ticks elapsed since the start of the program. To get the number of seconds used by the CPU, we should divide by CLOCKS_PER_SEC."
    },
    {
        "id": 1356,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code if the name entered is “TOM” and time taken to enter this name is 2 seconds?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n\ttime_t time1<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>time2<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> get_input <span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">256</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw4\">double</span> dif_sec<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw3\">time</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>time1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Please enter the name of your pet: \"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw3\">gets</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>get_input<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw3\">time</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>time2<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\tdif_sec <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">difftime</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span>time2<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>time1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%.2f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> dif_sec <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 2.0",
            "d) 2.00"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The library function difftime() returns the difference in seconds between time1 and time 2. Since the format specifier is %.2f, the output will be 2.00."
    },
    {
        "id": 1357,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code, if the system date is 6/23/2017?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    local<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>tm_mday<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6",
            "b) 22",
            "c) 23",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: tm_mday returns the day of the month in terms of an integer (date). Hence the output of the code shown above will be 23 (since the system date is 6/23/2017)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1358,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code, if the system date is 6/24/2017?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    time_t ct<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>ct<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Junk value",
            "c) 6",
            "d) June"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output to the above code will be some junk value (not in the human readable form). This is because we have not used the ctime() to convert the date and time into a string."
    },
    {
        "id": 1359,
        "Question": "3. What is the meaning of the following C code if output is 0?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    local<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>local<span class=\"sy0\">-&gt;</span>tm_isdst<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) DST is in effect",
            "b) DST status is unknown",
            "c) DST is not in effect",
            "d) DST is corresponding with local time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Daylight Savings time is in effect when the value of tm_isdt is 1. It is not in effect when the value of tm_isdst is 0 and it’s status is unknown when the value of tm_isdst is -1."
    },
    {
        "id": 1360,
        "Question": "Which of the following format specifiers is used to specify whether the given time is in AM or PM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %P",
            "b) %I",
            "c) %X",
            "d) %p"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: %p (small letter) is used to specify whether the given time is in AM or PM. %I is used to represent the number of hours in the 12 hour clock format. %X is used to represent the standard time zone."
    },
    {
        "id": 1361,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code if the system time is 1:52 PM (Sunday)?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> tm <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>ptr<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    time_t t<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> str<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    t <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">time</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>NULL<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    ptr <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">localtime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>t<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">strftime</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%I\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ptr<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">puts</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>str<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 01",
            "c) 1",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Although the code shown above does not give the correct answer, it does not result in an error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1362,
        "Question": "Which of the following format specifiers is used to represent the hours in the 24 hour clock (0-23) format?",
        "Options": [
            "a) %I",
            "b) %H",
            "c) %i",
            "d) %h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: %I is a format specifier which is used to represent the number of hours in 12 hour clock format. Hence the output of the code shown above will be 01."
    },
    {
        "id": 1363,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;time.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw4\">double</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\td <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">difftime</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">17</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw3\">printf</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%.2f<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> d <span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n\t<span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12.00",
            "b) -12.00",
            "c) Error",
            "d) 12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: %H is a format specifier used to represent the number of hours in 24 hour clock format."
    },
    {
        "id": 1364,
        "Question": "The value returned by the library function mktime(), on failure is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) -2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The library function difftime(time1,time2) is used to find the difference between time1 and time2 such as: time1-time2. Hence the output of the code shown above will be 5-17=12.00."
    },
    {
        "id": 1365,
        "Question": "Which of the following is defined under the header file time.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) strnct()",
            "b) fabs()",
            "c) iscntrl()",
            "d) null"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The library function mktime() converts the date and time into calendar format and returns the value -1 on the failure of this action."
    },
    {
        "id": 1366,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"The minimum value of LONG = %lf<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> LONG_MIN<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -2147483648 (The minimum value of LONG)",
            "b) 0.000000",
            "c) 0",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The maximum value of a signed char is 127 and that the maximum value of an unsigned char is 255. Thus it is clear that the maximum value of a signed char is not the same as the maximum value of an unsigned char."
    },
    {
        "id": 1367,
        "Question": "The macro __________ defines the number of bits in a byte, which is equal to _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) CHAR_BIT, 4",
            "b) CHAR_BYTE, 8",
            "c) CHAR_BIT, 8",
            "d) CHAR_BYTE, 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the format specifier %lf is used, 0.000000 is given as the output. If we want the output to be the minimum value of LONG, we should use the format specifier %ld is used."
    },
    {
        "id": 1368,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%f\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>FLT_MIN<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Minimum negative value of float",
            "b) Maximum positive value of float",
            "c) Error",
            "d) Minimum positive value of float"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The macro CHAR_BIT defines the number of bits in a byte, which is equal to 8."
    },
    {
        "id": 1369,
        "Question": "The macro MB_LEN_MAX is used to find _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Maximum number of bytes in a multi-byte character",
            "b) Whether the given function is valid or not",
            "c) The maximum time taken for the execution of a particular function",
            "d) Maximum number of bits in a multi-byte character"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The macro FLT_MIN is not defined under the header file limits.h. To use any macro relate to a floating point value or a double value, we should include the header file float.h. Since this header file is not included in the code shown above, it will result in an error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1370,
        "Question": "The value of CHAR_MAX will be equal to SCHAR_MAX when _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) char represents positive value",
            "b) char represents value equal to 0",
            "c) char represents negative value",
            "d) char represents an exponential value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macro MB_LEN_MAX is defined under the header file limits.h and is used to find the maximum number of bytes in a multi-byte character."
    },
    {
        "id": 1371,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code, given that the maximum value of signed char is 127 and that of unsigned char is 255.<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define SCHAR_MAX</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>SCHAR_MAX<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 256",
            "b) Error",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 128"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The macro CHAR_MAX defines the maximum value for type char and its value is equal to SCHAR_MAX is char represents negative value, otherwise UCHAR_MAX."
    },
    {
        "id": 1372,
        "Question": "The macro which is used to find the maximum value of an unsigned integer is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) UNINT_MAX",
            "b) UNSINT_MAX",
            "c) UINT_MAX",
            "d) UNIT_MAX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above will be equal to 1. This is because we have used the macro define to define a variable known as SCHAR_MAX (assigned a value of zero). Had this line not been a part of the above code, the output would be 128."
    },
    {
        "id": 1373,
        "Question": "To find the maximum value of an object of type unsigned long long int, we use the macro _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ULINT_MAX",
            "b) ULLINT_MAX",
            "c) ULONG_MAX",
            "d) ULLONG_MAX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The macro which is used to define the maximum value on an unsigned integer is: UINT_MAX. To find the maximum value on a signed integer, we use the macro: SINT_MAX."
    },
    {
        "id": 1374,
        "Question": "Which of the following macros is defined under the header limits.h?",
        "Options": [
            "a) FLT_ROUNDS",
            "b) USHRT_MAX",
            "c) DBL_MAX",
            "d) DECIMAL_DIG"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The macro ULLONG_MAX is used to find the maximum value of unsigned long long int type. The macro ULONG_MAX is used to find the maximum value of unsigned long type."
    },
    {
        "id": 1375,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>UCHAR_MAX<span class=\"sy0\">&lt;=</span>SCHAR_MAX<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"good\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) hello",
            "c) good",
            "d) hellogood"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since UCHAR_MAX (255) is greater then SCHAR_MAX (127), the output of the code shown above will be “good”."
    },
    {
        "id": 1376,
        "Question": "Which of the following macros is not defined?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ULONG_MIN",
            "b) LONG_MIN",
            "c) ULONG_MAX",
            "d) LONG_MAX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macro ULONG_MIN is not defined whereas the macros LONG_MIN, ULONG_MAX and LONG_MAX are all defined in the header file limits.h."
    },
    {
        "id": 1377,
        "Question": "3. Given that the value of SHRT_MAX is equal to 32767 and that of SHRT_MIN is equal to -32768, What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    d<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>SHRT_MAX <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> SHRT_MIN<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) error",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SHRT_MIN is defined as –SHRT_MAX – 1, hence the output of the code shown above will be zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 1378,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    d<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>CHAR_MIN<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) -128",
            "c) error",
            "d) -1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Since the minimum value of CHAR_MIN is equal to -128, hence the output of the code shown above is -128."
    },
    {
        "id": 1379,
        "Question": "_____________ defines the minimum value for a short integer.",
        "Options": [
            "a) SHINT_MIN",
            "b) SHRT_MIN",
            "c) SINT_MIN",
            "d) SHORT_MIN"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: to define the minimum value for a short integer, we use the macro SHRT_MIN (defined under the header file limits.h)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1380,
        "Question": "The macro definition of INT_MIN is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) –INT_MAX – 1",
            "b) INT_MAX – 1",
            "c) –INT_MAX + 1",
            "d) INT_MAX + 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macro definition of INT_MIN is –INT_MAX – 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 1381,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">Maximum value of <span class=\"kw4\">int</span>  <span class=\"sy0\">=</span>  <span class=\"nu0\">1000</span>\nMaximum value of <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">5000</span>\nMaximum value of <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">327</span>\nMinimum value of <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">328</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;float.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">short</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    d<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>INT_MAX <span class=\"sy0\">+</span> FLT_MAX<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) 6000",
            "c) 327",
            "d) -328"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Since the data type in which we store the result of the expression INT_MAX +  FLT_MAX is of the type short int, the output of the code shown above will be the maximum of short int. Hence the output is 327."
    },
    {
        "id": 1382,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code if the value of UCHAR_MAX is 127?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;limits.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> d<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    d<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>CHAR_MAX<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>d<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 127",
            "c) Alphabet corresponding to the value 127",
            "d) Junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Macros such as INT_MAX, ULONG_MAX etc which are defined under the header file limits.h are not defined under any other header file."
    },
    {
        "id": 1383,
        "Question": "The minimum value of CHAR_BIT is equal to  ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above will be some junk value. This is because we have used the format specifier %c in the print statement. Had we used the format specifier %d, the output would have been 127 (maximum value of char)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1384,
        "Question": "Local variables are stored in an area called ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Heap",
            "b) Permanent storage area",
            "c) Free memory",
            "d) Stack"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Local variables are stored in an area called stack. Global variables, static variables and program instructions are stored in the permanent storage area. The memory space between these two regions is known a heap."
    },
    {
        "id": 1385,
        "Question": "Choose the statement which is incorrect with respect to dynamic memory allocation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Memory is allocated in a less structured area of memory, known as heap",
            "b) Used for unpredictable memory requirements",
            "c) Execution of the program is faster than that of static memory allocation",
            "d) Allocated memory can be changed during the run time of the program based on the requirement of the program"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Memory can be allocated or de-allocated during the run time in the heap region. Memory bindings (allocation and de-allocation) are established and destroyed during the execution of the program. Hence we can see that the size of heap does not remain same during run time. However, the size of stack remains the same."
    },
    {
        "id": 1386,
        "Question": "Which of the following header files must necessarily be included to use dynamic memory allocation functions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdlib.h",
            "b) stdio.h",
            "c) memory.h",
            "d) dos.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Execution of the program using dynamic memory allocation is slower than that using static memory allocation. This is because in dynamic memory allocation, the memory has to be allocated during run time. This slows down the execution of the program."
    },
    {
        "id": 1387,
        "Question": " The type of linked list in which the node does not contain any pointer or reference to the previous node is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Circularly singly linked list",
            "b) Singly linked list",
            "c) Circular doubly linked list",
            "d) Doubly linked list"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: stdlib.h is a header file which stands for the standard library. It consists of the declaration for dynamic memory allocation functions such as malloc(), calloc(), realloc() and free."
    },
    {
        "id": 1388,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example for non linear data type?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tree",
            "b) Array",
            "c) Linked list",
            "d) Queue"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A singly linked list is one in which each node has two fields, namely data field and pointer field. Data field stores the data and the pointer field points to the address of the next node."
    },
    {
        "id": 1389,
        "Question": "Queue data structure works on the principle of ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Last In First Out (LIF0)",
            "b) First In Last Out (FILO)",
            "c) First In First Out (FIFO)",
            "d) Last In Last Out (LILO)"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A data structure is said to be linear if its elements form a sequence or a linear list. For example array, linked list, queue, stack etc. Elements in a non linear data structure do not form a sequence. For example Trees, graphs etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 1390,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example of static memory allocation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linked list",
            "b) Stack",
            "c) Queue",
            "d) Array"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Queue is a linear data structure which works on the principle of first in first out. This means that the first element to be inserted in a queue will be the first one to be removed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1391,
        "Question": "Array is preferred over linked list for the implementation of ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Radix sort",
            "b) Insertion sort",
            "c) Binary search",
            "d) Polynomial evaluation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Array is an example of static memory allocation whereas linked list, queue and stack are examples for dynamic memory allocation."
    },
    {
        "id": 1392,
        "Question": "The advantage of using linked lists over arrays is that ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Linked list is an example of linear data structure",
            "b) Insertion and deletion of an element can be done at any position in a linked list",
            "c) Linked list can be used to store a collection of homogenous and heterogeneous data types",
            "d) The size of a linked list is fixed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When we try to implement binary search using linked list, the traversal steps per element increases in order to find the middle element. Thus, this process is slow and inefficient. This process is much faster using an array, hence it is preferable to use an array for the implementation of binary search."
    },
    {
        "id": 1393,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code if the input entered as first and second number is 5 and 6 respectively?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    p<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">calloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Enter first number<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Enter second number<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">+</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">free</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 56",
            "b) Address of the locations where the two numbers are stored",
            "c) 57",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The above code results in an error. This is because the syntax of the function calloc() is incorrect. In order to rectify this error, we must write: calloc(3,sizeof(int)); "
    },
    {
        "id": 1394,
        "Question": "Which of the following functions allocates multiple blocks of memory, each block of the same size?",
        "Options": [
            "a) malloc()",
            "b) realloc()",
            "c) calloc()",
            "d) free()"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the function malloc(), allocated space is initialized to junk values. In calloc(), each byte of allocated space is initialized to zero."
    },
    {
        "id": 1395,
        "Question": "A condition where in memory is reserved dynamically but not accessible to any of the programs is called _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Memory leak",
            "b) Dangling pointer",
            "c) Frozen memory",
            "d) Pointer leak"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: malloc() allocates a single block of memory whereas calloc() allocates multiple blocks of memory, each block with the same size."
    },
    {
        "id": 1396,
        "Question": "5. What will happens if the statement free(a) is removed in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"*a%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">free</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">200</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a%p\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">200</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Memory leak",
            "c) Dangling pointer arises",
            "d) 200 is printed as output"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If we allocate memory dynamically in a function (malloc, calloc, realloc), the allocated memory will not be de-allocated automatically when the control comes out of the function. This allocated memory cannot be accessed and hence cannot be used. This unused inaccessible memory results in a memory leak."
    },
    {
        "id": 1397,
        "Question": "The incorrect statement with respect to dangling pointers is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pointer pointing to non-existent memory location is called dangling pointer",
            "b) When a dynamically allocated pointer references the original memory after it has been freed, a dangling pointer arises",
            "c) If memory leak occurs, it is mandatory that a dangling pointer arises",
            "d) Dangling pointer may result in segmentation faults and potential security risks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The pointer ‘a’ points to the recent value 200, making the memory allocated earlier inaccessible. Hence, the memory where the value 100 is inaccessible and cannot be freed. Therefore, memory leak occurs."
    },
    {
        "id": 1398,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"kw3\">calloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"welcome\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) welcome",
            "c) memory location stored by the pointer",
            "d) junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Memory leak and dangling pointers are not inter dependent. Hence, when memory leak occurs, it is not mandatory that a dangling pointer arises"
    },
    {
        "id": 1399,
        "Question": "In the function realloc(), if the new size of the memory block is larger than the old size, then the added memory ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) is initialized to junk values",
            "b) is initialized to zero",
            "c) results in an error",
            "d) is not initialized"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There is no error in the above code. The format specifier being %s, address is not returned. Hence, welcome is the output."
    },
    {
        "id": 1400,
        "Question": "The free() function frees the memory state pointed to by a pointer and returns ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) the same pointer",
            "b) the memory address",
            "c) no value",
            "d) an integer value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The function realloc() changes the size of a particular memory block. If the new size is larger than the old size, the added memory is not initialized."
    },
    {
        "id": 1401,
        "Question": "10. The following C code is an example of __________<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;string.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,*</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    p<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    q<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"p=%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"q=%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">free</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    q<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>NULL<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">gets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">gets</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>s”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Memory leak",
            "b) Dangling pointer",
            "c) Static memory allocation",
            "d) Linked list"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The free() function frees the memory state pointed by a pointer and returns no value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1402,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code if it is executed on a 32 bit processor?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">malloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">20</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">free</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 8",
            "d) Junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The size of a pointer is 2 bytes on a 16 bit platform, 4 bytes on a 32 bit platform and 8 bytes on a 64 bit platform."
    },
    {
        "id": 1403,
        "Question": "The number of arguments taken as input which allocating memory dynamically using malloc() is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: An example of memory allocated using malloc():\n(int*)malloc(3*sizeof(int)\nIt is clear from the above example that malloc() takes only one argument as input, that is the number of bytes to be allocated."
    },
    {
        "id": 1404,
        "Question": "Suppose we have a one dimensional array, named ‘x’, which contains 10 integers.  Which of the following is the correct way to allocate memory dynamically to the array  ‘x’ using malloc()?",
        "Options": [
            "a) x=(int*)malloc(10);",
            "b) x=(int*)malloc(10,sizeof(int));",
            "c) x=malloc(int 10,sizeof(int));",
            "d) x=(int*)malloc(10*sizeof(int));"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to the syntax of malloc, the correct way to do the specified operation is: x=(int*)malloc(10*sizeof(int)); This operation can also be performed using calloc(). In that case, the method will be: x=(int*)calloc(10,sizeof(int));"
    },
    {
        "id": 1405,
        "Question": "4. What will be the error (if any) in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdlib.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;string.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>p <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"kw3\">calloc</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">strcpy</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"st0\">\"HELLO\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%s\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">free</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No error",
            "b) Error in the statement: strcpy(p,”HELLO”);",
            "c) Error in the statement: *p=(char)calloc(10);",
            "d) Error in the statement: free(p);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The syntax for dynamically allocating memory using calloc() is incorrect. Hence, this code results in an error. The correct syntax for calloc is: void*calloc(size_t n, size_t size);"
    },
    {
        "id": 1406,
        "Question": "If malloc() and calloc() are not type casted, the default return type is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) void*",
            "b) void**",
            "c) int*",
            "d) char*"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If malloc() and calloc() are not type casted, they return a pointer of the type void."
    },
    {
        "id": 1407,
        "Question": "Pick out the correct statement with respect to the heap.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Local variables are stored on the heap",
            "b) Static variables are stored on the heap",
            "c) Heap is the data structure which is used to implement recursive function calls",
            "d) Everything on the heap is anonymous"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Local variables are stored on the stack. Static variables are stored in the permanent storage area. Stack is the data structure used to implement recursive function calls. Hence, it is true that everything on heap s anonymous."
    },
    {
        "id": 1408,
        "Question": "When the pointer is NULL, then the function realloc is equivalent to the function ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) malloc",
            "b) calloc",
            "c) free",
            "d) alloc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the above code, we are reallocating memory. When the size of the array is 4, the output is 0123. When the size of the array is changed to 5, the output is 01234. Hence, the output is:\n0123\n01234"
    },
    {
        "id": 1409,
        "Question": "Garbage collector frees the programmer from worrying about ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dangling pointers",
            "b) Creating new objects",
            "c) Memory leak",
            "d) Segmentation errors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If pointer is NULL, the call to the function realloc is equal to malloc(size), for any value of size. If size is equal to zero, then the pointer is not NULL and the call is equivalent to free(pointer)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1410,
        "Question": "If the space in memory allocated by malloc is not sufficient, then an allocation fails and returns ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) NULL pointer",
            "b) Zero",
            "c) Garbage value",
            "d) The number of bytes available"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A garbage collector is a program that automatically removes unwanted data held temporarily in the memory during processing. Hence it frees the programmer from worrying about memory leaks."
    },
    {
        "id": 1411,
        "Question": "The preprocessor directive used to give additional information to the compiler, beyond which is conveyed in the language _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) #include",
            "b) #define",
            "c) #pragma",
            "d) #elif"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The preprocessor directive #pragma is used to give additional information to the compiler, other than what is conveyed in the language itself."
    },
    {
        "id": 1412,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code, if it is run on a 32 bit platform?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#pragma(1)</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> test\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> j<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"kw4\">sizeof</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">struct</span> test<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: #pragma pack(n), where n is the number of alignment in bytes. #pragma pack(1) is the directive for the compiler to pack the structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 1413,
        "Question": "In the directive, #pragma pack(n), which of the following is not a valid value of n?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Valid arguments are 1,2,4 and 8. 3 is not a valid value for n."
    },
    {
        "id": 1414,
        "Question": "Which of the following attributes is used to specify that the minimum required memory to be used to represent the types?",
        "Options": [
            "a) packed",
            "b) aligned",
            "c) unused",
            "d) deprecated"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The keyword __attribute__ allows you to specify special attributes of struct type. 6 attributes are currently defined for types: aligned, packed, transparent_union, unused, deprecated and may_alias. The attribute “packed” is used to specify that the minimum required memory to be used to represent the types."
    },
    {
        "id": 1415,
        "Question": "In the directive #pragma pack(n), if the value of ‘n’ is given to be 5, then what happens?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Warning but no error",
            "c) Executes the pragma statement",
            "d) Ignores the pragma statement and executes the program"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Valid values for n are 1,2,4 and 8. If the value of n is one that the compiler does not recognize, then it simply ignores the pragma statement without throwing any error or warning."
    },
    {
        "id": 1416,
        "Question": "The correct syntax of the attribute packed is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) __attribute__((packed));",
            "b) _attribute(packed);",
            "c) _attribute_((packed));",
            "d) __attribute__(packed);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The correct syntax of the attribute packed is: __attribute__((packed));"
    },
    {
        "id": 1417,
        "Question": "The pragma ___________________ is used to remove an identifier completely from a program.",
        "Options": [
            "a) GNU piston",
            "b) GCC poison",
            "c) GNU poison",
            "d) GCC piston"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are several pragmas defines. One such pragma is GCC poison which is used to remove an identifier."
    },
    {
        "id": 1418,
        "Question": "The function of __attribute__((packed)); can also be performed using _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) #pragma pack(1);",
            "b) #pragma pack(2);",
            "c) #pragma pack(4);",
            "d) #pragma pack(8);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: __attribute((packed)); and #pragma(1) are used to perform the same function, that is, to direct the compiler to pack the structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 1419,
        "Question": "#pragma GCC poison should be followed by a list of identifiers that are _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) even in number",
            "b) odd in number",
            "c) valid",
            "d) invalid"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: #pragma poison GCC is used to remove an identifier from a program. It should be followed by a list of identifiers which are not valid in the program, for example: scanf, printf etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 1420,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#pragma GCC poison printf</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"sanfoundry\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error is thrown",
            "b) sanfoundry is printed",
            "c) warning but no error",
            "d) yrdnoufnas is printed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The code shown above results in an error: attempt to use poisoned printf\nWhen the above program is compiled, it results in an error since #pragma was used to specify that the identifier printf should not be used in the program."
    },
    {
        "id": 1421,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a stringizing operator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) < >",
            "b) #",
            "c) %",
            "d) ##"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: # is the stringizing operator. It allows formal arguments within a macro definition to be converted to a string."
    },
    {
        "id": 1422,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define sanfoundry(s,n) #s #n</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>sanfoundry<span class=\"br0\">(</span>hello<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>world<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) sanfoundry(hello,world)",
            "b) sanfoundry",
            "c) hello,world",
            "d) helloworld"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The output to this code will be helloworld because when we use the stringizing operator, the resulting string will automatically be concatenated (combined) with any adjacent strings."
    },
    {
        "id": 1423,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define display(text) printf(#text \"@\")</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    display<span class=\"br0\">(</span>hello.<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    display<span class=\"br0\">(</span>good morning<span class=\"sy0\">!</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) [email protected] morning!",
            "b) error",
            "c) hello.good [email protected]",
            "d) [email protected] [email protected]"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Each actual argument is converted into string within the printf function. Each argument is concatenated with ‘@’, which is written as a separate string within the macro definition."
    },
    {
        "id": 1424,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define display(a) #a</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>display<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"56#7\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) “56#7”",
            "c) 56#7",
            "d) 567"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In this case, it is not necessary for the argument in the printf function to be enclosed in double quotes. However, if the argument is enclosed in double quotes, no error is thrown. The output of the code shown will be  “56#7”."
    },
    {
        "id": 1425,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define HELLO(a) #a</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>HELLO<span class=\"br0\">(</span>good        morning<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) good        morning",
            "b) goodmorning",
            "c) good morning",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above will be: good morning\nIn the resulting string, the consecutive blank spaces are replaced by a single blank space when we use the stringizing operator."
    },
    {
        "id": 1426,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define sanfoundry(x)  #x</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> marks<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"value of %s is = %d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>sanfoundry<span class=\"br0\">(</span>marks<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>marks<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) value of marks=100",
            "c) value of=100",
            "d) 100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the code shown above, the variable name(marks) is passed as an argument. By using the # operator, we can print the name of the variable as a string."
    },
    {
        "id": 1427,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define hello(c) #c</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>am<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) i,am",
            "b) iam",
            "c) i am",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The above code will result in an error. This is because we have passed to arguments to the macro hello, but it should be talking only one."
    },
    {
        "id": 1428,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define hello(c,d) #c #d</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">(</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"st0\">\"am\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) iam",
            "b) i“am”",
            "c) am",
            "d) “am”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output for the following code will be i”am”. Since 2 arguments are passed and the macro hello takes two arguments, there is no error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1429,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define F abc</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define B def</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define FB(arg) #arg</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define FB1(arg) FB(arg)</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>FB<span class=\"br0\">(</span>F B<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    FB1<span class=\"br0\">(</span>F B<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) F B",
            "b) Error",
            "c) FB",
            "d) “FB”"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The argument F B(only one space between F and B) is passed to the macro FB. This argument is converted to a string with the by the stringizing operator. Thus F B is printed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1430,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define display(text) \"$\" #text</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>display<span class=\"br0\">(</span>hello\t   world<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello world",
            "b) $helloworld",
            "c) $hello world",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is $hello world\nThe argument “hello  world” is passed to the macro text. The symbol “$” is present from before. In the resulting string, all the blank spaces are replaced by a single blank space. In addition to this, “$” is concatenated to the beginning of the resultant string."
    },
    {
        "id": 1431,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define max 100</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef max</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100",
            "b) hello",
            "c) “hello”",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above results in an error. This is because the preprocessor #endif is missing in the above code. If the identifier is defined, then the statements following #ifdef are executed till #endif is encountered."
    },
    {
        "id": 1432,
        "Question": "_______________ is the preprocessor directive which is used to end the scope of #ifdef.",
        "Options": [
            "a) #elif",
            "b) #ifndef",
            "c) #endif",
            "d) #if"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The #ifdef preprocessor directive is used to check if a particular identifier is currently defined or not.  If the particular identifier is defined, the statements following this preprocessor directive are executed till another preprocessor directive #endif is encountered. #endif is used to end the scope of #ifdef."
    },
    {
        "id": 1433,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifndef max</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) hello",
            "b) hellohi",
            "c) error",
            "d) hi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The code shown above illustrates the preprocessor directive #ifndef. If the identifier checked is not defined, then the statements following #ifndef are executed. Here, since the identifier max is not defined, the statement after #ifndef is executed. Hence the output is: hellohi"
    },
    {
        "id": 1434,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define san 557</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifndef san</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"yes\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"no\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) yes",
            "c) no",
            "d) yesno"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output to the above code will be no. Since we have used the preprocessor directive, #ifndef and defined the identifier san, “yes” is not printed. Hence only “no” is printed as output."
    },
    {
        "id": 1435,
        "Question": " The preprocessor directive which checks whether a constant expression results in a zero or non-zero value __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) #if",
            "b) #ifdef",
            "c) #undef",
            "d) #ifndef"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: #if checks whether a constant expression results in zero or not. If the expression is a non-zero value, then the statements between #if and #endif will be executed.  If the constant expression results in a zero value, the statements between #if and #endif will not be executed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1436,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define max 100</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#if(max%10)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"san\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"foundry\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) san",
            "c) foundry",
            "d) sanfoundry"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above is an illustration of the preprocessor directive #if. The value of the defined identifier max is 100. On checking the condition (100510==), which is true, the statements after #if are executed till #endif is encountered. Hence the output is sanfoundry."
    },
    {
        "id": 1437,
        "Question": "The preprocessor directive which is used to remove the definition of an identifier which was previously defined with #define?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #ifdef",
            "b) #undef",
            "c) #ifndef",
            "d) #def"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: #undef is used to remove the definition of any identifier which had been previously defined in the code with #define."
    },
    {
        "id": 1438,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define hello 10</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#undef hello</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) hello",
            "c) error",
            "d) 1010"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Error: hello undeclared. An error is thrown when the code shown above is executed because before the second call to the printf function, the macro hello was undefined using #undef."
    },
    {
        "id": 1439,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define a 2</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> r<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define a 5</span>\n    r<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>r<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The macro ‘a’ is redefined in the code shown above. Hence the value of a, which is initially 2, is redefined to 5. The value stored in ‘r’ is the result of the expression (a*2), which is equal to 10. Hence the output of this code will be 10."
    },
    {
        "id": 1440,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code if the value of ‘p’ is 10 and that of ‘q’ is 15?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> p<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>q<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Enter two numbers<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,&amp;</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">scanf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,&amp;</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#if(4&lt;2)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>p<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#elif(2&gt;-1)</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>q<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"bye\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 15",
            "c) bye",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is 15. The values given for ‘p’ and ‘q’ are 10 and 15 respectively. Since the condition given for #elif is true, the value stored in ‘q’ will be printed, that is 15."
    },
    {
        "id": 1441,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define san 10</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef san</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define san 20</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>san<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 20",
            "c) Error",
            "d) 1020"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the code shown above, if the identifier san is defined, then its value is redefined and changed to 20. It is then printed. Hence the output is 20."
    },
    {
        "id": 1442,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define hello </span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef hello</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define hi 4</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#else</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define hi 5</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>hi<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n&nbsp;\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 45",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The code shown above illustrates #define, #ifdef, #else, #endif. Since the identifier hello is defined (condition of #if is true), another identifier names hi is defined and it’s value is 4. If hello was not defined, then the value of hi would be 5."
    },
    {
        "id": 1443,
        "Question": "The purpose of the preprocessor directive #error is that ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) It rectifies any error present in the code",
            "b) It rectifies only the first error which occurs in the code",
            "c) It causes the preprocessor to report a fatal error",
            "d) It causes the preprocessor to ignore an error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: #error is a preprocessor directive which causes the preprocessor to report a fatal error. The tokens which form the rest of the line after #error are used as the error message."
    },
    {
        "id": 1444,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define max 20</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifndef max</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define min 10</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#else</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define min 30</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>min<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 20",
            "c) 30",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is 30. Since the identifier max is defined (the condition of #ifndef is true), hence another identifier, that is, min is defined and its value is equal to 30."
    },
    {
        "id": 1445,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define hello 10</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef hello</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#undef hello</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define hello 100</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#else</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define hello 200</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 100",
            "d) 200"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is 100. If the identifier hello is defined, then it is undefined and redefined. It’s new value is 100. If the identifier was not defined, it would be defined with a value of 200."
    },
    {
        "id": 1446,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define sf 10</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>sf<span class=\"sy0\">==</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"good\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"bad\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n        sf<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">100</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>sf<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100",
            "b) bad",
            "c) 10",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The above code will result in an error because a macro cannot be defined using a simple assignment operator. In the code shown above, the value of sf is changed to 100 using the assignment operator. This causes an error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1447,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define sf 100</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>sf<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#define sf 99;</span>\n    f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>sf<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) 100",
            "c) 99",
            "d) 10099"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Macro definition is global even if it is appears within the function scope. In this case the macro sf is defined in the function f(). Hence it results in a compile time error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1448,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define INDIA 1</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define US 2</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define CC US</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#if CC==INDIA</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Rupee\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#elif CC==US</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Dollar\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#else</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Euro\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#endif </span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Euro",
            "b) Rupee",
            "c) Dollar",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is Dollar. Since the macro CC is defined as US at the beginning of the code, it satisfies the condition #elif(CC==US). Hence “Dollar” is printed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1449,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#define sqr(x) x*x</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a1<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    a1<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">25</span><span class=\"sy0\">/</span>sqr<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a1<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 25",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 5",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The output of the code shown above is 25. This is because the arithmetic statement takes the form of: 25/5*5 (which is equal to 1). If the macro had been defined as #define sqr(x) (x*x), the output would have been 1."
    },
    {
        "id": 1450,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a preprocessor directive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #error",
            "b) #pragma",
            "c) #if",
            "d) #ifelse"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: #ifelse is not a preprocessor directive. #error, #pragma, #if are preprocessor directives. There is a preprocessor directive, #elif, which performs the function of else-if."
    },
    {
        "id": 1451,
        "Question": "Which of the following operators is used to concatenate two strings without space?",
        "Options": [
            "a) #",
            "b) < >",
            "c) **",
            "d) ##"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The operator ## is used for token concatenation (to concatenate two strings without space)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1452,
        "Question": "2. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define p( n ) printf( \"t\" #n \" = %d\", t##n )</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> t3<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   p<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) t=10",
            "b) t3=10",
            "c) t10=3",
            "d) t=3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The code shown above uses the ## operator to concatenate ‘t’ and 3. t3 has been declared as 10 in the code, Hence the output of the code shown above is: t3=10"
    },
    {
        "id": 1453,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define p( n,m ) printf( \"%d\", m##n )</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   p<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) Junk value",
            "c) 34",
            "d) 43"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the code shown above, we have concatenated the two tokens in the order: mn. The value of m is equal to 4 and that of n is equal to 3. Hence the output of this code is 43."
    },
    {
        "id": 1454,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define p( n,m ) printf( \"%d\", m##n )</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define q(a,b) printf(\"%d\",a##b)</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   p<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   q<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4356",
            "b) 3456",
            "c) 4365",
            "d) 3465"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the code shown above we have concatenated m and n in one statement and a and b in another. Since we have not used a new line character, the output of this code will be equal to 4356."
    },
    {
        "id": 1455,
        "Question": "6. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define display( n ) printf( \"a\" #n \" = %d\", a##n )</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   display<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a3",
            "b) 31",
            "c) a 3",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The code shown above does not result in an error. The output of this code is t^^3=junk value."
    },
    {
        "id": 1456,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define hello( n ) a##n</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a3<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    x<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>hello<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">!=</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"hi\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"good\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) a3",
            "c) good",
            "d) hi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above results in an error because we have not explicitly declared a3. Had we declared a3 in this code, it would not have thrown an error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1457,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define hello( n ) printf( \"a\" #n \"= %d\", a##n )</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a3<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef a3</span>\n       hello<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"co2\">#else</span>\n       <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"sorry\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"co2\">#endif</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a3=3",
            "b) error",
            "c) a=3",
            "d) sorry"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The code shown will print ‘hi’ if x is not equal to zero and ‘good’ if x is equal to zero. In the above code, we have declared x (equal to zero). Hence ‘good’ is printed as output."
    },
    {
        "id": 1458,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define p( n ) printf( \"t*\" #n \" = %s\", t##n )</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">char</span> tsan<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"st0\">\"tsan\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    x<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>p<span class=\"br0\">(</span>san<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) error",
            "b) tsan=tsan",
            "c) t*san=t*san",
            "d) t*san=tsan"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The code shown above prints a3=3 if as is defined. Since a3 is not defines, ‘sorry’ is printed as output."
    },
    {
        "id": 1459,
        "Question": "Name the function whose definition can be substituted at a place where its function call is made _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) friends function",
            "b) inline function",
            "c) volatile function",
            "d) external function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The inline function, whose definitions being small can be substituted at a place where its function call is made. They are inlined with their function calls."
    },
    {
        "id": 1460,
        "Question": "3. What will be the error (if any) in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"kw2\">inline</span> func1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">float</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n     <span class=\"kw2\">inline</span> func1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu16\">2.2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n     <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) No error",
            "b) Error in statement: void inline func1(float b)",
            "c) Error in statement: printf(“%lf\\n”,b*2);",
            "d) Error in statement: inline func1(2.2);"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The code shown above is an example of inline function. Both functions 1 and 2 are inline functions. Hence the output will be as shown in option \na=1 and b=4\nsquare val = 36\n\n\n        ."
    },
    {
        "id": 1461,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"kw2\">inline</span> f1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    f1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) a",
            "b) 65",
            "c) error",
            "d) 97"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The keyword inline is used only with the function definition. In the code shown above it has been used with the function call. Hence there is an error in the statement: inline func1(2.2);"
    },
    {
        "id": 1462,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> <span class=\"kw2\">inline</span> func1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> b<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n     func1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"sanfoundry\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n     <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) s",
            "b) n",
            "c) a",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The definition of the function f1 is replaced with the function call. Since the format specifier used is %d, the ASCII value of the said character is printed. Hence the output of the code shown above is 97 (ASCII value of the alphabet ‘a’)."
    },
    {
        "id": 1463,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">static</span> <span class=\"kw2\">inline</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> max<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    m<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>max<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"sy0\">,-</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -6",
            "b) -5",
            "c) Junk value",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the code shown above, the definition of function func1 is replaced with its function call. The function prints the alphabet at the second index of the given string. Hence the output of this code is ‘n’."
    },
    {
        "id": 1464,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define inline</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">inline</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n        <span class=\"co2\">#ifdef inline</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n        <span class=\"co2\">#endif </span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">'a'</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) a",
            "c) No error but nothing will be printed as output",
            "d) 97"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above code will result in an error because we have used the keyword inline in the function call. Had the keyword inline been used in the function definition, the code would not have thrown an error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1465,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw2\">extern</span> <span class=\"kw2\">inline</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> min<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span> \n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n  <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">&lt;</span> b <span class=\"sy0\">?</span> a <span class=\"sy0\">:</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> m<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    m<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>min<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">3</span><span class=\"sy0\">,-</span><span class=\"nu0\">5</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>m<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Error",
            "b) 3",
            "c) -5",
            "d) Junk value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The code shown a replaces the definition of a function max with it’s function call. This function is used to print the bigger of the two arguments. Hence -5 is printed."
    },
    {
        "id": 1466,
        "Question": "To have GCC inline the given function regardless of the level of optimization, we must declare the function with the attribute _________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) optimize_inline",
            "b) packed_inline",
            "c) always_inline",
            "d) level_inline"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the code shown above, we have defined identifier names inline using the macro #define. The output will be printed only if inline is defined. Since it is defined, ‘a’ is printed as output."
    },
    {
        "id": 1467,
        "Question": "A machine in which the least significant byte is stored in the smallest address is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Big endian machine",
            "b) Bi-endian machine",
            "c) Binary bit machine",
            "d) Little endian machine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In little endian machines, last byte of binary representation (least significant byte) of a multi byte data type is stored first, whereas in big endian method, the first byte of binary representation of a multi byte data type is stored first."
    },
    {
        "id": 1468,
        "Question": "2. If the output of the following C code is “Big endian”, then what will be the value of *a is?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n   <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> i <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> <span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a <span class=\"sy0\">=</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">if</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n       <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Little endian\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n       <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Big endian\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"kw3\">getchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n   <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -1",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In the code shown above, a character pointer ‘a’ points to an integer ‘i’. Since the size of the character is 1 byte, when the character pointer is de-referenced, it contains 1 integer byte. If the machine is a little endian machine then the value of *a will be 1, since the last byte is stored first. If the machine is big endian, the value of *a will be 0."
    },
    {
        "id": 1469,
        "Question": "The standard byte order for networks is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bit-Binary",
            "b) Little endian",
            "c) Big endian",
            "d) Bi-endian"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is possible for a processor to support both little and big endian methods. Such machines are known as bi-endian machines."
    },
    {
        "id": 1470,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of big endian machines?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Power PC",
            "b) Motorola 68K",
            "c) SPARC processors",
            "d) ARM processors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The standard byte order (network byte order) for networks is big endian. Before transferring data on a network, data is converted to big endian."
    },
    {
        "id": 1471,
        "Question": "Suppose we transfer a file written on a little endian machine to a big endian machine and there is no transformation from little endian to big endian, then what happens?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The big endian machine throws an error when it receives the file",
            "b) The big endian machine reads the file in the reverse order",
            "c) The big endian machine does not read the file",
            "d) The big endian machine reads the file in the normal order"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ARM processor is an example of little endian machine. Current generation ARM processor is an example of bi-endian machine. Power PC, Motorola 68K and SPARC are examples of big endian mahines."
    },
    {
        "id": 1472,
        "Question": "File formats which have _________ as a basic unit are independent of endianness.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 byte",
            "b) 2 bytes",
            "c) 3 bytes",
            "d) 4 bytes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: If there is no transformation from little endian to big endian on transfer of a file from a little endian machine to a big endian machine, the big endian machine reads the file in reverse order."
    },
    {
        "id": 1473,
        "Question": "8. If the code shown below is executed on a little endian machine, then what will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> y<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span> <span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">char</span><span class=\"sy0\">*</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">&amp;</span>y<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 1000",
            "c) 9999",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  File formats which have 1 byte as the basic unit are not endianness dependent. Eg: ASCII files. Other file formats have fixed endianness formats."
    },
    {
        "id": 1474,
        "Question": "If the data “ABCD” is to be stored in a little endian machine, it will be stored as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) ABCD",
            "b) DCBA",
            "c) CDAB",
            "d) BCDA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The output of the above code will be one when it is run on a little endian machine. This is because a little endian machine stores the least significant byte in the smallest address."
    },
    {
        "id": 1475,
        "Question": "The sequential order used to interpret a range of bytes in the memory of a computer is known as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ordering",
            "b) Sequencing",
            "c) Endianness",
            "d) Byte prediction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In a little endian machine, the least significant byte (right most) is stored in the smallest address. Hence the data “ABCD” will be stored in the form of “DCBA”."
    },
    {
        "id": 1476,
        "Question": "1. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    n<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>f1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">4</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\nf1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">==</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n        b<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">*</span>f1<span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 24",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 12",
            "d) 10"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above code returns the factorial of a given number using the method of recursion. The given number is 4 in the above code, hence the factorial of 4, that is, 24 will be returned."
    },
    {
        "id": 1477,
        "Question": "The data structure used to implement recursive function calls _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Array",
            "b) Linked list",
            "c) Binary tree",
            "d) Stack"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The compiler uses the data type stack for implementing normal as well as recursive function calls."
    },
    {
        "id": 1478,
        "Question": "The principle of stack is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) First in first out",
            "b) First in last out",
            "c) Last in first out",
            "d) Last in last out"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A stack is a last in first out(LIFO) data type. This means that the last item to get stored in the stack is the first item to get out of it."
    },
    {
        "id": 1479,
        "Question": "In the absence of a exit condition in a recursive function, the following error is given __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compile time error",
            "b) Run time error",
            "c) Logical error",
            "d) No error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: When a recursive function is called in the absence of an exit condition, it results in an infinite loop due to which the stack keeps getting filled(stack overflow). This results in a run time error."
    },
    {
        "id": 1480,
        "Question": "5. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>i<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    n<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">6</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\nf<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> x<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">==</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n            <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"+\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n        f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>x<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) ++++2",
            "b) +++++2",
            "c) +++++",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:\nWhen x=6: ‘+’ is printed.\nWhen x=5: ‘+’ is printed.\nWhen x=4: ‘+’ is printed.\nWhen x=3: ‘+’ is printed.\nWhen x=2: 2 is printed.\nHence the output is: ++++2."
    },
    {
        "id": 1481,
        "Question": "6. How many times is ‘a’ printed when the following C code is executed?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span>f1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\nf1<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> b<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">==</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">else</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n        <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"a\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n        f1<span class=\"br0\">(</span>b<span class=\"sy0\">--</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9 times",
            "b) 10 times",
            "c) 0 times",
            "d) Infinite number of times"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Although we have specified the exit condition, the code above results in an infinite loop because we have used b- -(decrement operator) to call the recursive function. Due to this, the loop goes on infinitely. However, if we had used f1(b-1) instead, the answer would have been 10 times."
    },
    {
        "id": 1482,
        "Question": "7. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%d\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">int</span> n<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">&gt;</span><span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n        <span class=\"kw1\">return</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">+</span>f<span class=\"br0\">(</span>n<span class=\"sy0\">-</span><span class=\"nu0\">2</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 80",
            "c) 30",
            "d) Error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The recursive function returns n+f(n-2) till 10>0.\nTherefore, the above code will be evaluated as: 10+8+6+4+2, which is equal to 30."
    },
    {
        "id": 1483,
        "Question": "8. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"Hello\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hello is printed once",
            "b) Hello infinite number of times",
            "c) Hello is not printed at all",
            "d) 0 is returned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: in the above code, we are calling main() from main(), which is recursion. However, we have not defined any condition for the program to exit. Hence, “hello” will be printed infinite number of times. To prevent this, we need to define a proper exit condition in the recursive function."
    },
    {
        "id": 1484,
        "Question": "9. What will be the output of the following C code if the input given to the code shown below is “sanfoundry”?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"co2\">#define NL '\\n'</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"enter the word<span class=\"es1\">\\n</span>\"</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">void</span> f<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"kw4\">void</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> c<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">if</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>c<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"kw3\">getchar</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">!=</span>NL<span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\nf<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%c\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>c<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span>\n<span class=\"kw1\">return</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) sanfoundry",
            "b) infinite loop",
            "c) yrdnuofnas",
            "d) fnasyrdnuo"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The above code prints the reverse of the word entered. The recursive function terminates when getchar() is equal to null."
    },
    {
        "id": 1485,
        "Question": "In a signed integer, the sign is represented by ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Least significant bit",
            "b) Most significant bit",
            "c) System dependent",
            "d) The mean of the most significant bit and the least significant bit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In a signed integer, the most significant bit represents the sign whereas, in an unsigned integer, no bit is used to represent the sign."
    },
    {
        "id": 1486,
        "Question": "3. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\n<span class=\"kw4\">int</span> main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">signed</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> ch<span class=\"sy0\">=</span> ‘a’<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>u”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>ch<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -65",
            "b) 65",
            "c) -97",
            "d) 97"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sign qualifiers cannot be applied to the data types: float and double"
    },
    {
        "id": 1487,
        "Question": "4. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\"><span class=\"co2\">#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;</span>\nmain<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">signed</span> <span class=\"kw4\">char</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"sy0\">=</span> “BAT”<span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>c”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span> a<span class=\"br0\">[</span><span class=\"nu0\">1</span><span class=\"br0\">]</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw1\">return</span> <span class=\"nu0\">0</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) -A",
            "b) BAT",
            "c) A",
            "d) 65"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Only for completeness, sign qualifiers are available with char data type."
    },
    {
        "id": 1488,
        "Question": "What is the default state of an integer in c language?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Signed",
            "b) Unsigned",
            "c) System dependent",
            "d) There is no default state"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Sign qualifiers are available for char data types only for completeness. Format specifier used: %c, which prints a character. a[1] will print ‘A’."
    },
    {
        "id": 1489,
        "Question": "What is the binary representation of the integer -14?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11110",
            "b) 01110",
            "c) 01100",
            "d) 11100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The default state of an integer in c language is signed. Hence we can store both positive and negative integer values in it."
    },
    {
        "id": 1490,
        "Question": "Which of the following header files must necessarily be included in your code, if you want to find the minimum value of unsigned short integer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) stdio.h",
            "b) stdlib.h",
            "c) limits.h",
            "d) math.h"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: An integer literal can have a suffix that is a combination of U and L( uppercase or lowercase). The prefix specifies the base or the radix, ie: 0x for hexadecimal, 0 for octal and nothing for decimal."
    },
    {
        "id": 1491,
        "Question": "9. What will be the error in the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">long</span> <span class=\"kw4\">float</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">=-</span><span class=\"nu19\">25.373e22</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"st0\">\"%lf\"</span><span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) Negative number cannot be assigned to float data type",
            "b) Long and float cannot be used together",
            "c) Does not result in error",
            "d) Logical error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The left most bit (most significant bit) is used to represent the sign of the number: 0 for positive and 1 for negative. For example, a value of positive 14 is written as 01110(in binary). But a value of negative 14 is written as: 11110."
    },
    {
        "id": 1492,
        "Question": "10. What will be the output of the following C code?<div class=\"hk1_style-wrap4\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap3\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap2\"><div class=\"hk1_style-wrap\"><div class=\"hk1_style\"><div class=\"c\"><pre class=\"de1\">main<span class=\"br0\">(</span><span class=\"br0\">)</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">{</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> a<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">10</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw4\">long</span> <span class=\"kw4\">unsigned</span> b<span class=\"sy0\">=</span><span class=\"nu0\">5l</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n    <span class=\"kw3\">printf</span><span class=\"br0\">(</span>“<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>lu<span class=\"sy0\">%</span>u”<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>a<span class=\"sy0\">,</span>b<span class=\"br0\">)</span><span class=\"sy0\">;</span>\n<span class=\"br0\">}</span></pre></div></div></div></div></div></div>",
        "Options": [
            "a) 105",
            "b) 510",
            "c) 10",
            "d) error"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The header file limits.h is used to find the value of constants such as minimum and maximum. stdio.h: standard input and output, stdlib.h: standard library, math.h: mathematics functions library"
    }
]